function showAnswer(){
    var e = document.getElementById("answer");
    var w=document.getElementById("show");
    
    if(e.style.display == 'none'){
        e.style.display = 'block';
        w.innerHTML ="Hide Answer";
    }else{
        e.style.display = 'none';
        w.innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    }
}

var king_1 = { //might need to add "james" : [] but dont have to cause chapters are definet numbers
    "c1":[
        {"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 1, Now [who] was _____, advanced in years; and they put covers on him, but he could not get warm.","answer":"Now [King David] was [old],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 1, Now King David was old, [and what else]; and they put covers on him, but he could not get warm.","answer":"[advanced in years];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 1, Now King David was old, advanced in years; and they put [what] on him, but he could not get warm.","answer":"and they put [covers] on him,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 1, Now King David was old, advanced in years; and they put covers on him, but he could not [what].","answer":"but he could not [get warm]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore [who] said to him, \u201cLet a young woman, a virgin, be sought for our lord the king, and let her stand before the king, and let her care for him; and let her lie in your bosom, that our lord the king may be warm.\u201d","answer":"Therefore [his servants] said to him,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore his servants said to him, \u201cLet a [what], a [what], be sought for our lord the king, and let her stand before the king, and let her care for him; and let her lie in your bosom, that our lord the king may be warm.\u201d","answer":"\u201cLet a [young woman], a [virgin], be sought for our lord the king,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore his servants said to him, \u201cLet a young woman, a virgin, be sought for our lord the king, and let her [do what], and let her care for him; and let her lie in your bosom, that our lord the king may be warm.\u201d","answer":"and let her [stand before the king],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore his servants said to him, \u201cLet a young woman, a virgin, be sought for our lord the king, and let her stand before the king, and let her [do what]; and let her lie in your bosom, that our lord the king may be warm.\u201d","answer":"and let her [care for him];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore his servants said to him, \u201cLet a young woman, a virgin, be sought for our lord the king, and let her stand before the king, and let her care for him; and let her [do what], that our lord the king may be warm.\u201d","answer":"and let her [lie in your bosom],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 2, Therefore his servants said to him, \u201cLet a young woman, a virgin, be sought for our lord the king, and let her stand before the king, and let her care for him; and let her lie in your bosom, [why].\u201d","answer":"[that our lord the king may be warm].\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 3, So they sought for a [what where], and found Abishag the Shunammite, and brought her to the king.","answer":"So they sought for a [lovely young woman throughout all the territory of Israel],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 3, So they sought for a lovely young woman throughout all the territory of Israel, and found [whom], and brought her to the king.","answer":"and found [Abishag the Shunammite],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 3, So they sought for a lovely young woman throughout all the territory of Israel, and found Abishag the Shunammite, and [did what with her].","answer":"and [brought her to the king]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 4, The young woman was [what]; and she cared for the king, and served him; but the king did not know her.","answer":"The young woman was [very lovely];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 4, The young woman was very lovely; and she [did what], and served him; but the king did not know her.","answer":"and she [cared for the king],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 4, The young woman was very lovely; and she cared for the king, and [did what]; but the king did not know her.","answer":"and [served him];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 4, The young woman was very lovely; and she cared for the king, and served him; but the king did not [what].","answer":"but the king did not [know her]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 5, Then [who] [did what], saying, \u201cI will be king\u201d; and he prepared for himself chariots and horsemen, and fifty men to run before him.","answer":"Then [Adonijah the son of Haggith] [exalted himself],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 5, Then Adonijah the son of Haggith exalted himself, saying, \u201c[what]\u201d; and he prepared for himself chariots and horsemen, and fifty men to run before him.","answer":"saying, \u201c[I will be king]\u201d;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 5, Then Adonijah the son of Haggith exalted himself, saying, \u201cI will be king\u201d; and he [what two things], and fifty men to run before him.","answer":"and he [prepared for himself chariots and horsemen],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 5, Then Adonijah the son of Haggith exalted himself, saying, \u201cI will be king\u201d; and he prepared for himself chariots and horsemen, and [what].","answer":"and [fifty men to run before him]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 6, (And his father had not [done what] at any time by saying, \u201cWhy have you done so?\u201d He was also very good-looking. His mother had borne him after Absalom.)","answer":"(And his father had not [rebuked him] at any time by saying,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 6, (And his father had not rebuked him at any time by saying, \u201c[what]\u201d He was also very good-looking. His mother had borne him after Absalom.)","answer":"\u201c[Why have you done so?]\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 6, (And his father had not rebuked him at any time by saying, \u201cWhy have you done so?\u201d He was also [what]. His mother had borne him after Absalom.)","answer":"He was also [very good-looking]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 6, (And his father had not rebuked him at any time by saying, \u201cWhy have you done so?\u201d He was also very good-looking. [who] had borne him [when].)","answer":"[His mother] had borne him [after Absalom].)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:7, Adonijah conferred with whom and a priest?","answer":"Then he conferred with Joab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:7, Who was Joab's father?","answer":"the son of Zeruiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:7, Adonijah conferred with Joab and who else?","answer":"and with Abiathar the priest,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:7, What did Joab and Abiathar do for Adonijah?","answer":"and they followed and helped Adonijah."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But [who], Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, Nathan the prophet, Shimei, Rei, and the mighty men who belonged to David were not with Adonijah.","answer":"But [Zadok the priest],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But Zadok the priest, [who], Nathan the prophet, Shimei, Rei, and the mighty men who belonged to David were not with Adonijah.","answer":"[Benaiah the son of Jehoiada],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But Zadok the priest, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, [who], Shimei, Rei, and the mighty men who belonged to David were not with Adonijah.","answer":"[Nathan the prophet],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But Zadok the priest, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, Nathan the prophet, [who], Rei, and the mighty men who belonged to David were not with Adonijah.","answer":"[Shimei],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But Zadok the priest, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, Nathan the prophet, Shimei, _____, and the mighty men who belonged to David were not with Adonijah.","answer":"[Rei],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 8, But Zadok the priest, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, Nathan the prophet, Shimei, Rei, and [who] were not with Adonijah.","answer":"and [the mighty men who belonged to David] were not with Adonijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:9, Adonijah sacrificed what three kinds of animals by the stone of Zoheleth?","answer":"And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 9, And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle [where], which is by En Rogel; he also invited all his brothers, the king\u2019s sons, and all the men of Judah, the king\u2019s servants.","answer":"[by the stone of Zoheleth],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:9, Where is the stone of Zoheleth?","answer":"which is by En Rogel;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 9, And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle by the stone of Zoheleth, which is by En Rogel; he also invited [whom], the king\u2019s sons, and all the men of Judah, the king\u2019s servants.","answer":"he also invited [all his brothers],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 9, And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle by the stone of Zoheleth, which is by En Rogel; he also invited all his brothers, [also known as what], and all the men of Judah, the king\u2019s servants.","answer":"[the king\u2019s sons],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 9, And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle by the stone of Zoheleth, which is by En Rogel; he also invited all his brothers, the king\u2019s sons, and [who], the king\u2019s servants.","answer":"and [all the men of Judah],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 9, And Adonijah sacrificed sheep and oxen and fattened cattle by the stone of Zoheleth, which is by En Rogel; he also invited all his brothers, the king\u2019s sons, and all the men of Judah, [also known as what].","answer":"[the king\u2019s servants]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 10, But he did not invite [who], Benaiah, the mighty men, or Solomon his brother.","answer":"But he did not invite [Nathan the prophet],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 10, But he did not invite Nathan the prophet, [who], the mighty men, or Solomon his brother.","answer":"[Benaiah],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 10, But he did not invite Nathan the prophet, Benaiah, [who], or Solomon his brother.","answer":"[the mighty men],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 10, But he did not invite Nathan the prophet, Benaiah, the mighty men, or [who].","answer":"or [Solomon his brother]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:11, Which prophet gave life-saving advice to whom?","answer":"So Nathan spoke to Bathsheba the mother of Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 11, So Nathan spoke to Bathsheba the mother of Solomon, saying, \u201c[what about who] the son of Haggith has become king, and David our lord does not know it?","answer":"saying, \u201c[Have you not heard that Adonijah]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 11, So Nathan spoke to Bathsheba the mother of Solomon, saying, \u201cHave you not heard that Adonijah [how is Adonijah described?] has become [what],","answer":"[the son of Haggith] has become [king],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 11, So Nathan spoke to Bathsheba the mother of Solomon, saying, \u201cHave you not heard that Adonijah the son of Haggith has become king, and [who?] does not [what?]?","answer":"and [David our lord] does not [know it]?"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 12, _____, please, let me [when] [do what], that you may save your own life and the life of your son Solomon.","answer":"[Come], please, let me [now] [give you advice],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 12, Come, please, let me now give you advice, [why?] and the life of your son Solomon.","answer":"[that you may save your own life]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 12, Come, please, let me now give you advice, that you may save your own life and [what else?].","answer":"and [the life of your son Solomon]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 13, [do what?] [how soon?] to [whom?] and say to him, \u2018Did you not, my lord, O king, swear to your maidservant, saying, \u201cAssuredly your son Solomon shall reign after me, and he shall sit on my throne\u201d? Why then has Adonijah become king?\u2019","answer":"[Go] [immediately] to [King David]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 13, Go immediately to King David and say to him, \u2018[what?], saying, \u201cAssuredly your son Solomon shall reign after me, and he shall sit on my throne\u201d? Why then has Adonijah become king?\u2019","answer":"and say to him, \u2018[Did you not, my lord, O king, swear to your maidservant],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 13, Go immediately to King David and say to him, \u2018Did you not, my lord, O king, swear to your maidservant, saying, \u201c[with what certainty?] [who?] shall [do what], and he shall sit on my throne\u201d? Why then has Adonijah become king?\u2019","answer":"saying, \u201c[Assuredly] [your son Solomon] shall [reign after me],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 13, Go immediately to King David and say to him, \u2018Did you not, my lord, O king, swear to your maidservant, saying, \u201cAssuredly your son Solomon shall reign after me, and he shall [do what?]\u201d? Why then has Adonijah become king?\u2019","answer":"and he shall [sit on my throne]\u201d?"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 13, Go immediately to King David and say to him, \u2018Did you not, my lord, O king, swear to your maidservant, saying, \u201cAssuredly your son Solomon shall reign after me, and he shall sit on my throne\u201d? Why then has [who?] become [what?]?\u2019","answer":"Why then has [Adonijah] become [king]?\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:14, Nathan was planning for what to be happening when he would visit the king?","answer":"Then, while you are still talking there with the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:14, In comparison to Bathsheba's visit to the king, when was Nathan was planning his visit?","answer":"I also will come in after you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:14, Why was Nathan planning to visit the king after Bathsheba?","answer":"and confirm your words.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:15, what did Bathsheba do after Nathan gave his advice to her?","answer":"So Bathsheba went into the chamber to the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:15, was the king young when Bathsheba visited the king?","answer":"(Now the king was very old,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:15, who was serving the king when Bathsheba went into the chamber of the king?","answer":"and Abishag the Shunammite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:15, what was Abishag the Shunamite doing when Bathsheba went into the chamber of the king?","answer":"was serving the king.)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:16, What did Bathsheba do after she went into the chamber of the king before the king spoke to her?","answer":"And Bathsheba bowed and did homage to the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:16, What did the king do after Bathsheba bowed and did homage to him?","answer":"Then the king said, \u201cWhat is your wish?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 17, Then she said to him, \u201cMy lord, you [did what] by [whom] to [whom], saying, \u2018Assuredly Solomon your son shall reign after me, and he shall sit on my throne.\u2019","answer":"Then she said to him, \u201cMy lord, you [swore] by [the Lord your God] to [your maidservant],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:17, Bathsheba recalled David telling her who would reign after him. What words did he use?","answer":"saying, \u2018Assuredly Solomon your son shall reign after me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:17, Bathsheba recalled David telling her Solomon who would reign after him. What else did he say Solomon would do?","answer":"and he shall sit on my throne.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:18, Who did Bathsheba say had actually become king after David?","answer":"So now, look! Adonijah has become king;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 18, So now, look! Adonijah has become king; and [whan], my lord the king, [what?].","answer":"and [now], my lord the king, [you do not know about it]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:19, Bathsheba said Adonijah had done what in abundance?","answer":"He has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 19, He has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has [done what] [to whom], Abiathar the priest, and Joab the commander of the army; but Solomon your servant he has not invited.","answer":"and has [invited] [all the sons of the king],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 19, He has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has invited all the sons of the king, [whom], and Joab the commander of the army; but Solomon your servant he has not invited.","answer":"[Abiathar the priest],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 19, He has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has invited all the sons of the king, Abiathar the priest, and _____ ______ _____ _____ _____ _____; but Solomon your servant he has not invited.","answer":"and [Joab the commander of the army];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19, who did Bathsheba say Adonijah had not invited to the sacrifices?","answer":"but Solomon your servant he has not invited."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 20, And as for [who], the eyes of all Israel are on you, that you should tell them who will sit on the throne of my lord the king after him.","answer":"And as for [you, my lord, O king],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:20 what did Bathsheba say was on King David?","answer":"the eyes of all Israel are on you,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 20, And as for you, my lord, O king, the eyes of all Israel are on you, [what did Bathsheba ask David to do about] who will sit on the throne of my lord the king after him.","answer":"[that you should tell them]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 20, And as for you, my lord, O king, the eyes of all Israel are on you, that you should tell them [what].","answer":"[who will sit on the throne of my lord the king after him]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 21, Otherwise _____ ______ _____, when my lord the king rests with his fathers, that I and my son Solomon will be counted as offenders.\u201d","answer":"Otherwise [it will happen],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:21, Bathsheba told David that he didn't do something when would she and Solomon be counted offenders?","answer":"when my lord the king rests with his fathers,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:21, Who would be counted as offenders when Daved rests with his fathers?","answer":"that I and my son Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:21, how will Bathsheba and Solomon be viewed when David rests with his fathers?","answer":"will be counted as offenders.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 22, [When did] Nathan the prophet also came in.","answer":"[And just then, while she was still talking with the king,]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 22, And just then, while she was still talking with the king, [what happened].","answer":"[Nathan the prophet also came in]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 23, [who said], \u201cHere is Nathan the prophet.\u201d","answer":"[So they told the king, saying],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 23, So they told the king, saying, \u201cHere is [who].\u201d","answer":"\u201cHere is [Nathan the prophet].\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 23, So they told the king, saying, \u201cHere is Nathan the prophet.\u201d And [when is it that] he bowed down before the king with his face to the ground.","answer":"And [when he came in before the king,]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 23, So they told the king, saying, \u201cHere is Nathan the prophet.\u201d And when he came in before the king, [what did he do?].","answer":"[he bowed down before the king with his face to the ground]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 24, And Nathan said, \u201c[what], and he shall sit on my throne\u2019?","answer":"And Nathan said, \u201c[My lord, O king, have you said, \u2018Adonijah shall reign after me],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 24, And Nathan said, \u201cMy lord, O king, have you said, \u2018Adonijah shall reign after me, and he shall [do what]\u2019?","answer":"and he shall [sit on my throne]\u2019?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:25 What was the first thing Nathan told David Adonijah had done that day?","answer":"For he has gone down today,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 25, For he has gone down today, and has [done what], and has invited all the king\u2019s sons, and the commanders of the army, and Abiathar the priest; and look! They are eating and drinking before him; and they say, \u2018Long live King Adonijah!\u2019","answer":"and has [sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 25, For he has gone down today, and has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has [done what], and the commanders of the army, and Abiathar the priest; and look! They are eating and drinking before him; and they say, \u2018Long live King Adonijah!\u2019","answer":"and has [invited all the king\u2019s sons],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 25, For he has gone down today, and has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has invited all the king\u2019s sons, and [whom], and Abiathar the priest; and look! They are eating and drinking before him; and they say, \u2018Long live King Adonijah!\u2019","answer":"and [the commanders of the army],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 25, For he has gone down today, and has sacrificed oxen and fattened cattle and sheep in abundance, and has invited all the king\u2019s sons, and the commanders of the army, and [whom]; and look! They are eating and drinking before him; and they say, \u2018Long live King Adonijah!\u2019","answer":"and [Abiathar the priest];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:25, what did Nathan say Adonijah's guests were doing?","answer":"and look! They are eating and drinking before him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:25, what did Nathan say Adonijah's guests were saying?","answer":"and they say, \u2018Long live King Adonijah!\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:26 What did Nathan tell King David that Adonijah had not done for Nathan.","answer":"But he has not invited me\u2014me your servant"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 26, But he has not invited me\u2014me your servant\u2014nor [whom], nor Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, nor your servant Solomon.","answer":"\u2014nor [Zadok the priest],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 26, But he has not invited me\u2014me your servant\u2014nor Zadok the priest, nor [whom], nor your servant Solomon.","answer":"nor [Benaiah the son of Jehoiada],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 26, But he has not invited me\u2014me your servant\u2014nor Zadok the priest, nor Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, nor [whom].","answer":"nor [your servant Solomon]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 27, [Nathan asked King David...] Has [what happened] by [whom], and you have not told your servant who should sit on the throne of my lord the king after him?\u201d","answer":"Has [this thing been done] by [my lord the king],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 27, [Nathan asked King David...] Has this thing been done by my lord the king, and you have not _____ ______ _____ who should sit on the throne of my lord the king after him?\u201d","answer":"and you have not [told your servant]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 27, [Nathan asked King David...] Has this thing been done by my lord the king, and you have not told your servant [what]\u201d","answer":"[who should sit on the throne of my lord the king after him?]\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 28, [who said], \u201cCall Bathsheba to me.\u201d","answer":"[Then King David answered and said],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:28 how did King David respond when Nathan asked if he had made Adonijah King.","answer":"\u201cCall Bathsheba to me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:28 what was Bathsheba's first action when David called for her?","answer":"So she came into the king\u2019s presence"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:28 what was Bathsheba's second action when David colled for her?","answer":"and stood before the king."},{"question":"According to 1 King 1:29 what did King David do when Bathsheba came in to his presence after Nathan had talked with him?","answer":"And the king took an oath and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:29, by whom did David sware?","answer":"\u201cAs the Lord lives,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:29 how did David describe the LORD?","answer":"who has redeemed my life from every distress,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 30, [How did David indicate that he had previously told Bathsheba], \u2018Assuredly Solomon your son shall be king after me, and he shall sit on my throne in my place,\u2019","answer":"[just as I swore to you by the Lord God of Israel, saying],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:30, what had David sworn to Bathsheba that her son would be?","answer":"\u2018Assuredly Solomon your son shall be king after me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:30, where had David sworn to Bathsheba that Solomon would sit?","answer":"and he shall sit on my throne in my place,\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:30, David said he would make Solomon king when?","answer":"so I certainly will do this day.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:31, Bathsheba did 3 things when David swore to make Solomon King that day.  What was the first thing she did?","answer":"Then Bathsheba bowed with her face to the earth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:31, Bathsheba did 3 things when David swore to make Solomon King that day.  What was the second thing she did?","answer":"and paid homage to the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:31, Bathsheba did 3 things when David swore to make Solomon King that day.  What was the third thing she did?","answer":"and said, \u201cLet my lord King David live forever!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:32, After David swore to make Solomon king that day, who was the first person he asked to come before him?","answer":"And King David said, \u201cCall to me Zadok the priest,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 32, [David swore to make Solomon king that day...] And King David said, \u201cCall to me Zadok the priest, [who], and Benaiah the son of Jehoiada.\u201d So they came before the king.","answer":"[Nathan the prophet],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 32, [David swore to make Solomon king that day...] And King David said, \u201cCall to me Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, and [who].\u201d So they came before the king.","answer":"and [Benaiah the son of Jehoiada].\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 32, [David swore to make Solomon king that day...] And King David said, \u201cCall to me Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, and Benaiah the son of Jehoiada.\u201d So they [did what].","answer":"So they [came before the king]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:33, who did David ask Zadok, Nathan and Benaiah to take with them?","answer":"The king also said to them, \u201cTake with you the servants of your lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:33, How was Solomon supposed to get to Gihon to be anointed king?","answer":"and have Solomon my son ride on my own mule,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:33 Where was Solomon going to be anointed king?","answer":"and take him down to Gihon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:34, Two people were supposed to anoint Solomon king.  Who was the first person mentioned and what was his role?","answer":"There let Zadok the priest"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:34, Two people were supposed to anoint Solomon king.  Who was the second person mentioned and what was his role?","answer":"and Nathan the prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:34, After Zadok, Nathan, and Solomon got to Gihon, what was the first thing they were to do to Solomon?","answer":"anoint him king over Israel;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:34, After Zadok and Nathon had anointed Solomon king, what was the next thing they were to do?","answer":"and blow the horn,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:34, After Zadok and Nathon had anointed Solomon king and blew the horn, what was the next thing they were to do?","answer":"and say, \u2018Long live King Solomon!\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:35, where were Zadok, Nathan, and Beniah supposed to go when Solomon left Gihon?","answer":"Then you shall come up after him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:35, where was Solomon supposed to sit after he left Gihon?","answer":"and he shall come and sit on my throne,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:35, After Solomon left Gihon what did David say Solomon was supposed to be?","answer":"and he shall be king in my place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:35, Why did David ask Zadok, Nathan, and Beniah to make Solomon king?","answer":"For I have appointed him to be ruler over Israel and Judah.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 36, [When David explained the plan to make Solomon king, who responded], \u201cAmen! May the Lord God of my lord the king say so too.","answer":"[Benaiah the son of Jehoiada answered the king and said],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:36, What did Benaiah say to indicate he agreed to the King's plan to make Solomon king?","answer":"\u201cAmen! May the Lord God of my lord the king say so too."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:37, to what extent did Benaiah want the LORD to be with Solomon as king?","answer":"As the Lord has been with my lord the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:37 Benaiah wanted the LORD to be with whom like He had been with David?","answer":"even so may He be with Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:37 how did Benaiah ask the LORD to make Solomon's throne compared to David's?","answer":"and make his throne greater than the throne of my lord King David.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So [who], Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites went down and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and took him to Gihon.","answer":"So [Zadok the priest],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, [who], Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites went down and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and took him to Gihon.","answer":"[Nathan the prophet],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, [who], the Cherethites, and the Pelethites went down and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and took him to Gihon.","answer":"[Benaiah the son of Jehoiada],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, [who], and the Pelethites went down and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and took him to Gihon.","answer":"[the Cherethites],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and [who] [did what] and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and took him to Gihon.","answer":"and [the Pelethites] [went down]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites went down and had [who] [do what], and took him to Gihon.","answer":"and had [Solomon] [ride on King David\u2019s mule],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 38, So Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites went down and had Solomon ride on King David\u2019s mule, and [did what].","answer":"and [took him to Gihon]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:39, where did Zadok get the oil to anoint Solomon?","answer":"Then Zadok the priest took a horn of oil from the tabernacle"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:39, what did Zadok to with the oil he took from the tabernacle?","answer":"and anointed Solomon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:39, what did they do with the horn of oil after Zadok had anointed Solomon with the oil?","answer":"And they blew the horn,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:39, what did the people say after the horn was blown?","answer":"and all the people said, \u201cLong live King Solomon!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 40, [What did they do after Solomon left Gihon?] ; and the people played the flutes and rejoiced with great joy, so that the earth seemed to split with their sound.","answer":"[And all the people went up after him];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 40, And all the people went up after him; and [did what as Solomon left Gihon?] and rejoiced with great joy, so that the earth seemed to split with their sound.","answer":"and [the people played the flutes]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 40, And all the people went up after him; and the people played the flutes and [did what as Solomon left Gihon?], so that the earth seemed to split with their sound.","answer":"and [rejoiced with great joy],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:40, the people with Solomon made so much noise that it seemed that what might happen?","answer":"so that the earth seemed to split with their sound."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:41, who were the people by the stone of Zoheleth that heard a great sound from Gihon?","answer":"Now Adonijah and all the guests who were with him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:41, What was Adonidjah doing when he heard the sound of the horn used to anoint Solomon?","answer":"heard it as they finished eating."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:41, Who wanted to know why the city was being so noisy?","answer":"And when Joab heard the sound of the horn,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:41, What did Joab want to know when he heard the horn?","answer":"he said, \u201cWhy is the city in such a noisy uproar?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, What was Joab doing when Jonathan arrived by the stone of Zoheleth?","answer":"While he was still speaking,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, Who arrived while Joab was asking about the noisy city?","answer":"there came Jonathan,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, Who was Jonathan's father?","answer":"the son of Abiathar the priest."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, When Jonathan the son of Abiathar the priest came to Adonijah's coronation celebration, where did Adonijah ask him to go?","answer":"And Adonijah said to him, \u201cCome in,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, When Jonathan the son of Abiathar the priest came to Adonijah's coronation celebration, how did Adonijah describe him?","answer":"for you are a prominent man,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:42, When Jonathan the son of Abiathar the priest came to Adonijah's coronation celebration, what kind of a message did Adonijah expect?","answer":"and bring good news.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:43, Who was the first to tell Adonijah that David had made Solomon king?","answer":"Then Jonathan answered and said to Adonijah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:43, How did Jonathan respond to Adonijah when Adonijah was expecting good news?","answer":"\u201cNo! Our lord King David has made Solomon king."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 44, The king has sent with him [who], Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites; and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule.","answer":"The king has sent with him [Zadok the priest],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 44, The king has sent with him Zadok the priest, [who], Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites; and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule.","answer":"[Nathan the prophet],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 44, The king has sent with him Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, _____ ______ _____ _____ _____, the Cherethites, and the Pelethites; and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule.","answer":"[Benaiah the son of Jehoiada],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 44, The king has sent with him Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the [which group of people?], and the Pelethites; and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule.","answer":"the [Cherethites],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 1 verse 44, The king has sent with him Zadok the priest, Nathan the prophet, Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the Cherethites, and the [which group of people]; and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule.","answer":"and the [Pelethites];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:44, what did the people make Solomon do?","answer":"and they have made him ride on the king\u2019s mule."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, Who did Jonathan say was the prist at Solomon's coronation?","answer":"So Zadok the priest"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, Who did Jonathan say was the prophet at Solomon's coronation?","answer":"and Nathan the prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, What did Jonathan say Zadok and Nathan had done to\/for Solomon?","answer":"have anointed him king at Gihon;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, After Solomon was anointed king, what did Jonathan say the people did?","answer":"and they have gone up from there rejoicing,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, What did the city do when Solomon went up from the near the stone of Zoheleth","answer":"so that the city is in an uproar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:45, what did Jonathan say to summarize his message for Adonidjah?","answer":"This is the noise that you have heard."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:46, what was Solomon doing when Jonathan left?","answer":"Also Solomon sits on the throne of the kingdom."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:47, what group of people blessed David after Solomon sat on the throne?","answer":"And moreover the king\u2019s servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:47, why did the king's servants ask God to make Solomon better than David?","answer":"have gone to bless our lord King David,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:47, What was the first thing the King's servants asked God to do for Solomon after he became king?","answer":"saying, \u2018May God make the name of Solomon better than your name,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:47, How did the King's servants ask God to make Solomon's throne compared to David's?","answer":"and may He make his throne greater than your throne.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:47, What did David do when his servant's blessed him?","answer":"Then the king bowed himself on the bed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:48, who did David bless after his servants blessed him?","answer":"Also the king said thus, \u2018Blessed be the Lord God of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:48, when David was blessing God, what did David say the LORD God of Israel had done?","answer":"who has given one to sit on my throne this day,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:48, What was David was grateful he was doing while Soloman was sitting on his throne?","answer":"while my eyes see it!\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:49, how did Adonijah and his guests feel when they heard Jonathan's message?","answer":"So all the guests who were with Adonijah were afraid,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:49, What was the first thing Adonijah's guests did when they heard Jonathan's message?","answer":"and arose,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:49, What was the second thing Adonijah's guests did when they heard Jonathan's message?","answer":"and each one went his way."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:50, how did Adonijah feel about Solomon after hearing what David had done for him?","answer":"Now Adonijah was afraid of Solomon;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:50, What was the first thing Adonijah did when his guests left?","answer":"so he arose,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:50, What was the second think Adonijah did when his guests left?","answer":"and went and took hold of the horns of the altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:51, A message was sent to Solomon saying how Adonijah felt about Solomon.  What was this message?","answer":"And it was told Solomon, saying, \u201cIndeed Adonijah is afraid of King Solomon;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:51, What observable act had Adonijah done that showed he was aftraid of King Solomon?","answer":"for look, he has taken hold of the horns of the altar,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:51, Adonijah asked for someone to sware to him. Who was it?","answer":"saying, \u2018Let King Solomon swear to me today"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:51, What did Adonijah ask Solomon to swear to him?","answer":"that he will not put his servant to death with the sword.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:52, Solomon agreed that Adonijah could live if he would do what?","answer":"Then Solomon said, \u201cIf he proves himself a worthy man,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:52, What did Solomon say would be the concequence to Adonijah if he proved himself a worthy man?","answer":"not one hair of him shall fall to the earth;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:52, Solomon said Adonijah would die if a condition was met. What condition was this?","answer":"but if wickedness is found in him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:52, Solomon said what would happen if wickedness was found in Solomon?","answer":"he shall die.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:53, After Solomon declared that Adonijah could live if he proved himself a worthy man, what did Solomon do?","answer":"So King Solomon sent them to bring him down from the altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:53, Where did King Solomon tell Adonijah to go when the king had asked him to be brought before him?","answer":"and Solomon said to him, \u201cGo to your house.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 1:53, What did Adonijah do when we was brought before King Solomon?","answer":"And he came and fell down before King Solomon;"}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],
    "c2":[
        //Do Not Neglect Salvation 
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:1, What drew near when David charged Solomon?","answer":"Now the days of David drew near that he should die,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 1, Now the days of David drew near that he should die, and [:what did he do?]","answer":"and [he charged Solomon his son, saying]:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:2, what phrase did David say to explain that he was going to die soon?","answer":"\u201cI go the way of all the earth;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 2, \u201cI go the way of all the earth; [do what] and prove yourself a man.","answer":"[be strong, therefore,]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 2, \u201cI go the way of all the earth; be strong, therefore, and [do what].","answer":"and [prove yourself a man]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:3, what summary statement did David say Solomon should do so that he would prosper?","answer":"And keep the charge of the Lord your God:"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 3, And keep the charge of the Lord your God: [to do what], to keep His statutes, His commandments, His judgments, and His testimonies, as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;","answer":"[to walk in His ways],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 3, And keep the charge of the Lord your God: to walk in His ways, [to keep what], His commandments, His judgments, and His testimonies, as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;","answer":"[to keep His statutes],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 3, And keep the charge of the Lord your God: to walk in His ways, to keep His statutes, [what else], His judgments, and His testimonies, as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;","answer":"[His commandments],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 3, And keep the charge of the Lord your God: to walk in His ways, to keep His statutes, His commandments, [what else], and His testimonies, as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;","answer":"[His judgments],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 3, And keep the charge of the Lord your God: to walk in His ways, to keep His statutes, His commandments, His judgments, and [what else], as it is written in the Law of Moses, that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;","answer":"and [His testimonies],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:3, Where is the charge of the Lord your God written?","answer":"as it is written in the Law of Moses,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:3, What are the benefits of keeping the Law of Moses?","answer":"that you may prosper in all that you do and wherever you turn;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 4, [And keep the charge of the Lord your God...] that the Lord may fulfill [what] which He spoke concerning [who],","answer":"that the Lord may fulfill [His word] which He spoke concerning [me],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 4, \u2018If your [what] [do what], to walk before Me in truth with all their heart and with all their soul,\u2019 He said, \u2018you shall not lack a man on the throne of Israel.\u2019","answer":"saying, \u2018If your [sons] [take heed to their way],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 4, \u2018If your sons take heed to their way, to [do what] with all their heart and with all their soul,\u2019 He said, \u2018you shall not lack a man on the throne of Israel.\u2019","answer":"to [walk before Me in truth]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 4, \u2018If your sons take heed to their way, to walk before Me in truth with [what] and with all their soul,\u2019 He said, \u2018you shall not lack a man on the throne of Israel.\u2019","answer":"with [all their heart]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 4, \u2018If your sons take heed to their way, to walk before Me in truth with all their heart and with [what],\u2019 He said, \u2018you shall not lack a man on the throne of Israel.\u2019","answer":"and with [all their soul],\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:4, What blessing did God say would come to David if his descendants followed God's way fully?","answer":"He said, \u2018you shall not lack a man on the throne of Israel.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, who killed Abner and Amasa?","answer":"\u201cMoreover you know also what Joab the son of Zeruiah did to me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, what function did Abner and Amasa have before Joab killed them?","answer":"and what he did to the two commanders of the armies of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, what were the names of the two commanders that Joab killed?","answer":"to Abner the son of Ner and Amasa the son of Jether,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, what did Joab do to Abner and Amasa?","answer":"whom he killed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, did Joab kill Abner and Amasa in battle?","answer":"And he shed the blood of war in peacetime,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, what did Joab do to his belt?","answer":"and put the blood of war on his belt that was around his waist,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:5, Joab put blood on his belt and one other place.  What place was that?","answer":"and on his sandals that were on his feet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:6, what phase did David say that gave Solomon freedom in how to deal with Joab?","answer":"Therefore do according to your wisdom,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:6, what did David ask Solomon to do concerning Joab?","answer":"and do not let his gray hair go down to the grave in peace."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 7, \u201cBut [do what] to [whom (2 pts)], and let them be among those who eat at your table,","answer":"\u201cBut [show kindness] to [the sons of Barzillai the Gileadite],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 7, \u201cBut show kindness to the sons of Barzillai the Gileadite, and let them be [what],","answer":"and let them be [among those who eat at your table],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 2 verse 7, \u201cBut show kindness to the sons of Barzillai the Gileadite, and let them be among those who eat at your table, [why].","answer":"[for so they came to me when I fled from Absalom your brother]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, what was the name of the Benjamite from Bahurim and the name of his father who cursed David when he went to Mahanaim?","answer":"\u201cAnd see, you have with you Shimei the son of Gera,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, From what tribe and place was Shimei the son of Gera who cursed David and threw stones at him (See also 2 Samuel 16:5-8)?","answer":"a Benjamite from Bahurim,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, what wrong did Shimei the son of Gera do to David?","answer":"who cursed me with a malicious curse in the day when I went to Mahanaim."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, where did Shimei the son of Gera go to ask David to be merciful to him?","answer":"But he came down to meet me at the Jordan,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, How strongly did David state that he was not going to kill Shimei the son of Gera?","answer":"and I swore to him by the Lord, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:8, What did David swear to Shimei the son of Gera?","answer":"\u2018I will not put you to death with the sword.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:9, what did David ask Solomon to not do regarding Shimei the son of Gera?","answer":"Now therefore, do not hold him guiltless,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:9, David gave Solomon a complement when he was instructing him how to deal with Shimei the son of Gera. What was this complement?","answer":"for you are a wise man and know what you ought to do to him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:9, What punishment did David ask Solomon to give to Shimei the son of Gera?","answer":"but bring his gray hair down to the grave with blood.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:10, How is David's death described?","answer":"So David rested with his fathers,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:10, Where was David buried?","answer":"and was buried in the City of David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:11, how long did David reign over Israel?","answer":"The period that David reigned over Israel was forty years;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:11, how long did David reign in Hebron?","answer":"seven years he reigned in Hebron,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:11, how log did David reign in Jerusalem?","answer":"and in Jerusalem he reigned thirty-three years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kigns 2:11, what were the names of the two places that David reigned over Israel?","answer":"Hebron and Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:12, Where did Solomon sit after David was buried?","answer":"Then Solomon sat on the throne of his father David;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:12, How secure was Solomon's kingdom after David died?","answer":"and his kingdom was firmly established."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:13, who came to Solomon's mother to try to get Abishag the Shunammite to be his wife?","answer":"Now Adonijah the son of Haggith came to Bathsheba the mother of Solomon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:13, what was the first thing that Bathsheba ask Adonijah the son of Haggith when he came to her?","answer":"So she said, \u201cDo you come peaceably?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:13, How did Adonijah the son of Haggith answer Bathsheba when she asked him if he was coming peaceably?","answer":"And he said, \u201cPeaceably.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:14, When Adonijah the son of Haggith came to Bathsheba to try to get Abishag the Shunammite to be his wife, he answered her initial question. What did he do next?","answer":"Moreover he said, \u201cI have something to say to you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:14, How did Bathsheba replay when Adonijah the son of Haggith told her he had something to say to her?","answer":"And she said, \u201cSay it.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, Who did Adonijah say had owned the kingdom before it became Solomon\u2019s?","answer":"Then he said, \u201cYou know that the kingdom was mine,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, Who had expected Adonijah to reign after David?","answer":"and all Israel had set their expectations on me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, What did Adonijah say all Israel expect him to do?","answer":"that I should reign."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, What did Adonijah say had happened to the kingdom between the time that it was his and when it became his brother's?","answer":"However, the kingdom has been turned over,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, To whom was the kingdom turned over after it was turned over from Adonijah?","answer":"and has become my brother\u2019s;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:15, Why did Adonijah say the kingdom had become his brother's?","answer":"for it was his from the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:16, what did Adonijah ask Bathsheba not to deny him?","answer":"Now I ask one petition of you;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:16, Adonijah made a special request of Bathsheba about his petition. What was this special request?","answer":"do not deny me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:16, Adonijah asked Bathsheba to agree to grant him his petition even before he told her what the petition was. How did she wisely reply?","answer":"And she said to him, \u201cSay it.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:17, Who did Adonijah want Bathsheba to speak to for him?","answer":"Then he said, \u201cPlease speak to King Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:17 Why did Adonijah want Bathsheba to ask King Solomon his question?","answer":"for he will not refuse you,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:17 What did Adonijah want Bathsheba to speak to King Solomon about?","answer":"that he may give me Abishag the Shunammite as wife.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:18, who agreed to ask King Solomon if Adonijah could have Abishag the Shunamite as wife?","answer":"So Bathsheba said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:18, What did Bathsheba say to Adonijah when he asked is she would present his request to King Solomon about Abishage the Shunamite?","answer":"\u201cVery well, I will speak for you to the king.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:19, What did Bathsheba do after she agreed to speak for Adonijah to the king?","answer":"Bathsheba therefore went to King Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:19, Why did Bathsheba go to King Solomon?","answer":"to speak to him for Adonijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:19, What did King Solomon do to great Bathsheba when she came to the throne room?","answer":"And the king rose up to meet her and bowed down to her,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:19, What two things did Solomon do after he bowed down to Bathsheba?","answer":"and sat down on his throne and had a throne set for the king\u2019s mother;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:19, When Bathsheba sat on her throne, where did she sit in comparison to the king's throne?","answer":"so she sat at his right hand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:20, What did Bathsheba first say to King Solomon when she came to speak to him for Adonijah?","answer":"Then she said, \u201cI desire one small petition of you; do not refuse me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:20, How did King Solomon respond to Bathsheba when she asked him not to refuse her petition before she told him what the petition was?","answer":"And the king said to her, \u201cAsk it, my mother, for I will not refuse you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:21, Who did Bathsheba ask to be given to Adonijah as wife?","answer":"So she said, \u201cLet Abishag the Shunammite be given to"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:21, To whom did Bathsheba ask for Abishag the Shunamite be given to as wife?","answer":"Adonijah your brother"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:21, What type of relationship did Bathsheba ask for Adonijah to have with Abishag?","answer":"as wife.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon answered Bathsheba's petition with a question. What was this question?","answer":"And King Solomon answered and said to his mother, \u201cNow why do you ask Abishag the Shunammite for Adonijah?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon compared Bathsheba's petition for Adonijah to another petition he might have desired.  What was it?","answer":"Ask for him the kingdom also\u2014"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon gave a reason that it might be appropriate for Adonijah to be king instead of himself. What was this reason?","answer":"for he is my older brother"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon listed 3 people that had nearly made Adonijah king. Who did he mention first?","answer":"\u2014for him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon listed 3 people that had nearly made Adonijah king. Who was the religious leader?","answer":"and for Abiathar the priest,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:22, Solomon listed 3 people that had nearly made Adonijah king. Who was the army captain?","answer":"and for Joab the son of Zeruiah.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:23, By whom did the king swear when he was declaring what would happen to Adonijah?","answer":"Then King Solomon swore by the Lord, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:23, What did Solomon ask to be done to himself if he didn't put Adonijah to death?","answer":"\u201cMay God do so to me, and more also,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:23, Against what did Solomon say Adonijah had asked about Abishag becoming his wife?","answer":"if Adonijah has not spoken this word against his own life!"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, When Solomon was swearing that Adonijah would be killed, how did he describe God?","answer":"Now therefore, as the Lord lives,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, When Solomon was swearing that Adonijah would be killed, he described 3 things that the Lord had done for him. What was the first thing?","answer":"who has confirmed me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, When Solomon was swearing that Adonijah would be killed, he described 3 things that the Lord had done for him. What was the second thing?","answer":"and set me on the throne of David my father,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, When Solomon was swearing that Adonijah would be killed, he described 3 things that the Lord had done for him. What was the third thing?","answer":"and who has established a house for me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, Had the Lord told Solomon the he was going to be made king?","answer":"as He promised,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:24, what did Solomon swear would be done to his brother that day?","answer":"Adonijah shall be put to death today!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:25, who did Solomon send to kill his brother?","answer":"So King Solomon sent by the hand of Benaiah the son of Jehoiada;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:25, how did Benaiah kill Jehoiada?","answer":"and he struck him down,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:25, what happened to Jehoiada when Benaiah struck him?","answer":"and he died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, who did Solomon send to Anathoth?","answer":"And to Abiathar the priest the king said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, to what place did Solomon send Abiathar?","answer":"\u201cGo to Anathoth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, where is Anathoth did Solomon send Abiathar?","answer":"to your own fields,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, what punishment did Solomon say Abiathar deserved?","answer":"for you are deserving of death;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, did Solomon initially decide to kill Abiathar?","answer":"but I will not put you to death at this time,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, there were two reasons why did Solomon decide initially to not kill Abiathr.  What was the first reason?","answer":"because you carried the ark of the Lord God before my father David,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:26, there were two reasons why did Solomon decide initially to not kill Abiathr.  What was the second reason?","answer":"and because you were afflicted every time my father was afflicted.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:27, Did Abiathar continue as a priest when Solomon sent him to Anathoth?","answer":"So Solomon removed Abiathar from being priest to the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:27, What was the reason the Lord had for Solomon to remove Abiathar from the priesthood?","answer":"that he might fulfill the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:27, when he send Abiathar to Anathoth, Solomon was fulfilling a prophecy concerning what?","answer":"which He spoke concerning the house of Eli at Shiloh."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:28, what motivated Joab to flee to the tabernacle of the Lord?","answer":"Then news came to Joab,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:28, why was Joab afriad?","answer":"for Joab had defected to Adonijah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:28, had Joab been unfaithful to David in the past?","answer":"though he had not defected to Absalom."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:28, to what tent did Joab flee for safety from Solomon?","answer":"So Joab fled to the tabernacle of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:28, what did Joab do in the tabernacle of the Lord when he fled for his life?","answer":"and took hold of the horns of the altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:29, How did Solomon learn that someone was by the brazen alter?","answer":"And King Solomon was told, \u201cJoab has fled to the tabernacle of the Lord;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:29, Solomon told that Joab was where in the tabernacle?","answer":"there he is, by the altar.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:29, Who did Solomon send to Joab in the tabernacle?","answer":"Then Solomon sent Benaiah the son of Jehoiada,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:29, What did Solomon tell Benaiah the son of Jehoiada to do to Joab who was in the tabernacle?","answer":"saying, \u201cGo, strike him down.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:30, Where did Benaiah go when Solomon told him to kill Joab?","answer":"So Benaiah went to the tabernacle of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:30, What message did Benaiah give Joab in the tabernacle of the Lord?","answer":"and said to him, \u201cThus says the king, \u2018Come out!\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:30, How did Joab reply to the message from the king to come out of the tabernacle?","answer":"And he said, \u201cNo, but I will die here.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:30, What did Benaiah do when Joab didn't come out of the tabernacle?","answer":"And Benaiah brought back word to the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:30, What did Benaiah tell Solomon when Joab ask to die in the tabernacle?","answer":"saying, \u201cThus said Joab, and thus he answered me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, What did Solomon do when he was told Joab wanted to die in the tabernacle?","answer":"Then the king said to him, \u201cDo as he has said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, What did Solomon say should be done to kill Joab?","answer":"and strike him down"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, What did Solomon should be done after Joab was killed?","answer":"and bury him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, From whom did Solomon want to remove the innocent blood which Joab had Shed?","answer":"that you may take away from me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, From where did Solomon want to remove the innocent blood which Joab had Shed?","answer":"and from the house of my father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:31, When explaining why he wanted Joab to be killed, what did Solomon say he want to be removed from the house of his father?","answer":"the innocent blood which Joab shed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, what would be returned to Joab?","answer":"So the Lord will return his blood on his head,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, how did Joab treat his contenders that were better then he was?","answer":"because he struck down two men more righteous and better than he,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, What weapon did Joab use to kill Abner and Amasa?","answer":"and killed them with the sword\u2014"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, What was the full name of the commander of the army of Israel?","answer":"Abner the son of Ner,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, What role did Abner have?","answer":"the commander of the army of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32,  What was the full name of the commander of the army of Judah?","answer":"and Amasa the son of Jether,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, What role did Amasa have?","answer":"the commander of the army of Judah\u2014"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:32, Did David know that Joab was going to kill Abner and Amasa?","answer":"though my father David did not know it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:33, Solomon wanted the guilt of Abner and Amasa's death to go on two places.  Where was the first place?","answer":"Their blood shall therefore return upon the head of Joab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:33, Solomon wanted the guilt of Abner and Amasa's death to go on two places.  Where was the second place?","answer":"and upon the head of his descendants forever."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:33, Solomon wanted peace upon four places.  What were the first two?","answer":"But upon David and his descendants,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:33, Solomon wanted peace upon four places.  What were the second two?","answer":"upon his house and his throne,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:33, What did Solomon expected to be on David's descendants as a result of Joab's death?","answer":"there shall be peace forever from the Lord.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:34, who killed Joab?","answer":"So Benaiah the son of Jehoiada"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:34, there were 4 things that Benaiah did after Solomon told him to kill Joab in the tabernacle.  What were the first three?","answer":"went up and struck and killed him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:34, what happened to Joab after Benaiah killed him?","answer":"and he was buried"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:34, where was Joab buried?","answer":"in his own house in the wilderness."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:35, who filled Joab's position after his death?","answer":"The king put Benaiah the son of Jehoiada in his place over the army,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:35, who filled the priest's office after Abiathar was sent to Anathoth?","answer":"and the king put Zadok the priest in the place of Abiathar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:36, After ordering Joab to be killed who did Solomon ask to appear before him?","answer":"Then the king sent and called for Shimei,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:36, What did Solomon say Shimei should do in Jarusalem?","answer":"and said to him, \u201cBuild yourself a house in Jerusalem and dwell there,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:36, Where did Solomon say Shimei was free to roam before expanding the region to the Brook Kidron?","answer":"and do not go out from there anywhere."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:37, how long after crossing the Brook Kidron would Shimei be put to death?","answer":"For it shall be, on the day you go out"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:37, Shimei would be killed if he crossed what waterway?","answer":"and cross the Brook Kidron,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:37, what did Solomon tell Shimei would happen the day Shimei crossed the Brook Kidron?","answer":"know for certain you shall surely die;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:37, Who did Solomon tell Shimei would be guilty of his death if he crossed the Brook Kidron and was killed?","answer":"your blood shall be on your own head.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:38, Did Shimei like what the Solomon told him to do?","answer":"And Shimei said to the king, \u201cThe saying is good."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:38, when Shimei replied to Solomon, how did he address him?","answer":"As my lord the king has said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:38, what did Shimei say to indicate he intended to obey Solomon's order?","answer":"so your servant will do.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:38, was Shimei quick to disobey Solomon?","answer":"So Shimei dwelt in Jerusalem many days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:39, How many years did Shimei dwell in Jerusalem?","answer":"Now it happened at the end of three years,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:39, What did Shimei's slaves do at the end of Solomon's third year of reigning?","answer":"that two slaves of Shimei ran away to Achish the son of Maachah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:39, what role did Achish the son of Maachah have at the end of Solomon's third year?","answer":"king of Gath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:39, what message did Shimei receive from Achish's kingdom at the end of Solomon's third year?","answer":"And they told Shimei, saying, \u201cLook, your slaves are in Gath!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, Shimei did three or four things when he heard that his slaves had god to Gath.  What was the firs thing he did?","answer":"So Shimei arose,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, How did Shimei travel to Gath to get his slaves?","answer":"saddled his donkey,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, to whom did Shimei go to get his slaves?","answer":"and went to Achish at Gath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, why did Shimei go to Gath?","answer":"to seek his slaves."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, did Shimei stay in Jerusalem even when his slaves left him?","answer":"And Shimei went"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:40, what did Shimei do with his slaves after he had obtained them again?","answer":"and brought his slaves from Gath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:41, how did Solomon learn that Shimei had gone to Gath?","answer":"And Solomon was told"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:41, Solomon was told that someone had left Jerusalem and returned.  Who was it? and Where did he go?","answer":"that Shimei had gone from Jerusalem to Gath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:41, When Shimei left Jerusalem did Solomon hear if he came back?","answer":"and had come back."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, What was the first thing Solomon did when he heard Shimei had come back from Gath?","answer":"Then the king sent and called for Shimei,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, What did Solomon confirmed with Shimei that he made Shimei do?","answer":"and said to him, \u201cDid I not make you swear by the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, In addition to making Shimei swear by the Lord what type of message had Solomon given Shimei?","answer":"and warn you,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, what actions did Solomon remind Shimei would result in Shimie's death?","answer":"saying, \u2018Know for certain that on the day you go out and travel anywhere,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, what did Solomon remind Shimei would happen if Shimei traveled anywhere?","answer":"you shall surely die\u2019?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:42, How did Solomon remind Shimei that Shimei had agreed to stay in Jerusalem?","answer":"And you said to me, \u2018The word I have heard is good.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:43, Solomon ask Shimei a question about his promise before God.  What was this question?","answer":"Why then have you not kept the oath"},{"question":"According to 1 King 2:43, Solomon asked Shimei why he had not kept which oath?","answer":"of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:43, Solomon asked Shimei why he ad not kept two things.  The oath of the Lord and what else?","answer":"and the commandment that I gave you?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:44, who did Solomon say knew all the wickedness that Shimei did to David?","answer":"The king said moreover to Shimei, \u201cYou know,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:44, What did Solomon say about Shimei's heart?","answer":"as your heart acknowledges,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:44, What did Solomon say that Shimei knew?","answer":"all the wickedness that you did to my father David;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:44, What did Solomon say the Lord would do to Shimei?","answer":"therefore the Lord will return your wickedness on your own head."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:45, how did Solomon expect God to deal with him for putting Shimei to death?","answer":"But King Solomon shall be blessed,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:45, what lasting blessing did Solomon expect the Lord to do for his father?","answer":"and the throne of David shall be established before the Lord forever.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:46, Who did Solomon command to kill Shimei?","answer":"So the king commanded Benaiah the son of Jehoiada;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:46, What two actions did Benaiah do that resulted in Shimei's death?","answer":"and he went out and struck him down,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:46, What happened to Shimei when Benaiah struck him down?","answer":"and he died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 2:46, What was the result to the kingdom after Abiathar was sent to Anathoth and the death of Adonijah, Joab, and Shimei.","answer":"Thus the kingdom was established in the hand of Solomon."}
        
        
       
       /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],
    "c3":[
        
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, What is the first kingdom that Solomon made an agreement with after his kingdom was established?","answer":"Now Solomon made a treaty with Pharaoh king of Egypt,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, In addition to making a treaty with Paraoh, what else did Solomon do to secure good relations with Egypt?","answer":"and married Pharaoh\u2019s daughter;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, Where was the first place Solomon had for Pharaoh's daughter to live?","answer":"then he brought her to the City of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, There were thee construction projects Solomon completed before he moved Pharaoh's daughter out of the City of David. What is the first project listed?","answer":"until he had finished building his own house,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, There were thee construction projects Solomon completed before he moved Pharaoh's daughter out of the City of David. What is the second project listed?","answer":"and the house of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:1, There were thee construction projects Solomon completed before he moved Pharaoh's daughter out of the City of David. What is the third project listed?","answer":"and the wall all around Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:2, Where did people worship the Lord before the temple was built?","answer":"Meanwhile the people sacrificed at the high places,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:2, Why did people initially sacrifice at the high places?","answer":"because there was no house built for the name of the Lord until those days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:3, How did Solomon feel toward the Lord?","answer":"And Solomon loved the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:3, Did Solomon honor his father?","answer":"walking in the statutes of his father David,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:3, At what types of places did Solomon worship the Lord before the temple was built?","answer":"except that he sacrificed and burned incense at the high places."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:4, what was the name of the place that Solomon offered 1000 burnt offerings?","answer":"Now the king went to Gibeon to sacrifice there,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:4, why did Solomon choose Gibeon as the place to sacrifice 100 burnt offerings?","answer":"for that was the great high place:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:4, what did Solomon do at Gibeon to worship the Lord?","answer":"Solomon offered a thousand burnt offerings on that altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:5, during what time of day did God ask Solomon what he would like to have?","answer":"At Gibeon the Lord appeared to Solomon in a dream by night;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:5, When the Lord appeared to Solomon at Gibeon, what did he ask him?","answer":"and God said, \u201cAsk! What shall I give you?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, How did Solomon say that God had dealt with his father?","answer":"And Solomon said: \u201cYou have shown great mercy to Your servant David my father,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, Solomon listed 3 reasons that God had sown mercy to David.  What was the first reason?","answer":"because he walked before You in truth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, Solomon listed 3 reasons that God had sown mercy to David.  What was the second reason?","answer":"in righteousness,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, Solomon listed 3 reasons that God had sown mercy to David.  What was the third reason?","answer":"and in uprightness of heart with You;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, did Solomon think God's kindness to David was continuing after his death?","answer":"You have continued this great kindness for him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, what evidence did Solomon give that God's kindness to David was continuing beyond his death?","answer":"and You have given him a son to sit on his throne,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:6, Was Solomon reigning as king when the Lord appeared to him at Gibeon?","answer":"as it is this day."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:7, How did Solomon think that he had become king?","answer":"Now, O Lord my God, You have made Your servant king instead of my father David,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:7, How mature did Solomon feel he was to be king?","answer":"but I am a little child;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:7, What basic thing did Solomon say he didn't even know how to do that showed he was not knowledgeable enough to be king?","answer":"I do not know how to go out or come in."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:8, where was Solomon positioned compared to the people God had chosen?","answer":"And Your servant is in the midst of Your people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:8, Solomon used 3 different attributes to describe God's people. What was the first attribute?","answer":"whom You have chosen,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:8, Solomon used 3 different attributes to describe God's people. What was the second attribute?","answer":"a great people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:8, Solomon used 3 different attributes to describe God's people. What was the third attribute?","answer":"too numerous to be numbered or counted."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:9, When the Lord asked Solomon what he wanted, what did Solomon request?","answer":"Therefore give to Your servant an understanding heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:9, Solomon wanted an understanding heart to judge what?","answer":"to judge Your people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:9, Solomon wanted to be able to understand the difference between two opposite things. What were they?","answer":"that I may discern between good and evil."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:9, When Solomon was asking the Lord for an understanding heart he indicated that he didn't think anyone could really judge God's people.  How did he express this thought?","answer":"For who is able to judge this great people of Yours?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 3:10, How did the Lord feel about the thing Solomon had requested?","answer":"The speech pleased the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 10, The speech pleased the Lord, that [who] had [done what].","answer":"that [Solomon] had [asked this thing]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 11, Then God said to him: \u201cBecause you have [what], and have not asked long life for yourself,","answer":"Then God said to him: \u201cBecause you have [asked this thing],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:11, God listed three things he was pleased that Solomon did not request. What was the first thing?","answer":"and have not asked long life for yourself,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:11, God listed three things he was pleased that Solomon did not request. What was the second thing?","answer":"nor have asked riches for yourself,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:11, God listed three things he was pleased that Solomon did not request. What was the third thing?","answer":"nor have asked the life of your enemies,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:11, With what words did God summarize Solomon's request?","answer":"but have asked for yourself understanding to discern justice,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 12, behold, I have done [what]; see, I have given you a wise and understanding heart,","answer":"behold, I have done [according to your words];"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 12, behold, I have done according to your words; see, I have given you a _____ and _____ ______,","answer":"see, I have given you a [wise] and [understanding heart],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 12, behold, I have done according to your words; see, I have given you a wise and understanding heart, so that there has not been [what] before you,","answer":"so that there has not been [anyone like you] before you,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 12, behold, I have done according to your words; see, I have given you a wise and understanding heart, so that there has not been anyone like you before you, nor shall any like you [do what].","answer":"nor shall any like you [arise after you]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 13, And I have also given you [what]: both riches and honor,","answer":"And I have also given you [what you have not asked]:"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 13, And I have also given you what you have not asked: _____ ______ _____ _____, so that there shall not be anyone like you among the kings all your days.","answer":"[both riches and honor],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 13, And I have also given you what you have not asked: both riches and honor, so that there shall not be [what].","answer":"so that there shall not be [anyone like you among the kings all your days]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 14, So if you [do what], to keep My statutes and My commandments, as your father David walked, then I will lengthen your days.\u201d","answer":"So if you [walk in My ways],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 14, So if you walk in My ways, to [do what] and [what], as your father David walked, then I will lengthen your days.\u201d","answer":"to [keep My statutes] and [My commandments],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:14, God asked Solomon to walk in His ways like who did?","answer":"as your father David walked,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 14, So if you walk in My ways, to keep My statutes and My commandments, as your father David walked, then I will [do what].\u201d","answer":"then I will [lengthen your days].\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 King 3:15, how did Solomon realize it was in a dream that the Lord was speaking to him?","answer":"Then Solomon awoke;"},{"question":"According to 1 King 3:15, what did Solomon realize when he awoke?","answer":"and indeed it had been a dream."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:15, to what city did Solomon go after he left Gibeon?","answer":"And he came to Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:15, where did Solomon stand when returned to Jerusalem?","answer":"and stood before the ark of the covenant of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:15, Solomon offered two type of offerings when he returned to Jerusalem from Gibeon.  What was the first type?","answer":"offered up burnt offerings,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:15, Solomon offered two type of offerings when he returned to Jerusalem from Gibeon.  What was the second type?","answer":"offered peace offerings,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:15, For whom did Solomon make a feast?","answer":"and made a feast for all his servants."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:16, How many women came to Solomon?","answer":"Now two women"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:16, What did the two women who came to Solomon do for a living?","answer":"who were harlots"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:16, To whom did the two harlots come?","answer":"came to the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:16, When the two harlots came to Solomon what is the first thing we know they did?","answer":"and stood before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:17, When the harlots came to Solomon, how did the woman address the King?","answer":"And one woman said, \u201cO my lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:17, Where did the two women dwell?","answer":"this woman and I dwell in the same house;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:17, what one woman do while the other was in the house?","answer":"and I gave birth while she was in the house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:18, When did the second woman also give birth?","answer":"Then it happened, the third day after I had given birth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:18, What happened the third day after the first woman had given birth?","answer":"that this woman also gave birth."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 18, And we were _____; no one was with us in the house, except the two of us in the house.","answer":"And we were [together];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:18, who was with the women and the babies in the house?","answer":"no one was with us in the house,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 3 verse 18, And we were together; no one was with us in the house, except [whom].","answer":"except [the two of us in the house]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:19, was the woman's child a girl or a boy?","answer":"And this woman\u2019s son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:19, what happened to the second woman's child when she lay on him?","answer":"died in the night,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:19, why did the second woman's child to die?","answer":"because she lay on him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:20, When did the second woman swap the children?","answer":"So she arose in the middle of the night"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:20, From where did the second woman take the first woman's child?","answer":"and took my son from my side,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:20, What was the first woman doing when the second woman swapped the children?","answer":"while your maidservant slept,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:20, Where did the second woman put the first woman's son?","answer":"and laid him in her bosom,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:20, Where did the second womon put her own son?","answer":"and laid her dead child in my bosom."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 3:21, When did the first woman try to nurse her son and discovered the child was dead.","answer":"And when I rose in the morning"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:21, What did the first woman intend to do when she rose in the morning?","answer":"to nurse my son,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:21, In the morning what was the first thing the first woman discovered about the child who was with her.","answer":"there he was, dead."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:21, how did the first woman discover that the child near her was not hers.","answer":"But when I had examined him in the morning,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:21, In the morning what was the second thing the first woman discovered about the child who was with her.","answer":"indeed, he was not my son whom I had borne.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, who was the first to say, \u201cNo! But the living one is my son,\u201d","answer":"Then the other woman said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, What did the second woman say about the living child?","answer":"\u201cNo! But the living one is my son,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, What did the second woman say about the dead child?","answer":"and the dead one is your son.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, who said, \u201cNo! But the dead one is your son,\u201d","answer":"And the first woman said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, What did the first woman say about the dead child?","answer":"\u201cNo! But the dead one is your son,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, What did the first woman say about the living child?","answer":"and the living one is my son.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:22, Did the prostitutes argue with each other before the king?","answer":"Thus they spoke before the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:23, Who in this verse showed good listening skills by summarizing what the two women had said?","answer":"And the king said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:23, How did Solomon summarize what the first woman said about the living child?","answer":"\u201cThe one says, \u2018This is my son, who lives,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:23, How did Solomon summarize what the first woman said abou the dead child?","answer":"and your son is the dead one\u2019;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:23, How did Solomon summarize what the second woman said about the dead child?","answer":"and the other says, \u2018No! But your son is the dead one,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:23, How did Solomon summarize what the second woman said about the living child?","answer":"and my son is the living one.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:24, After summarizing the argument that the women had, what did Solomon do next?","answer":"Then the king said, \u201cBring me a sword.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:24, When Solomon had heard the arguments of the women and Solomon made a command, what did they do?","answer":"So they brought a sword before the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:25, After asking for a sword, what did Solomon say should be done to the living child?","answer":"And the king said, \u201cDivide the living child in two,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:25, What did Solomon say should be given to the first woman?","answer":"and give half to one,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:25, What did Solomon say should be given to the second woman?","answer":"and half to the other.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, Who was the first to respond to the king when he said the child should be divided?","answer":"Then the woman whose son was living spoke to the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, Why did the mother of the living child respond to the king?","answer":"for she yearned with compassion for her son;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, How did the mother of the living child address the king?","answer":"and she said, \u201cO my lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, To whom did the mother of the living child ask for her child to be given?","answer":"give her the living child,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, What did the mother of the living child ask the king to not do?","answer":"and by no means kill him!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, The mother of the dead child agreed with Solomon's decision to divide the living child.  What reason did she give?","answer":"But the other said, \u201cLet him be neither mine nor yours,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:26, The mother of the dead child agreed that Solomon should do what with the living child?","answer":"but divide him.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:27, After hearing the women's responses to his command, to whom did Solomon say the child should be given?","answer":"So the king answered and said, \u201cGive the first woman the living child,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:27, After hearing the women's responses to his command, what did he say about dividing the living child?","answer":"and by no means kill him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:27, Why did Solomon say the child should be given to the first woman?","answer":"she is his mother.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:28, who heard of Solomon's judgement?","answer":"And all Israel heard of the judgment which the king had rendered;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:28, How did all Israel think about the king when they heard of his judgment of the two prostitutes?","answer":"and they feared the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 3:28, Why did all Israel fear king Solomon?","answer":"for they saw that the wisdom of God was in him to administer justice."}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
    ],
    "c4":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:1, what was the extent of Solomon's reign?","answer":"So King Solomon was king over all Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:2, Azariah was listed first in the list of Solomon's what?","answer":"And these were his officials:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:2, What was the first official listed in King Solomn's list of officials?","answer":"Azariah the son of Zadok,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:2, What role did Azariah have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"the priest;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:3, Who were Solomon's scribes (2 points)?","answer":"Elihoreph and Ahijah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:3, Who was the ancestor of Solomon's scribes?","answer":"the sons of Shisha,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:3, What role in Solomon's reign did Elihoreph and Ahijah have?","answer":"scribes;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:3, Who was the recorder for Solomon?","answer":"Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:3, What role for Solomon did Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud have?","answer":"the recorder;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:4, Who was over Solomon's army?","answer":"Benaiah the son of Jehoiada,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:4, What role did Solomon give Benaiah?","answer":"over the army;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:4, Who were the priests during Solomon's reign?","answer":"Zadok and Abiathar,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:4, What role did Zadok and Abiathar have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"the priests;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:5, what was the name of Solomon's official who was over the officers?","answer":"Azariah the son of Nathan,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:5, what role did Azariah the son of Nathan have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"over the officers;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:5, what was the name of Solomon's official who was a priest and his friend?","answer":"Zabud the son of Nathan,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:5, what role did Zabud the son of Nathan have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"a priest and the king\u2019s friend;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:6, Who was over Solomon's household?","answer":"Ahishar,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:6, What role did Ahishar have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"over the household;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:6, Who was over the labor force during Solomon's reign?","answer":"and Adoniram the son of Abda,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:6, What role did Adoniram the son of Abda have during Solomon's reign?","answer":"over the labor force."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:7, What officers provided food for Solomon?","answer":"And Solomon had twelve governors over all Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:7, What was the duty of Solomon's governors?","answer":"who provided food for the king and his household;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:7, For what duration of time did each governor need to provide food for Solomon?","answer":"each one made provision for one month of the year."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:8, what was the name of Solomon's governor in Ephraim?","answer":"These are their names: Ben-Hur,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:8, over what region was Ben-Hur governor?","answer":"in the mountains of Ephraim;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:9, What places was governor Ben-Dekr in charge of (4 points)?","answer":"Ben-Deker,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:9, Who was the governor in Makaz, Shaalbim, Beth Shemesh, and Elon Beth Hanan?","answer":"in Makaz, Shaalbim, Beth Shemesh, and Elon Beth Hanan;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:10 who was the governor over Arubboth, Sochoh and all the land of Hepher?","answer":"Ben-Hesed,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:10, Who was the governor of Arubboth, Sochoh and all the land of Hepher?","answer":"in Arubboth; to him belonged Sochoh and all the land of Hepher;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:11, Who was the governor in all the regions of Dor?","answer":"Ben-Abinadab,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:11, Ben-Abinadab was governor over what region?","answer":"in all the regions of Dor;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:11, who was Ben-Abinadab married to?","answer":"he had Taphath the daughter of Solomon as wife;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:12, Who governed Taanach, Megiddo among other places?","answer":"Baana the son of Ahilud,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:12, The description of the territory of Baana includes the names of 7 places.  What are they?","answer":"in Taanach, Megiddo, and all Beth Shean, which is beside Zaretan below Jezreel, from Beth Shean to Abel Meholah, as far as the other side of Jokneam;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, Who was governor over Gilead and Bashan?","answer":"Ben-Geber, in Ramoth Gilead;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, What was the name of the governor in the town of Ramoth-Gilead?","answer":"Ben-Geber, in Ramoth Gilead;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, Manassah had a son with towns named after him -- what was his name?","answer":"to him belonged the towns of Jair the son of Manasseh,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, Ben-Geber was governor over what area, with the towns of Ramoth Gilead and Jair in it?","answer":"in Gilead;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, Ben-Geber was governor not only over the area of Gilead, but also the region of what in Bashan?","answer":"to him also belonged the region of Argob"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, The region of Argob was in what country?","answer":"in Bashan\u2014"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, How many large cities with walls and bronze gate-bars were in Bashan?","answer":"sixty"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, There were 60 what with walls and bronze gate-bars in Bashan?","answer":"large cities"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:13, 2 pts.  What was noteable about the 60 large cities in Bashan?","answer":"with walls and bronze gate-bars;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:14, What was the name of Iddo's sone?","answer":"Ahinadab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:14, Who was the governor over Mahanaim?","answer":"Ahinadab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:14, Ahinadab was the son of whom?","answer":"the son of Iddo,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:14, Ahinadab was governor over what area?","answer":"in Mahanaim;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:15, Naphtali had whom as governor?","answer":"Ahimaaz,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:15, Ahimaaz was governor where?","answer":"in Naphtali;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:15, Ahimaaz was married to whom?","answer":"he also took Basemath the daughter of Solomon as wife;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:11-15, BONUS:  Name the 2 governors who had Solomon as a father-in-law.","answer":"Ben-Abinadab, Ahimaaz"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:11-15, BONUS:  Name the 2 daughters of Solomon who were married to governors.","answer":"Taphath, Basemath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:16, What was the name of the son of Hushai?","answer":"Baanah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:16, Who was governor over Asher and Aloth?","answer":"Baanah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:16, Baanah was the son of whom?","answer":"the son of Hushai,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:16, Baanah was governor of what two places?","answer":"in Asher and Aloth;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:17, Who was governor over Issachar?","answer":"Jehoshaphat the son of Paruah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:17, Where did Jehoshaphat the son of Paruah govern?","answer":"in Issachar;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:18, Who was the governor in Benjamin?","answer":"Shimei the son of Elah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:18, Who was the son of Elah?","answer":"Shimei the son of Elah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:18, Where was Shimei the son of Elah governor?","answer":"in Benjamin;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:19, Name the father of the Geber who governed over the Amorites and in Bashan?","answer":"Geber the son of Uri,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 19, Geber the son of Uri, in [where], in the country of Sihon king of the Amorites, and of Og king of Bashan. He was the only governor who was in the land.","answer":"in [the land of Gilead],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:19, Geber the son of Uri governed the areas of Gilead (not covered by Ben-Geber), and in the country of where, and of Og king of Bashan?","answer":"in the country of Sihon king of the Amorites,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:19, Geber the son of Uri governed the areas of Gilead (not covered by Ben-Geber), and in the country of Sihon king of the Amorites, and where else?","answer":"and of Og king of Bashan."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:19, T or F:  (trick question!)  Geber was the only governor who was in the land.","answer":"He was the only governor who was in the land."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:8-19, BONUS:  Can you name the 12 governors, but no need to include the names of their fathers.","answer":"Ben-Hur, Ben-Deker, Ben-Hesed, Ben-Abinadab, Baana, Ben-Geber, Ahinadab, Ahimaaz, Baanah, Jehoshaphat, Shimei, Geber"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:20, 2 pts.  What were as numerous as the sand by the sea in multitude?","answer":"Judah and Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:20, There were so many people in Judah and Israel they were compared to what?","answer":"were as numerous as the sand by the sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:20, In what measurement were Judah and Israel compared to sand by the sea?","answer":"in multitude,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:20, What did Judah and Israel do during Solomon's reign?","answer":"eating and drinking and rejoicing."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:21, Who reigned over the kingdoms from the River","answer":"So Solomon reigned over all kingdoms"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:21, What were the north-east and central west boarders of Solomon's reign?","answer":"from the River to the land of the Philistines,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:21, What was the south-west boarder of Solomon's reign?","answer":"as far as the border of Egypt."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:21, How long did Solomon receive tribute from the surrounding kingdoms?","answer":"They brought tribute and served Solomon all the days of his life."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:22, How long would would it take Solomon to consume 30 kors of fine flour and 60 kors of meal?","answer":"Now Solomon\u2019s provision for one day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:22, How much was Solomon's daily provision of fine flour.","answer":"was thirty kors of fine flour,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:22, How much was Solomon's daily provision of meal.","answer":"sixty kors of meal,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:23, How many fatted oxen did Solomon use in 1 day?","answer":"ten fatted oxen,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:23, How many oxen from the pastures did Solomon use in 1 day?","answer":"twenty oxen from the pastures,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:23, How many sheep did Solomon use in 1 day?","answer":"and one hundred sheep,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:23, 4 pts.  What else besides oxen and sheep did Solomon use in 1 day?","answer":"besides deer, gazelles, roebucks, and fatted fowl."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 24, For he had _____ over all the region on [where] from Tiphsah even to Gaza, namely over all the kings on this side of the River; and he had peace on every side all around him.","answer":"For he had [dominion] over all the region on [this side of the River]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 24, For he had dominion over all the region on this side of the River from _____ even to _____, namely over all the kings on this side of the River; and he had peace on every side all around him.","answer":"from [Tiphsah] even to [Gaza],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 24, For he had dominion over all the region on this side of the River from Tiphsah even to Gaza, namely over [whom] [where]; and he had peace on every side all around him.","answer":"namely over [all the kings] [on this side of the River];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:24, What did Solomon have on every side all around him?","answer":"and he had peace"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:24, Where did Solomon have peace?","answer":"on every side all around him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:25, (2 points) Who dwelt safely?","answer":"And Judah and Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:25, How did Judah and Israel dwell during Solomon's reign?","answer":"dwelt safely,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:25, During Solomon's reign, where on his own property did each subject dwelt safely?","answer":"each man under his vine and his fig tree,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:25, Between what two towns did Solomon's subjects dwell safely during Solomon's reign?","answer":"from Dan as far as Beersheba,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:25, During what portion of Solomon's life did Judah and Israel dwell safely?","answer":"all the days of Solomon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:26, How many stalls of horses for chariots did Solomon have?","answer":"Solomon had forty thousand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:26, Solomon had 40,000 of something for his chariots.  Of what did he have 40,000?","answer":"stalls of horses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:26, Solomon had 40,000 stalls of horses for what?","answer":"for his chariots,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:26, How many horsemen did Solomon have?","answer":"and twelve thousand horsemen."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:27, who provided food for King Solomon?","answer":"And these governors,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:27, when did each governor provide food for Solomon?","answer":"each man in his month,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:27, What did one of the 12 governors provide monthly to the King?","answer":"provided food"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:27, Who did the governors' provisions feed in addition to King Solomon?","answer":"for King Solomon and for all who came to King Solomon\u2019s table."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:27, by how much did the governors fail to meet their quota for King Solomon?","answer":"There was no lack in their supply."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:28, What did the governors provide for Solomon's horses and steeds?","answer":"They also brought barley and straw"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:28, To where did the governors bring barley and straw? (be specific)","answer":"to the proper place,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:28, For whom or what did the governors provide barley and straw? (2 points)","answer":"for the horses and steeds,"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 28, They also brought barley and straw to the proper place, for the horses and steeds, each man according to [what].","answer":"each man according to [his charge]."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 29, And God gave Solomon [what] and exceedingly great understanding, and largeness of heart like the sand on the seashore.","answer":"And God gave Solomon [wisdom]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 29, And God gave Solomon wisdom and [what], and largeness of heart like the sand on the seashore.","answer":"and [exceedingly great understanding],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 29, And God gave Solomon wisdom and exceedingly great understanding, and [what] like the sand on the seashore.","answer":"and [largeness of heart]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 29, And God gave Solomon wisdom and exceedingly great understanding, and largeness of heart like [what].","answer":"like [the sand on the seashore]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:30, How did Solomon's wisdom compare that the men of the East and the wisdom of Egypt?","answer":"Thus Solomon\u2019s wisdom excelled the wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 30, Thus Solomon\u2019s wisdom excelled the wisdom [whom] and all the wisdom of Egypt.","answer":"[of all the men of the East]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 4 verse 30, Thus Solomon\u2019s wisdom excelled the wisdom of all the men of the East and all the wisdom of [where].","answer":"and all the wisdom of [Egypt]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, How did Solomon compare to Ethan the Ezrahite and the sons of Mahol?","answer":"For he was wiser"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, Solomon was wiser than how many men?","answer":"than all men\u2014"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, Solomon was wiser than which Ethan?","answer":"than Ethan the Ezrahite,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, Solomon was wiser than which sons of Mahol?","answer":"and Heman, Chalcol, and Darda,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, who was the father of Heman, Chalcol, Darda?","answer":"the sons of Mahol;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, what about Solomon was known in all the surrounding nations?","answer":"and his fame was"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:31, where was Solomon's fame?","answer":"in all the surrounding nations."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:32, how many proverbs did Solomon speak?","answer":"He spoke three thousand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:32, Solomon knew 3000 what?","answer":"proverbs,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:32, Solomon knew 1005 what?","answer":"and his songs were"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:32, Solomon knew how many songs?","answer":"one thousand and five."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:33, What grand type of plants did Solomon speak about?","answer":"Also he spoke of trees,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:33, What was the grandest type of tree of which Solomon spoke?","answer":"from the cedar tree of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:33, What was the smallest type of tree of which Solomon spoke?","answer":"even to the hyssop"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:33, where does hyssop grow?","answer":"that springs out of the wall;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:33, Of what items from the animal kingdom did Solomon speak?","answer":"he spoke also of animals, of birds, of creeping things, and of fish."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:34, Who had heard of Solomon's wisdom?","answer":"And men of all nations,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:34, Men of all nations came from where to hear the wisdom of Solomon?","answer":"from all the kings of the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:34, Men who had heard of what came to Solomon?","answer":"who had heard of his wisdom,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 4:34, Why did did men of all nations come?","answer":"came to hear the wisdom of Solomon."}
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],
    "c5":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:1, What was the name of the king of Tyre?","answer":"Now Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:1, Hiram was king of what place?","answer":"king of Tyre"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:1, Whom did Hiram king of Tyre send to Solomon?","answer":"sent his servants to Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:1, What did Hiram king of Tyre hear so that he sent his servants to Solomon?","answer":"because he heard that they had anointed him king in place of his father,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:1, How had Hiram felt about David?","answer":"for Hiram had always loved David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:2, Who sent to Hiram?","answer":"Then Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:2, Solomon sent to whom?","answer":"sent to Hiram, saying:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, who was not able to build a house for the name of the Lord his God?","answer":"You know how my father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, what was David not able to do for the name of the Lord his God?","answer":"could not build a house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, You know how my father David could not build a house for what?  Be specific.","answer":"for the name of the Lord his God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, Why could Solomon's father David not build a house for the name of the Lord his God?","answer":"because of the wars which were fought against him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, Where were the wars fought against David?","answer":"on every side,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, What did the Lord put under the soles of David's feet?","answer":"until the Lord put his foes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:3, Where did the Lord put David's foes?","answer":"under the soles of his feet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:4, What had God given Solomon?","answer":"But now the Lord my God has given me rest"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:4, Where had God given Solomon rest?","answer":"on every side;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 5 verse 4, But now the Lord my God has given me rest on every side; there is neither _____ nor _____ ______.","answer":"there is neither [adversary] nor [evil occurrence]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, what did Solomon propose to do?","answer":"And behold, I propose to build a house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, Solomon proposed to build a house for whom?","answer":"for the name of the Lord my God,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, Who told Solomon's dad that Solomon would build a house for God?","answer":"as the Lord spoke to my father David, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, Who did God tell David would build a house for His name?","answer":"\u201cYour son,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, Which son of David did God say would build a house for His name?","answer":"whom I will set on your throne in your place,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:5, What did God tell David Solomon would do?","answer":"he shall build the house for My name.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, What did Solomon ask Hiram to command be done in Lebanon for Solomon?","answer":"Now therefore, command that they cut down cedars for me"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, From where did Solomon ask Hiram to cut down cedars?","answer":"from Lebanon;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, Where did Solomon say his servants would be while Hiram's servants were cutting down trees?","answer":"and my servants will be with your servants,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, What did Solomon say he would do for Hiram in exchange for the labor of his servants?","answer":"and I will pay you wages"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, Solomon agreed to pay Hiram wages for what?","answer":"for your servants"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, How much was Solomon willing to pay Hiram for his servants?","answer":"according to whatever you say."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, Why did Solomon ask Hiram to help cut the timber?","answer":"For you know there is none among us who has skill"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, What did Solomon say the Sidonians were more skilled at doing than Solomon's servants?","answer":"to cut timber"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:6, Who was more skilled to cut timber than Solomon's servants?","answer":"like the Sidonians."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, When did Hiram rejoice greatly?","answer":"So it was, when Hiram heard the words of Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, Who rejoiced greatly when he heard the words of  Solomon?","answer":"So it was, when Hiram heard the words of Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, What did Hiram do when he heard the words of Solomon?","answer":"that he rejoiced greatly and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, Who did Hiram bless when he heard Solomon\u2019s words?","answer":"Blessed be the Lord this day,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, Why did Hiram say, \"Blessed be the Lord...\"?","answer":"for He has given David a wise son"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:7, How did Hiram describe the people in Solomon's kingdom?","answer":"over this great people!"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:8, Who said that he would do all that Solomon desired?","answer":"Then Hiram sent to Solomon, saying:"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:8, What did Hiram say he did with Solomon's message?","answer":"I have considered the message which you sent me,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:8, Which of Solomon's requests did Hiram agree to do concerning the logs?","answer":"and I will do all you desire"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:8, From what types of trees did Hiram agree to provide logs?","answer":"concerning the cedar and cypress logs."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, Who shall bring logs down from Lebanon to the sea?","answer":"My servants shall bring them down"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, Between what two locations did Hiram offer for his servant to transport logs before make rafts?","answer":"from Lebanon to the sea;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, How did Hiram plan to transport the logs in the sea?","answer":"I will float them in rafts"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, In what did Hiram plan to float the rafts to get them to the place Solomon would indicate?","answer":"by sea"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, To what location did Hiram offer to deliver the logs?","answer":"to the place you indicate to me,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, What would Hiram do with the rafts once they were delivered to the place Solomon would indicate?","answer":"and will have them broken apart there;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, Once the rafts were broken apart, what did Hiram ask Solomon to do with the logs?","answer":"then you can take them away."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, What would giving food for Hiram's household accomplish for him?","answer":"And you shall fulfill my desire"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:9, Hiram ask Solomon to fulfill his desire by doing what?","answer":"by giving food for my household."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:10, who gave Solomon logs?","answer":"Then Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:10, to whom did Hiram give logs?","answer":"gave Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:10, (2 points) what type of wood did Hiram give Solomon?","answer":"cedar and cypress logs"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:10, How many of which logs did Hiram give Solomon?","answer":"according to all his desire."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:11, How much wheat did Solomon give Hiram?","answer":"And Solomon gave Hiram twenty thousand kors"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:11, Solomon gave Hiram 20,000 kors of something as food for his household?  What was this something?","answer":"of wheat as food for his household,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:11, How much pressed oil did Solomon give Hiram?","answer":"and twenty kors"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:11, Solomon gave Hiram 20 kors of something to Hiram.  What was this something?","answer":"of pressed oil."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:11, How often did Solomon give Hiram 20,000 kors of wheat and 20 kors of pressed oil for his household in exchange for cedar and cypress logs according to all his desire?","answer":"Thus Solomon gave to Hiram year by year."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:12, What did the Lord do for Solomon as he had promised him?","answer":"So the Lord gave Solomon wisdom,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:12, Why did the Lord give Solomon wisdom?","answer":"as He had promised him;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:12, Describe the relationship between Hiram and Solomon when they made a treaty together.","answer":"and there was peace between Hiram and Solomon,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:12, What did Hiram and Solomon do together?","answer":"and the two of them made a treaty together."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:13, What did Solomon raise up out of all Israel?","answer":"Then King Solomon raised up a labor force"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:13, Then King Solomon raised up a labor force out of where?","answer":"out of all Israel;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:13, There were 30,000 men on what?","answer":"and the labor force"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:13, How many men were on Solomon's labor force?","answer":"was thirty thousand men."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, Where did Solomon send his labor force in shifts?","answer":"And he sent them to Lebanon,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, How many people did Solomon send to Lebanon each month?","answer":"ten thousand a month"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, Solomon sent men to Lebanon, 10,000 a month how?","answer":"in shifts:"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, How long was each shift of Solomon's labor force in Lebanon?","answer":"they were one month in Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, How long was each shift of Solomon's labor force at home?","answer":"and two months"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, Solomon's men were in Lebanon for 1 month and then where for 2 months?","answer":"at home;"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, Who was in charge of Solomon's labor force?","answer":"Adoniram"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:14, What was Adoniram's responsibility?","answer":"was in charge of the labor force."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:15, How many of Solomon's men carried burdens?","answer":"Solomon had seventy thousand"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:15, Solomon had 70,000 men who did what?","answer":"who carried burdens,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:15, How many of Solomon's men quarried stone in the mountains?","answer":"and eighty thousand"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 5:15, Solomon and 80,000 men who did what?","answer":"who quarried stone in the mountains,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:16, Solomon had 150,000 laborers, besides how many chief deputies?","answer":"besides three thousand three hundred"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:16, From what group of people did Solomon select 3,300 men to supervise the laborers?","answer":"from the chiefs of Solomon\u2019s deputies,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:16, What did Solomon assign 3,300 of the chiefs of his deputies to do?","answer":"who supervised the people who labored in the work."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:17, Who commanded the people to quarry stones?","answer":"And the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:17, What did the king command to be done regarding stones?","answer":"commanded them to quarry"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:17, Solomon commanded his men to quarry what 3 things?","answer":"large stones, costly stones, and hewn stones,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:17, What was to be done with the stones Solomon's men quarried?","answer":"to lay the foundation of the temple."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:18, Who quarried the stones and prepared both the stones and the timber?","answer":"So Solomon\u2019s builders, Hiram\u2019s builders, and the Gebalites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:18, In addition to preparing the stones what did Solomon's builders, Hiram's builders, and the Gebalites do with them?","answer":"quarried them;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:18, In addition to quarrying the stones what did the Gebalites do to help build the temple.","answer":"and they prepared timber and stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 5:18, For what purpose did Solomon's builders, Hiram's builders, and the Gebalites prepare timber and stones?","answer":"to build the temple."}
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],
    "c6":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, In what year after the Israelites left Egypt did Solomon begin to build the house of the Lord?","answer":"And it came to pass in the four hundred and eightieth year"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, Solomon began to build the house of the Lord in the 480th year after who left Egypt?","answer":"after the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, Solomon began to build the house of the Lord in the 480th year after the children of Israel did what?","answer":"had come out of the land of Egypt,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, The 480th year after the children of Israel had come out of the land of Egypt was in which year of Solomon's reign over Israel?","answer":"in the fourth year of Solomon\u2019s reign over Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, What was the name of the month when he (Solomon) began to build the house of the Lord?","answer":"in the month of Ziv,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, Which month of the year is the month of Ziv?","answer":"which is the second month,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, What did Solomon begin to do the 480th year after the children of Israel had come out of the land of Egypt?","answer":"that he began to build the house of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:1, What did Solomon begin to do during the 2nd month in the 4th year of his reign?","answer":"that he began to build the house of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:2, What building measured 60 cubits long x 20 cubits wide x 30 cubits in height?","answer":"Now the house which King Solomon built for the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:2, What was the length of the house which King Solomon built for the Lord?","answer":"its length was sixty cubits,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:2, What was the width of the house which King Solomon built for the Lord?","answer":"its width twenty,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:2, What was the height of the house which King Solomon built for the Lord?","answer":"and its height thirty cubits."},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, What was in front of the sanctuary of the house which was 20 cubits across the width of the house?","answer":"The vestibule"},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, The vestibule in front of what was 20 cubits long across the width of the house?","answer":"in front of the sanctuary of the house"},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, The vestibule in front of the sanctuary of the house was how long across the width of the house?","answer":"was twenty cubits long across the width of the house,"},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, The width of what extended 10 cubits from the front of the house?","answer":"and the width of the vestibule"},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, The width of the vestibule extended how far from the front of the house?","answer":"extended ten cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 King 6:3, The width of the vestibule extended 10 cubits from what?","answer":"from the front of the house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:4, What did he make for the house with beveled frames?","answer":"And he made for the house windows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:4, He made for the house windows with what feature?","answer":"with beveled frames."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:5, Against where he built chambers all around?","answer":"Against the wall of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:5, Against the wall of the temple he built what all around?","answer":"he built chambers"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 5, Against the wall of the temple he built chambers all _____, against the _____ ______ _____ _____, all around the sanctuary and the inner sanctuary.","answer":"all [around], against the [walls of the temple],"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:5, 2 points.  He built chambers all around, against the walls of the temple, all around the what?","answer":"all around the sanctuary and the inner sanctuary."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:5, Thus he made what all around the sanctuary?","answer":"Thus he made side chambers all around it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, What was 5 cubits wide?","answer":"The lowest chamber"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, The lowest chamber was how wide?","answer":"was five cubits wide,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, What was 6 cubits wide?","answer":"the middle"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, The middle (chamber) was how wide?","answer":"was six cubits wide,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, What was 7 cubits wide?","answer":"and the third"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, The third (topmost side chambers) was how wide?","answer":"was seven cubits wide;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, What did he make around the outside of the temple, so that the support beams would not be fasted into the walls of the temple?","answer":"for he made narrow ledges"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, He made narrow ledges where, so that the support beams would not be fastened into the walls of the temple?","answer":"around the outside of the temple,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, He made narrow ledges around the outside of the temple, so that what would not be fastened into the walls of the temple?","answer":"so that the support beams"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:6, He made narrow ledges around the outside of the temple, so that the support beams would not be fastened into what?","answer":"would not be fastened into the walls of the temple."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, And the what, when it was being built, was built with stone finished at the quarry?","answer":"And the temple,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, The temple, when it was what, was built with stone finished at the quarry?","answer":"when it was being built,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, The temple, when it was being built, was built with what finished at the quarry?","answer":"was built with stone"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, The temple, when it was being built, was built with stone finished where?","answer":"finished at the quarry,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, 3 pts.  The temple, \u2026 was built with stone finished at the quarry, so that no what was heard in the temple while it was being built?","answer":"so that no hammer or chisel or any iron tool"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:7, The temple, \u2026 was built with stone finished at the quarry, so that no hammer or chisel or any iron tool was what while it was being built?","answer":"was heard in the temple while it was being built."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:8, The doorway for what was on the right side of the temple?","answer":"The doorway for the middle story"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:8, The doorway for the middle story was where?","answer":"was on the right side of the temple."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:8, They went up how to the middle story, and from the middle story to the third?","answer":"They went up by stairs"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:8, They went up by stairs to where, and from the middle to the third?","answer":"to the middle story,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:8, They went up by stairs to the middle story, and from the middle to where?","answer":"and from the middle to the third."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:9, So he built what and finished it?","answer":"So he built the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:9, So he built the temple and did what?","answer":"and finished it,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:9, ...and he did what with beams and boards of cedar?","answer":"and he paneled the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:9, ...and he paneled the temple with what?","answer":"with beams and boards of cedar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:10, He built what against the entire temple, each 5 cubits high?","answer":"And he built side chambers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:10, He built side chambers against what, each 5 cubits high?","answer":"against the entire temple,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:10, He built side chambers against the entire temple, each how high?","answer":"each five cubits high;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:10, What was five cubits high?","answer":"each five cubits high;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:10, The side chambers were attached to the temple with what?","answer":"they were attached to the temple with cedar beams."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 11, Then [what] came to Solomon, saying:","answer":"Then [the word of the Lord]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 11, Then the word of the Lord came to [whom], saying:","answer":"came to [Solomon], saying:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:12, the Lord spoke to Solomon about which temple?","answer":"\u201cConcerning this temple which you are building,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:12, what 4 conditions did the Lord tell Solomon he needed to meet for the Lord to do for him as he had promised David.","answer":"if you walk in My statutes, execute My judgments, keep all My commandments, and walk in them,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:12, what blessing would Solomon receive if he did as the Lord instructed him?","answer":"then I will perform My word with you,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:12, the Lord spoke to Solomon about his word which he spoke to whom?","answer":"which I spoke to your father David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:13, What did the Lord say he would do among the children of Israel?","answer":"And I will dwell"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:13, Where did the Lord say he would dwell?","answer":"among the children of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:13, What did the Lord say he would not do?","answer":"and will not forsake My people Israel.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 14, So Solomon _____ the _____ and _____ it.","answer":"So Solomon [built] the [temple] and [finished] it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:15, What did Solomon build with cedar boards?","answer":"And he built the inside walls of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:15, Solomon built the inside walls of the temple with what?","answer":"with cedar boards;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 15, And he built the inside walls of the temple with cedar boards; from [where] to [where] he paneled the inside with wood; and he covered the floor of the temple with planks of cypress.","answer":"from [the floor of the temple] to [the ceiling]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 15, And he built the inside walls of the temple with cedar boards; from the floor of the temple to the ceiling he [did what] with wood; and he covered the floor of the temple with planks of cypress.","answer":"he [paneled the inside] with wood;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:15, What did he cover with planks of cypress?","answer":"and he covered the floor of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:15, He covered the floor of the temple with what?","answer":"with planks of cypress."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, Then he built the what size room at the rear of the temple?","answer":"Then he built the twenty-cubit room"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, Then he built the 20 cubit room where?","answer":"at the rear of the temple,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, He built the 20 cubit room at the rear of the temple, from where to where, with cedar boards?","answer":"from floor to ceiling,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, What did he build the 20 cubit room at the rear of the temple with?","answer":"with cedar boards;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, What is another name for the Most Holy Place?","answer":"he built it inside as the inner sanctuary,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:16, What is another name for the inner sanctuary?","answer":"as the Most Holy Place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:17, Where was the temple sanctuary compared to the Most Holy Place?","answer":"And in front of it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:17, What was in front of the Most Holy Place?","answer":"the temple sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:17, How long was the temple sanctuary not counting the Most Holy Place?","answer":"was forty cubits long."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:18, Where was cedar, carved with ornamental buds and open flowers?","answer":"The inside of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:18, What type of wood was carved with ornamental buds and open flowers?","answer":"was cedar,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:18, 2 pts.  The inside of the temple was cedar, carved with what?","answer":"carved with ornamental buds and open flowers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:18, Inside the temple on what portion of the ceiling, walls and floor could cedar be seen?","answer":"All was cedar;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:18, Inside the temple on what portion of the ceiling, walls and floor could stone be seen?","answer":"there was no stone to be seen."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:19, where did Solomon prepare for the ark of the covenant?","answer":"And he prepared the inner sanctuary inside the temple,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:19, For what did Solomon prepared the inner sanctuary inside the temple?","answer":"to set the ark of the covenant of the Lord there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:20, what was 20 cubits long, 20 cubits wide, and 20 cubits high?","answer":"The inner sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:20, What were the dimensions of the inner sanctuary?","answer":"was twenty cubits long, twenty cubits wide, and twenty cubits high."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:20, With what was the inner sancutary overlaid?","answer":"He overlaid it with pure gold,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:20, What besides the inner sanctuary was overlaid with pure gold?","answer":"and overlaid the altar of cedar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:21, So Solomon overlaid what with pure gold?","answer":"So Solomon overlaid the inside of the temple with pure gold."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:21, What was across the front of the inner sanctuary?","answer":"He stretched gold chains"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:21, Where did Solomon stretch gold chains?","answer":"across the front of the inner sanctuary,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:21, with what did Solomon overlay the gold chains?","answer":"and overlaid it with gold."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 22, The whole temple he [did what], until he had finished all the temple;","answer":"The whole temple he [overlaid with gold],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 22, The whole temple he overlaid with gold, until he had [done what];","answer":"until he had [finished all the temple];"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:22, He did what with the entire altar that was by the inner sanctuary?","answer":"also he overlaid with gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:22, What was by the inner sanctuary that he overlaid with gold?","answer":"the entire altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:22, He overlaid with gold the entire altar that was where?","answer":"that was by the inner sanctuary."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:23, Where were the 2 cherubim made?","answer":"Inside the inner sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:23, Inside the inner sanctuary he made how many cherubim?","answer":"he made two"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:23, Inside the inner sanctuary he made two what of olive wood?","answer":"cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:23, What were the two cherubim made of?","answer":"of olive wood,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:23, How high were each of the cherubim?","answer":"each ten cubits high."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:24, what was 5 cubits long?","answer":"One wing of the cherub"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:24, One wing of the chrub was how long?","answer":"was five cubits,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:24, How long was the other wing of the cherub?","answer":"and the other wing of the cherub five cubits:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:24, How many cubits was it from the tip of 1 wing to the tip of the other?","answer":"ten cubits from the tip of one wing to the tip of the other."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:25, The other cherub was how tall?","answer":"And the other cherub was ten cubits;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:25, What were both of the same size and shape?","answer":"both cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:25, 2 pts.  Both cherubim were of the same what?","answer":"were of the same size and shape."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:26, The height of 1 cherub was what?","answer":"The height of one cherub was ten cubits,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:26, The height of one cherub was 10 cubits.  What was the height of the OTHER cherub?","answer":"and so was the other cherub."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 27, Then he set [what] inside the inner room; and they stretched out the wings of the cherubim so that the wing of the one touched one wall, and the wing of the other cherub touched the other wall.","answer":"Then he set [the cherubim]"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:27, Where did Solomon set the cherubim?","answer":"inside the inner room;"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 27, they [did what] so that the wing of the one touched one wall, and the wing of the other cherub touched the other wall.","answer":"and they [stretched out the wings of the cherubim]"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 27, they stretched out the wings of the cherubim so that the wing of the one [did what], and the wing of the other cherub touched the other wall.","answer":"so that the wing of the one [touched one wall],"},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 27, they stretched out the wings of the cherubim so that the wing of the one touched one wall, and the wing of the other cherub [did what].","answer":"and the wing of the other cherub [touched the other wall]."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:27, What did the wings of the cherub","answer":"And their wings touched each other"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:27,","answer":"in the middle of the room."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:28, He overlaid what with gold?","answer":"Also he overlaid the cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:28, He overlaid the cherubim with what?","answer":"with gold."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:29, Solomon did what to all the walls of the temple all around?","answer":"Then he carved"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:29, Then Solomon carved what all around?","answer":"all the walls of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:29, Where did the carved figures of cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers go?","answer":"all the walls of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:29, 3 pts.  Then he carved all the walls of the temple where?","answer":"all around, both the inner and outer sanctuaries,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:29, 3 pts.  What did he carve on the walls of the temple all around?","answer":"with carved figures of cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers."},{"question":"According to 1Kings chapter 6 verse 30, And the _____ ______ _____ _____ he overlaid with gold, both the inner and outer sanctuaries.","answer":"And the [floor of the temple]"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:30, With what did Solomon use as the floor surface in the temple?","answer":"he overlaid with gold,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:30, 2 pts.  What floors of the temple did he overlay with gold?","answer":"both the inner and outer sanctuaries."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:31, Solomon made doors of olive wood for where?","answer":"For the entrance"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:31, Solomon made doors of olive wood for the entrance of what?","answer":"of the inner sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:31, For the entrance of the inner sanctuary he made what?","answer":"he made doors of olive wood;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:31, 2 pts.  What was 1\/5 of the wall?","answer":"the lintel and doorposts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:31, What size were the lintel and doorposts?","answer":"were one-fifth of the wall."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, How many doors were of olive wood?","answer":"The two doors"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, The two doors were of what?","answer":"were of olive wood;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, The two doors were of olive wood; and he did what on them?","answer":"and he carved on them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, What did Solomon carve on the two olive wood doors of the entrance to the inner sanctuary?","answer":"figures of cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, He carved on them figures of cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers, and then did what?","answer":"and overlaid them with gold;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, What did he spread on the cherubim and the palm trees?","answer":"and he spread gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:32, Solomon spread gold on what 2 things?","answer":"on the cherubim and on the palm trees."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:33, So for what he also made doorposts of olive wood?","answer":"So for the door of the sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:33, For the door of the sanctuary he also made what of olive wood?","answer":"he also made doorposts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:33, For the door of the sanctuary he also made doorposts of what?","answer":"of olive wood,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:33, For the door of the sanctuary he also made doorposts of olive wood, how tall?","answer":"one-fourth of the wall."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:34, And the 2 doors were of what; 2 panels comprised one folding door?","answer":"And the two doors were of cypress wood;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:34, How many panels comprised one folding door?","answer":"two panels comprised one folding door,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:34, How many panels comprised the other folding door?","answer":"and two panels comprised the other folding door."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:35, 3 pts.  Then he carved what on them, and overlaid them with gold?","answer":"Then he carved cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers on them,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:35, Then he carved cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers on them, and did what next?","answer":"and overlaid them with gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:35, describe the thickness of the gold on the carved work.","answer":"applied evenly on the carved work."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:36, What did Solomon build with 3 rows of hewn stone and a row of cedar beams?","answer":"And he built the inner court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:36, He built the inner court with how many rows of hewn stone?","answer":"with three rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:36, He built the inner court with 3 rows of what?","answer":"of hewn stone"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:36, He built the inner court with 3 rows of hewn stone and a row of what?","answer":"and a row of cedar beams."},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 6:37, In what year was the foundation of the house of the Lord was laid?","answer":"In the fourth year"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 6:37, In the 4th year what was laid, in the month of Ziv?","answer":"the foundation of the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 6:37, What happened to the foundation of the house of the Lord in the month of Ziv in the 4th year?","answer":"was laid,"},{"question":"According to 1 KIngs 6:37, In the 4th year the foundation of the house of the Lord was laid, in what month?","answer":"in the month of Ziv."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, In what year was the construction of the house of the Lord finished?","answer":"And in the eleventh year,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, What was the name of the month in which the construction of the house of the Lord was finished.","answer":"in the month of Bul,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, What month of the year is the month of Bul?","answer":"which is the eighth month,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, What happened in the eleventh year in the eighth month of Solomon's reign?","answer":"the house was finished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, What portion of the house of the Lord was finished by Solomon's eleventh as king in the eighth month of the year?","answer":"in all its details and according to all its plans."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, How many years was Solomon building the house of the Lord?","answer":"So he was seven years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 6:38, What did Solomon do for seven years concerning the house of the Lord?","answer":"in building it."}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
       
    ],
    "c7":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:1 Solomon took how many years to build his own house?","answer":"13 years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:1 Solomon took 13 years to do what?","answer":"to build his own house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:1 So he (Solomon) finished what?","answer":"all his own house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 He also built what; its length was 100 cubits?","answer":"the House of the Forest of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 How long was the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"100 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 How wide was the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"50 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 What was the height of the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"30 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 How many rows of cedar pillars were in the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"4 rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 There were 4 rows of what, and cedar beams on the pillars?","answer":"of cedar pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 There were 4 rows of cedar pillars, and what on the pillars?","answer":"cedar beams"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:2 Where were the cedar beams in the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"on the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 It was what with cedar above the beams that were on 45 pillars?","answer":"it was paneled"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 It was paneled with what above the beams that were on 45 pillars?","answer":"with cedar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 It was paneled with cedar where?","answer":"above the beams"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 How many pillars were there, fifteen to a row?","answer":"45 pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 There were 45 pillars in the House of the Forest of Lebanon, how many per row?","answer":"fifteen to a row"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:3 What building had 45 pillars, 15 to a row?","answer":"the House of the Forest of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 There were what with beveled frames in 3 rows?","answer":"windows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 There were windows with what in 3 rows?","answer":"with beveled frames"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 There were windows with beveled frames in how many rows?","answer":"3 rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 There were windows with beveled frames in 3 rows, and window was opposite what in 3 tiers?","answer":"window was opposite window"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 \u2026 window was opposite window arranged how?","answer":"in 3 tiers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:4 What was arranged in 3 tiers?","answer":"windows with beveled frames in 3 rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:5 All the _____ and _____ had rectangular frames?","answer":"doorways, doorposts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:5 All the doorways and doorposts had what?","answer":"had rectangular frames"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:5 All the doorways and doorposts had rectangular frames, and what was opposite window in 3 tiers?","answer":"window"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:5 All the doorways and doorposts had rectangular frames, and window was opposite what in 3 tiers?","answer":"window"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:5 All the doorways and doorposts had rectangular frames, and window was opposite window how?","answer":" in 3 tiers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 He also made a what: its length was 50 cubits?","answer":"a Hall of Pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 He also made a Hall of Pillars: its length was what?","answer":"50 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 What was the width of Hall of Pillars?","answer":"30 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 What was in front of the Hall of Pillars?","answer":"a portico with pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 What was in front of the portico with pillars?","answer":"a canopy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:6 What building had a length of 50 cubits and a width of 30?","answer":"the Hall of Pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 Then he made a what for the throne, the Hall of Judgment?","answer":"a hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 Then he made a hall for what, the Hall of Judgment?","answer":"for the throne"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 What was the name of the hall he made for the throne?","answer":"the Hall of Judgment"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 Then he made a hall for the throne, .. where he might do what?","answer":"might judge"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 Then he made a hall for the throne, \u2026 and it was what from floor to ceiling?","answer":"paneled with cedar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 Then he made a hall for the throne, \u2026 and it was paneled where?","answer":"from floor to ceiling"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:7 What was the name of the hall he made where he might judge?","answer":"the Hall of Judgment"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 And the house where he dwelt had what inside the hall?","answer":"another court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 What had another court inside the hall, of like workmanship?","answer":"the house where he dwelt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 The house where he dwelt had another court where?","answer":"inside the hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 The house where he dwelt had another court inside the hall, of what?","answer":"of like workmanship"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 What was of like workmanship?","answer":"the house where he dwelt OR another court inside the hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 Solomon also made a what like this hall for Pharaoh's daughter?","answer":"a house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 Solomon also made a house like what for Pharoah's daughter?","answer":"like this hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 Solomon also made a house like this hall for whom?","answer":"for Pharaoh's daughter"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 What did Solomon make for Pharaoh's daughter?","answer":"a house like this hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 Solomon also made a house like this hall for Pharaoh's daughter, whom he had what?","answer":"had taken as wife"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:8 Whom had Solomon taken as wife?","answer":"Pharaoh's daughter"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 All these were of what, trimmed with saws, inside and out?","answer":"of costly stones cut to size"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 All these were of costly stones cut to size, then what, inside and out?","answer":"trimmed with saws"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 2 pts. All these were of costly stones cut to size, trimmed with saws where?","answer":"inside and out"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 All these were of costly stones cut to size, \u2026 inside and out, from where to where, and also on the outside to the great court?","answer":"from the foundation to the eaves"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 All these were of costly stones cut to size, \u2026 inside and out, from the foundation to the eaves, and also where?","answer":"on the outside to the great court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:9 What were the houses for Solomon and for Pharaoh's daughter made of?","answer":"costly stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:10 The what was of costly stones, large stones, some 10 cubits and some 8 cubits?","answer":"the foundation"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:10 The foundation was of what, large stones, some 10 cubits and some 8 cubits?","answer":"of costly stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:10 The foundation was of costly stones, large stones, some _____ cubits and some _____ cubits.","answer":"10 cubits, 8 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:10 The foundation was of costly stones, what size, some 10 cubits and some 8 cubits?","answer":"large stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:10 What was 10 cubits and 8 cubits?","answer":"the foundation stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:11 And above were what, hewn to size, and cedar wood?","answer":"costly stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:11 Where were costly stones, hewn to size, and cedar wood?","answer":"above"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:11 And above were costly stones -- what was done to them?","answer":"hewn to size"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:11 Above were costly stones, hewn to size, and what else?","answer":"cedar wood"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 What was enclosed with 3 rows of hewn stones and a row of cedar beams? (a method of building to withstand earthquakes)","answer":"the great court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 The great court was enclosed with what and a row of cedar beams?","answer":"3 rows of hewn stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 The great court was enclosed with 3 rows of hewn stones and a what?","answer":"a row of cedar beams"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 So were the what of the house of the Lord and the vestibule of the temple?","answer":"the inner court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 So were the inner court of the what and the vestibule of the temple?","answer":"the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 So were the inner court of the house of the Lord and the what?","answer":"the vestibule of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:12 How was the inner court of the house of the Lord and vestibule of the temple built?","answer":"3 rows of hewn stones and a row of cedar beams (see Ezra 6 where Cyrus tells them to rebuild it this exact way)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:13 Now King Solomon sent and brought whom from Tyre?","answer":"Huram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:13 Now King Solomon sent and brought Huram from where?","answer":"from Tyre"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 He (Huram) was what from the tribe of Naphtali?","answer":"the son of the widow"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 He (Huram) was the son of a widow from which tribe?","answer":"the tribe of Naphtali"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 Who was the father of Huram?","answer":"a man of Tyre"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 What job did Huram's father have?","answer":"a bronze worker"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 \u2026 he (Huram) was filled with what 3 things in working with all kinds of bronze work?","answer":"with wisdom and understanding and skill"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 \u2026 he (Huram) was filled with wisdom and understanding and skill in doing what?","answer":"in working with bronze work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 So he came to King Solomon and did what?","answer":"all his work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:14 Who came to King Solomon and did all his work?","answer":"he (did) -- Huram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 He did what of bronze, each one 18 cubits high?","answer":"cast 2 pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 He cast 2 pillars of what, each one 18 cubits high?","answer":"of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 He cast 2 pillars of bronze, each one how high?","answer":"18 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 He cast 2 pillars of bronze, \u2026 and a line how long measured the circumference of each?","answer":"12 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 He cast 2 pillars of bronze, \u2026 and a line of 12 cubits measured the what of each?","answer":"the circumference"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:15 What had a circumference of 12 cubits?","answer":"the 2 bronze pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 Then he made how many capitals of cast bronze, to set on the tops of the pillars?","answer":"2 capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 Then he made 2 what of cast bronze, to set on the tops of the pillars?","answer":"capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 Then he made 2 capitals of what, to set on the tops of the pillars?","answer":"of cast bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 Then he made 2 capitals of cast bronze, to set where?","answer":"on the tops of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 The height of 1 capital was what, and the height of the other capital was what?","answer":"5 cubits, 5 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:16 What was 5 cubits in height?","answer":"the capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 He made a what, with wreaths of chainwork, for the capitals?","answer":"a lattice network"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 He made a lattice network, with what, for the capitals?","answer":"with wreaths of chainwork"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 He made a lattice network, with wreaths of chainwork, for the what which were on top of the pillars?","answer":"the capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 He made a lattice network, with wreaths of chainwork, for the capitals which were where?","answer":"on top of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 How many chains were in 1 capital?","answer":"7 chains"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:17 How many chains were there all together?","answer":"14 chains"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:18 He made the what, and 2 rows of pomegranates above the network all around to cover the capitals that were on top?","answer":"the capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:18 He made the pillars, and what above the network all around to cover the capitals?","answer":"2 rows of pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:18 He made the pillars, and 2 rows of pomegranates where all around to cover the capitals?","answer":"above the network"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:18 He made the pillars, and 2 rows of pomegranates above the network all around to do what on top?","answer":"to cover the capitals that were on top"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:18 What was to cover the capitals that were on top?","answer":"2 rows of pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:19 The capitals which were on top of the pillars where were in the shape of lilies, 4 cubits?","answer":"in the hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:19 The capitals which were on top of the pillars in the hall were in the shape of what?","answer":"of lilies"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:19 The capitals which were on top of the pillars in the hall were in the shape of lilies, what size?","answer":"4 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:19 What had a size of 4 cubits?","answer":"the lilies"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 The what on the 2 pillars also had pomegranates above?","answer":"the capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 The capitals on what also had pomegranates above?","answer":"on the 2 pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 The capitals on the 2 pillars also had what above?","answer":"pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 Where were the pomegranates, by the convex surface which was next to the network?","answer":"above"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 The capitals on the 2 pillars also had pomegranates above, by the what which was next to the network?","answer":"by the convex surface"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 The capitals on the 2 pillars also had pomegranates above, by the convex surface which was next to what?","answer":"to the network"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 How many pomegranates were there in rows on each of the capitals all around?","answer":200},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 There were 200 what in rows on each of the capitals all around?","answer":"such pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 There were 200 such pomegranates arranged how on each of the capitals all around?","answer":"in rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 There were 200 such pomegranates arranged in rows on what all around?","answer":" on each of the capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:20 There were 200 such pomegranates arranged in rows on each of the capitals how?","answer":"all around"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 Then he set up the what by the vestibule of the temple?","answer":"the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 Then he set up the pillars by what?","answer":"by the vestibule of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 He set up the pillar where and called its name Jachin?","answer":"on the right"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 What was the name of the pillar set up on the right?","answer":"Jachin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 He set up the pillar where and called its name Boaz?","answer":"on the left"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:21 What was the name of the pillar set up on the left?","answer":"Boaz"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:22 The tops of the pillars were in the shape of what?","answer":"of lilies"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:22 What was in the shape of lilies?","answer":"the tops of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:22 So the work of what was finished?","answer":"of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:22 So the work of the pillars was what?","answer":"was finished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 And he made the what, 10 cubits from 1 brim to the other?","answer":"the Sea of cast bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 And he made the Sea of cast bronze, how big from 1 brim to the other?","answer":"10 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 And he made the Sea of cast bronze, 10 cubits from where to where?","answer":"from 1 brim to the other"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 He made the Sea of cast bronze, 10 cubits from 1 brim to the other; it was what?","answer":"was completely round"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 What was the height of the Sea of cast bronze?","answer":"5 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 He made the Sea of cast bronze \u2026 a line of 30 cubits measured what?","answer":"its circumference"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:23 What was the circumference of the Sea of cast bronze?","answer":"30 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 Below its brim were what encircling it all around, 10 to a cubit?","answer":"ornamental buds"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 Where were the ornamental buds encircling it all around, 10 to a cubit?","answer":"below its brim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 Below its brim were ornamental buds encircling it all around, how many to a cubit?","answer":"10 to a cubit"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 \u2026 ornamental bud encircling it around, 10 to a cubit, where around the Sea?","answer":"all the way around"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 The ornamental buds were cast how when it was cast?","answer":"in 2 rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 What was cast in 2 rows when it was cast?","answer":"the ornamental buds"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:24 The ornamental buds were cast in 2 rows when it was what?","answer":"when it was cast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:25 It stood on what, 3 looking toward the north, 3 looking toward the west, 3 looking toward the south, and 3 looking toward the east?","answer":"on 12 oxen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:25 It stood on 12 oxen, 3 looking toward the _____, 3 looking toward the _____, 3 looking toward the _____, and 3 looking toward the _____.","answer":"north, west, south, east"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:25 The sea was set upon them, and all their what pointed inward?","answer":"their back parts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:25 The sea was set upon them, and all their back parts did what?","answer":"pointed inward"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:26 It was how thick; and its brim was shaped like the brim of a cup, like a lily blossom?","answer":"a handbreadth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:26 It was a handbreadth thick; and its what was shaped like the brim of a cup?","answer":"its brim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:26 2 pts. It was a handbreadth thick; and its brim was shaped like what?","answer":"like the brim of a cup, like a lily blossom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:26 It contained how many baths?","answer":"2,000 baths"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:26 What contained 2,000 baths?","answer":"the Sea of cast bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 He also made how many carts of bronze?","answer":"10 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 He also made 10 carts of what?","answer":"of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 What was the length of each cart?","answer":"4 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 What was the width of each cart?","answer":"4 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 What was the height of each cart?","answer":"3-1\/2 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:27 What measured 4 x 4 x 3-1\/2 cubits?","answer":"the carts of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:28 This was the what of the carts: they had panels, and the panels were between frames?","answer":"the design"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:28 This was the design of the what: they had panels, and the panels were between frames?","answer":"of the carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:28 This was the design of the carts: they had what, and the panels were between frames?","answer":"panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:28 They had panels, and the panels were between what?","answer":"between frames"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:28 What was between frames?","answer":"the panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 On the what that were between the frames were lions, oxen, and cherubim?","answer":"on the panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 On the panels that were between what were lions, oxen, and cherubim?","answer":"between the frames"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 3 pts. On the panels that were between the frames were what?","answer":"lions, oxen, and cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 What had lions, oxen, and cherubim on it?","answer":"the carts of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 On the frames was a what on top?","answer":"a pedestal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 On the what was a pedestal on top?","answer":"on the frames"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 2 pts. Below the what were wreaths of plaited work?","answer":"lions and oxen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 Below the lions and oxen were what?","answer":"wreaths of plaited work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:29 Where were the wreaths of plaited work?","answer":"below the lions and oxen (on the carts)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Every cart had 4 what and axles of bronze?","answer":"bronze wheels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Every cart had 4 bronze wheels and what?","answer":"and axles of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Every cart had 4 bronze wheels \u2026 and its what had supports?","answer":"its 4 feet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Every cart had 4 bronze wheels \u2026 and its feet had what?","answer":"had supports"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Under the what were supports of cast bronze beside each wreath?","answer":"under the laver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Under the laver were what beside each wreath?","answer":"supports of cast bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:30 Under the laver were supports of cast bronze where?","answer":"beside each wreath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 Its opening inside the crown at the top was how big in diameter?","answer":"1 cubit"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 Where was it 1 cubit in diameter?","answer":"inside the crown at the top"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 What was 1 cubit in diameter inside the crown at the top?","answer":"its opening"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 Its opening inside the crown where was 1 cubit in diameter?","answer":"at the top"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 The opening was what shape, shaped like a pedestal?","answer":"was round"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 The opening was round, shaped like a what?","answer":"like a pedestal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 What was shaped like a pedestal?","answer":"the opening"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 What was the outside diameter of the round opening?","answer":"1-1\/2 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 What was 1-1\/2 cubits in diameter?","answer":"the outside of the round opening"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 Also on the opening were what, but the panels were square, not round?","answer":"were engravings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 Where were there engravings?","answer":"on the opening"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 On the opening were engravings, but the panels were _____, not _____.","answer":"square, round"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:31 What was square, not round?","answer":"the panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 Under the what were the 4 wheels?","answer":"the panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 Under the panels were the what, and the axles of the wheels were joined to the cart?","answer":"the 4 wheels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 Under the panels were the 4 wheels, and the what were joined to the cart?","answer":"the axles of the wheels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 Under the panels were the 4 wheels, and the axles of the wheels were what?","answer":"were joined to the cart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 What was the height of a wheel?","answer":"1-1\/2 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:32 What in this verse was 1-1\/2 cubits in height?","answer":"a wheel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:33 The what of the wheels was like the workmanship of a chariot wheel?","answer":"the workmanship"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:33 The workmanship of the what was like the workmanship of a chariot wheel?","answer":"of the wheels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:33 The workmanship of the wheels was like the workmanship of what?","answer":"of a chariot wheel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:33 \u2026 their axle pins, their rims, their spokes, and their hubs were all of what?","answer":"of cast bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:33 Name the 4 parts of the wheels that were of cast bronze.","answer":"their axle pins, their rims, their spokes, their hubs"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 There were 4 what at the 4 corners of each cart?","answer":"4 supports"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 There were 4 supports where on each cart?","answer":"at the 4 corners"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 How many supports were there on each cart?","answer":4},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 There were 4 supports at the 4 corners of what?","answer":"of each cart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 There were 4 supports at the 4 corners of each cart; its supports were part of what?","answer":"of the cart itself"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:34 What was part of the cart itself?","answer":"the 4 supports"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:35 On the top of the cart, at what height, it was perfectly round?","answer":"half a cubit"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:35 2 pts.  Where on the cart was it perfectly round?  ","answer":"on the top, at the height of half a cubit"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:35 On the top of the cart, at the height of half a cubit, it was what?","answer":"was perfectly round"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:35 2 pts. On top of the cart, its what were of the same casting?","answer":"its flanges and its panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:35 On top of the cart, its flanges and its panels were of what?","answer":"of the same casting"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 On what and on its panels he engraved cherubim, lions, and palm trees?","answer":"on the plates of its flanges"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 On the plates of its flanges and on what he engraved cherubim, lions, and palm trees?","answer":"on its panels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 3 pts. On the plates of its flanges and on its panels he engraved what?","answer":"cherubim, lions, and palm trees"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 What did he do on the plates of its flanges and on its panels?","answer":"he engraved (cherubim, lions, and palm trees)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 On the plates of its flanges and on its panels he engraved \u2026 wherever there was what, with wreaths all around?","answer":" a clear space on each"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 On the plates of its flanges and on its panels he engraved \u2026 wherever there was a clear space on each, with what all around?","answer":"with wreaths"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:36 On the plates of its flanges and on its panels he engraved \u2026 wherever there was a clear space on each, with wreaths where?","answer":" all around"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:37 Thus he made the what? All of them were of the same mold \u2026","answer":"the 10 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:37 All of them were of the what, 1 measure, and 1 shape?","answer":"the same mold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:37 All of them were of the same mold, 1 what, and 1 shape?","answer":"1 measure"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:37 All of them were of the same mold, 1 measure, and 1 what?","answer":"1 shape"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:37 What was all of the same mold, 1 measure, and 1 shape?","answer":"the 10 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 Then he made 10 what?","answer":"lavers of bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 He made how many lavers of bronze?","answer":10},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 Each laver contained how many baths?","answer":"40 baths"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 Each what contained 40 baths?","answer":"laver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 Each laver was what size?","answer":"4 cubits"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 What in this verse was 4 cubits?","answer":"each laver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:38 On each of the 10 carts was a what?","answer":"a laver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 He put how many carts on the right side of the house?","answer":"5 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 He put 5 what on the right side of the house?","answer":"5 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 2 pts. He put 5 carts where?","answer":"5 on the right side of the house, and 5 on the left side of the house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 How many carts did he put on the left side of the house?","answer":"5 carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 He set the Sea where, toward the southeast?","answer":"on the right side of the house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 He set what on the right side of the house, toward the southeast?","answer":"the Sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:39 He set the Sea on the right side of the house, toward what?","answer":"toward the southeast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 Huram made what 3 things?","answer":"lavers, shovels, and bowls (compare to vs. 45, lavers vs. pots)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 Who made the lavers and the shovels and the bowls?","answer":"Huram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 So Huram finished doing what that he was to do for King Solomon for the house of the Lord?","answer":"all the work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 So who finished doing all the work that he was to do for King Solomon for the house of the Lord?","answer":"Huram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 So Huram finished doing all the work that he was to do for whom for the house of the Lord?","answer":"for King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:40 So Huram finished doing all the work that he was to do for King Solomon for what?","answer":"for the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 (So Huram finished \u2026) the 2 _____, the 2 bowl-shaped _____ that were on top of the 2 pillars, the 2 _____ covering the 2 bowl-shaped capitals which were on top of the pillars;","answer":"pillars, capitals, networks"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many pillars?","answer":2},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many bowl-shaped capitals that were on top of the pillars?","answer":2},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many networks covering the 2 bowl-shaped capitals which were on top of the pillars?","answer":2},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 What did the 2 capitals that were on top of the 2 pillars look like?","answer":"bowl-shaped"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 What was covering the 2 bowl-shaped capitals which were on top of the pillars?","answer":"networks"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 The 2 networks were covering what?","answer":"the 2 bowl-shaped capitals which were on top of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:41 Where were the capitals located?","answer":"on top of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many pomegranates?","answer":400},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 (So Huram finished \u2026) 400 what?","answer":"pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 (So Huram finished \u2026) 400 pomegranates for the what?","answer":"for the 2 networks"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 How many rows of pomegranates were for each network?","answer":"2 rows"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 There were 2 rows of what for each network?","answer":"of pomegranates"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 (So Huram finished \u2026) 400 pomegranates for the 2 networks (2 rows of pomegranates for each network, to cover the what?","answer":"the 2 bowl-shaped capitals that were on top of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 What was on top of the pillars?","answer":"the 2 bowl-shaped capitals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:42 The 2 bowl-shaped capitals were located where?","answer":"on top of the pillars"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:43 (So Huram finished \u2026) the 10 _____, and 10 _____ on the _____?","answer":"carts, lavers, carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:43 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many carts?","answer":10},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:43 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many lavers on the carts?","answer":10},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:43 Where were the lavers placed?","answer":"on the carts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:44 (So Huram finished \u2026) 1 _____, and 12 _____ under the _____.","answer":"Sea, oxen, Sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:44 (So Huram finished \u2026) how many oxen under the Sea?","answer":12},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:44 T or F:  There were two Seas -- one on the right side and one on the left.","answer":"F -- one Sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:44 Where were the oxen located?","answer":"under the Sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:44 What was under the Sea?","answer":"the 12 oxen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 (So Huram finished \u2026) the _____, the _____, and the _____?","answer":"pots, shovels, and the bowls (compare to vs. 40, pots vs. lavers)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 All these what which Huram made for King Solomon for the house of the Lord were of burnished bronze?","answer":"all these articles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 All these articles which who made for King Solomon for the house of the Lord were of burnished bronze?","answer":"Huram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 All these articles which Huram made for whom for the house of the Lord were of burnished bronze?","answer":"for King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 All these articles which Huram made for King Solomon for what were of burnished bronze?","answer":"for the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 All these articles which Huram made for King Solomon for the house of the Lord were of what?","answer":"of burnished bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:45 What was of burnished bronze?","answer":"all these articles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:46 Where did the king have them cast in clay molds, between Succoth and Zaretan?","answer":"in the plain of Jordan"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:46 In the plain of Jordan the king had them do what, between Succoth and Zaretan?","answer":"cast in clay molds"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:46 In the plain of Jordan the king had them cast in clay molds, between where and where?","answer":"Succoth and Zaretan"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:46 What did the king have them do between Succoth and Zaretan?","answer":"cast in clay molds"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:47 And Solomon did not do what, because there were so many?","answer":"did not weigh all the articles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:47 And Solomon did not weigh all the articles -- why?","answer":"because there were so many"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:47 The weight of what was not determined?","answer":"of the bronze"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:47 The weight of the bronze was not what?","answer":"was not determined"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 Thus Solomon had all the what made for the house of the Lord?","answer":"all the furnishings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made for what?","answer":"for the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made for the house of the Lord: the what, and the table of gold on which was the showbread?","answer":"the altar of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made for the house of the Lord: the altar of gold, and the what on which was the showbread?","answer":"table of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made for the house of the Lord: the altar of gold, and the table of gold on which was what?","answer":"was the showbread"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:48 What was on the table of gold?","answer":"showbread"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 (Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made \u2026); the what, 5 on the right side and 5 on the left in front of the inner sanctuary?","answer":"the lampstands of pure gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 (Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made \u2026); the lampstands of pure gold, 5 on the right side and 5 on the left where?","answer":"in front of the inner sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 How many lampstands did Solomon have made?","answer":"10 total"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 How were the lampstands placed in front of the inner sanctuary?","answer":"5 on the right side and 5 on the left"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 3 pts. The lampstands in front of the inner sanctuary had what else of gold?","answer":"the flowers and the lamps and the wick-trimmers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:49 The flowers and the lamps and the wick-trimmers were of what?","answer":"of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 (Thus Solomon had all the furnishings made \u2026); name the 6 items listed in this verse.","answer":"basins, trimmers, bowls, ladles, censers of pure gold, hinges of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 The hinges of gold were for which doors?","answer":"both for the doors of the inner room and for the doors of the main hall"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 What is the other name for the inner room?","answer":"the Most Holy Place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 What is the other name for the Most Holy Place?","answer":"the inner room"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 The censers were made of what?","answer":"of pure gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 What were the hinges for the doors made of?","answer":"of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:50 The hinges of gold were for both the doors of the inner room and for the doors of where?","answer":"of the main hall of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 So all the work that who had done for the house of the Lord was finished?","answer":"King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 So all the what that King Solomon had done for the house of the Lord was finished?","answer":"all the work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 So all the work that King Solomon had done for what was finished?","answer":"for the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 So all the work that king Solomon had done for the house of the Lord was what?","answer":"was finished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 And Solomon brought in the what which his father David had dedicated?","answer":"the things"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 Solomon brought in the things which who had dedicated?","answer":"his father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 Solomon brought in the things which his father David had what?","answer":"had dedicated"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 3 pts.  What had his father David dedicated?","answer":"the silver and the gold and the furnishings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 Where did Solomon put the things his father David had dedicated?","answer":"in the treasuries of the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 7:51 What was put in the treasuries of the house of the Lord?","answer":"the things which his father David had dedicated OR the silver and gold and the furnishings"}
        
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */        
    ],
    "c8":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Now who assembled the elders of Israel and all the heads of the tribes?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Now Solomon did what with the elders of Israel and all the heads of the tribes?","answer":"assembled (them)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 2 pts. Solomon assembled whom, the chief fathers of the children of Israel?","answer":"the elders of Israel and all the heads of the tribes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Solomon assembled the elders of Israel and all the heads of the tribes, the what of the children of Israel?","answer":"the chief fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Solomon assembled the elders of Israel and all the heads of the tribes, the chief fathers of whom?","answer":"of the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Where did Solomon assemble the elders and all the heads of the tribes, the chief fathers?","answer":"to King Solomon in Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Why did Solomon assemble the elders and all the heads of the tribes, the chief fathers?","answer":"that they might bring up the ark of the covenant of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 Where were they bringing up the ark of the covenant of the Lord from?","answer":"from the City of David, OR, Zion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 What's another name for the City of David?","answer":"Zion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 What is another name for Zion?","answer":"the City of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:1 What were they planning to bring up from Zion?","answer":"the ark of the covenant of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 Therefore who assembled with King Solomon at the feast in the month of Ethanim?","answer":"all the men of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 All the men of Israel assembled with whom at the feast in the month of Ethanim?","answer":"with King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 All the men of Israel assembled with King Solomon at what in the month of Ethanim?","answer":"at the feast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 All the men of Israel assembled with King Solomon at the feast in what month?","answer":"the month of Ethanim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 Which month is the month of Ethanim?","answer":"the 7th month"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:2 What is the name of the 7th month?","answer":"Ethanim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:3 So who came, and the priests took up the ark?","answer":"the elders of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:3 So the elders came, and who took up the ark?","answer":"the priests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:3 So the elders came, and the priests did what?","answer":"took up the ark"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 Then they brought up what, the tabernacle of meeting, and all the holy furnishings that were in the tabernacle?","answer":"the ark of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 Then they brought up the ark of the Lord, the what, and all the holy furnishings that were in the tabernacle?","answer":"the tabernacle of meeting"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 Then they brought up the ark of the Lord, the tabernacle of meeting, and all the what that were in the tabernacle?","answer":"the holy furnishings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 Then they brought up the ark of the Lord, the tabernacle of meeting, and all the holy furnishings that were where?","answer":"in the tabernacle"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 2 pts.  Who brought up the ark, the tabernacle, and all the holy furnishings?","answer":"the priests and the Levites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:4 The priests and the Levites did what?","answer":"brought them up"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 Also who, and all the congregation of Israel who were assembled with him, were with him before the ark?","answer":"King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 Also King Solomon, and who else who were assembled with him, were with him before the ark?","answer":"all the congregation of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 King Solomon, and all the congregation of Israel who were what, were with him before the ark?","answer":"were assembled with him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 King Solomon, and all the congregation of Israel who were assembled with him, were with him where?","answer":"before the ark"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 2 pts.  Who was assembled before the ark?","answer":"King Solomon and all the congregation of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 What was King Solomon and all the congregation doing before the ark?","answer":"sacrificing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 2 pts.  What was King Solomon and all the congregation sacrificing before the ark?","answer":"sheep and oxen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 King  Solomon and all the congregation \u2026 were sacrificing sheep and oxen that could not be _____ or _____ for multitude.","answer":"counted, numbered"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 King Solomon and all the congregation \u2026 were sacrificing sheep and oxen that could not be counted or numbered for what?","answer":"for multitude"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:5 What could not be counted or numbered for multitude?","answer":"the sacrifices OR the sheep and oxen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 Then who brought in the ark of the covenant of the Lord to its place, into the inner sanctuary of the temple, to the Most Holy Place?","answer":"the priests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 Then the priests brought in the what to its place? Be specific.","answer":"the ark of the covenant of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 Then the priests brought in the ark of the covenant of the Lord to where, into the inner sanctuary of the temple?","answer":"to its place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 Then the priests brought in the ark of the covenant of the Lord to its place, into what, to the Most Holy Place?","answer":"the inner sanctuary of the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 What was the inner sanctuary of the temple called?","answer":"the Most Holy Place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 Then the priests brought in the ark of the covenant of the Lord to its place, \u2026 under what?","answer":"under the wings of the cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:6 What was brought to its place under the wings of the cherubim?","answer":"the ark of the covenant of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 For the what spread their two wings over the place of the ark?","answer":"the cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 For the cherubim did what over the place of the ark?","answer":"spread their 2 wings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 For the cherubim spread their two wings over what?","answer":"over the place of the ark"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 2 pts. The cherubim overshadowed what?","answer":"the ark and its pole"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 What overshadowed the ark and its poles?","answer":"the cherubim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:7 The cherubim spread their two wings over the place of the ark, and the cherubim did what to the ark and its poles?","answer":"overshadowed (it)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 The poles did what so that the ends of the poles could be seen from the holy place?","answer":"extended"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 What extended so that the ends of the poles could be seen from the holy place?","answer":"the poles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 The poles extended so that the ends of the poles could be seen from the holy place, in front of where?","answer":"in front of the inner sanctuary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 The poles extended so that the ends of the poles could be what?","answer":"could be seen from the holy place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 What could be seen from the holy place?","answer":"the ends of the poles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 Where could the poles NOT be seen?","answer":"from outside"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 What could not be seen from outside?","answer":"the ends of the poles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 What is there to this day?","answer":"the poles"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 The poles are what to this day?","answer":"are there"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:8 The poles are there to when?","answer":"to this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 Nothing was in the ark except what which Moses put there at Horeb?","answer":"the two tablets of stone"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 Who put the two tablets of stone in the ark?","answer":"Moses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 Where was Moses when he put the 2 tablets of stone in the ark?","answer":"at Horeb"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 What did the Lord do at Horeb when Moses put the 2 tablets of stone in the ark?","answer":"made a covenant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 With whom did the Lord make a covenant at Horeb?","answer":"with the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 \u2026 the Lord made a covenant with the children of Israel, when they did what?","answer":"when they came up out of the land of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:9 Where had the children of Israel been before they reached Horeb?","answer":"Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:10 And it came to pass, when the priests came out of where, that the cloud filled the house of the Lord?","answer":"out of the holy place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:10 And it came to pass, when who came out of the holy place, that the cloud filled the house of the Lord?","answer":"the priests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:10 And it came to pass, when the priests came out of the holy place, that the cloud did what?","answer":" filled the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:10 What filled the house of the Lord when the priests came out of the holy place?","answer":"the cloud"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:11 \u2026 so that the priests could not do what because of the cloud; for the glory of the Lord filled the house of the Lord?","answer":"could not continue ministering"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:11 \u2026 so that the priests could not continue ministering -- why?","answer":"because of the cloud OR for the glory of the Lord filled the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:11 \u2026 so that the priests could not continue ministering because of the cloud; for what filled the house of the Lord?","answer":"the glory of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:11 \u2026 so that the priests could not continue ministering because of the cloud; for the glory of the Lord filled what?","answer":"the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:12 Then who spoke?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:12 The Lord said He would dwell where?","answer":"in the dark cloud"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:12 Who said He would dwell in the dark cloud?","answer":"the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:12 The Lord said He would do what in the dark cloud?","answer":"He would dwell"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:13 I have surely done what, and a place for You to dwell in forever.","answer":"built You an exalted house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:13 I have surely built you an exalted house, and a place for You to do what forever?","answer":"to dwell in"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:13 I have surely built you an exalted house, and a place for You to dwell in for how long?","answer":"forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:14 Then the king did what 2 things, while all the assembly of Israel was standing?","answer":"turned around and blessed the whole assembly of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:14 Then the king turned around and blessed whom, while all the assembly of Israel was standing?","answer":"the whole assembly of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:14 Then the king turned around and blessed the whole assembly of Israel, while who was standing?","answer":"all the assembly of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:14 Then the king turned around and blessed the whole assembly of Israel, while all the assembly was doing what?","answer":"was standing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:14 Who turned around and blessed the whole assembly of Israel?","answer":"the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:15 Blessed be whom, who spoke with His mouth to my father David? Be specific.","answer":"the Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:15 Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, who did what to my father David?","answer":"spoke with His mouth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:15 Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, who spoke with His mouth to whom?","answer":"to my father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:15 Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, who spoke with His mouth \u2026, and with His what has fulfilled it?","answer":"with His hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:15 Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, who spoke with His mouth \u2026, and with His hand has done what?","answer":"has fulfilled it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 Since when, I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house?","answer":"since the day I brought My people Israel out of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 Since the day I brought whom out of Egypt, I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house?","answer":"My people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 Since the day I brought My people Israel out of where, I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house?","answer":"out of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 Since the day I brought My people Israel out of Egypt, I have chosen no what in which to build a house?","answer":"no city from any tribe of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 Since the day I brought My people Israel out of Egypt, I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to do what?","answer":"in which to build a house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 \u2026 I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house, that My what might be there?","answer":"My name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 \u2026 I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house, that My name might be there; but I chose whom to be over My people Israel?","answer":"David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:16 \u2026 I have chosen no city from any tribe of Israel in which to build a house, that My name might be there; but I chose David to be over what?","answer":"My people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:17 Now it was in what of my father David to build a temple for the name of the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"in the heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:17 Now it was in the heart of whom to build a temple for the name of the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"my father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:17 Now it was in the heart of my father David to do what for the name of the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"to build a temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:17 Now it was in the heart of my father David to build a temple for what? Be specific.","answer":"for the name of the Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:18 Whereas it was in your what to build a temple for My name, you did well that it was in your heart?","answer":"in your heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:18 Whereas it was in your heart to do what, you did well that it was in your heart?","answer":"to build a temple for My name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:18 Whereas it was in your heart to build a temple for My name, you did well that it was what?","answer":"it was in your heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:19 Nevertheless you shall not what, but your son who will come from your body, he shall build the temple for My name?","answer":"not build the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:19 Nevertheless you shall not build the temple, but your _____ who shall come from your _____, he shall build the temple for My name.","answer":"son, body"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:19 You shall not build the temple, but your son who shall come from your body, he shall do what for My name?","answer":"build the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:19 You shall not build the temple, but your son who shall come from your body, he shall do built the temple for what?","answer":"for My name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:19 Who did the Lord say would build the temple?","answer":"your (David's) son who will come from your body, aka Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 So the Lord has done what which He spoke?","answer":"fulfilled His word"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 So the Lord has fulfilled His word which He what?","answer":"which He spoke"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 I have filled the what of my father David, and sit on the throne of Israel, as the Lord promised?","answer":"position"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 I have filled the position of whom, and sit on the throne of Israel, as the Lord promised?","answer":"of my father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 I have filled the position of my father David, and do what, as the Lord promised?","answer":"sit on the throne of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 I have filled the position of my father David, and sit on the throne of Israel, as what?","answer":"as the Lord promised"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 ... I have built what for the name of the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"a temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:20 \u2026 I have built a temple for whom? Be specific.","answer":"for the name of the Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 There I have made a what for the ark, in which is the covenant of the Lord which He made with our fathers?","answer":"a place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 There I have made a place for the what, in which is the covenant of the Lord which He made with our fathers?","answer":"for the ark"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 There I have made a place for the ark, in which is what which the Lord made with our fathers?","answer":"the covenant of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 There I have made a place for the ark, in which is the covenant of the Lord which He made with whom?","answer":"with our fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 When did the Lord make a covenant with our fathers?","answer":"when He brought them out of the land of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:21 I have made a place for the ark, in which is the covenant of the Lord which He made with our fathers, when He brought them out of where?","answer":"out of the land of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:22 Then Solomon stood where in the presence of all the assembly of Israel, and spread out his hands toward heaven?","answer":"before the altar of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:22 Then Solomon stood before the altar of the Lord in the presence of whom, and spread out his hands toward heaven?","answer":"of all the assembly of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:22 Then Solomon stood before the altar of the Lord in the presence of all the assembly of Israel, and did what?","answer":"spread out his hands toward heaven"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:22 Who spread out his hands toward heaven?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:22 Who stood before the altar of the Lord in the presence of all the assembly of Israel?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:23 2 pts. There is no God where like You, who keep Your covenant?","answer":"in heaven above or on earth below"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:23 There is no God in heaven above or in earth below like You, who keep _____ and _____ with Your servants who walk before You?","answer":"Your covenant, mercy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:23 There is no God \u2026 like You who keep Your covenant and mercy with whom who walk before You?","answer":"Your servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:23 There is no God \u2026 like You who keep Your covenant and mercy with Your servants who do what with all their hearts?","answer":"walk before You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:23 There is no God \u2026 like You who keep Your covenant and mercy with Your servants who walk before You with what?","answer":"with all their hearts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:24 You have _____ what You _____ Your servant David my father.","answer":"kept, promised"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:24 You have kept what You promised whom?","answer":"Your servant David my father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:24 You have both done what and fulfilled it with Your hand?","answer":"spoken with Your mouth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:24 You have both spoken with Your mouth and done what?","answer":"fulfilled it with Your hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:24 You have both spoken with Your mouth and fulfilled it with Your hand, as it is when?","answer":"this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 Therefore, whom, now keep what You promised Your servant David my father? Be specific.","answer":"Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 Therefore, Lord God of Israel, now keep what You promised whom?","answer":"Your servant David my father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have what on the throne of Israel, only if your sons take heed to their way?","answer":"a man sit before Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have a man sit before Me on what, only if your sons take heed to their way?","answer":"on the throne of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have a man sit before Me on the throne of Israel, only if your what take heed to their way?","answer":"your sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have a man sit before Me on the throne of Israel, only if your sons do what?","answer":" take heed to their way"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have a man sit before Me on the throne of Isarel, \u2026 that they do what before Me as you have walked before Me?","answer":"they walk before Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:25 You shall not fail to have a man sit before Me on the throne of Isarel, \u2026 that they shall walk before Me as you have done what?","answer":"have walked before Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:26 Let your what come true, which You have spoken to Your servant David my father?","answer":"Your word"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:26 Let Your word do what, which You have spoken to Your servant David my father?","answer":"come true"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:26 Let Your word come true, which You have spoken to whom?","answer":"to Your servant David my father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:27 But will God indeed do what?","answer":"dwell on earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:27 But will whom dwell on earth?","answer":"will God indeed"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:27 What two things cannot contain You (God)?","answer":"heaven and the heaven of heavens"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:27 Behold, heaven and the heaven of heavens cannot do what?","answer":"cannot contain You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:27 \u2026heaven \u2026 cannot contain You. How much less this what?","answer":"this temple which I have built"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 Yet regard the what of Your servant and his supplication?","answer":"the prayer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 Yet regard the prayer of whom and his supplication? Be specific.","answer":"of Your servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 Yet regard the prayer of Your servant and his what?","answer":"his supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 2 pts. \u2026listen to the what which Your servant is praying before You today?","answer":"the cry and the prayer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 \u2026 listen to the cry and the prayer which whom is praying before You today? Be specific.","answer":"Your servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 \u2026 listen to the cry and the prayer which Your servant is what?","answer":"is praying before You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:28 When is Your servant praying before You?","answer":"today"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 \u2026 that Your what may be open toward this temple night and day?","answer":"Your eyes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 \u2026 that Your eyes may be what toward this temple night and day?","answer":"may be open"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 2 pts. \u2026 that Your eyes may be open toward what night and day?","answer":"toward this temple, toward the place of which You said, 'My name shall be there'"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 2 pts.  \u2026 that Your eyes may be open toward this temple when?","answer":"night and day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 \u2026 that Your eyes may be open \u2026 toward the place of which You said what?","answer":" 'My name shall be there'"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:29 \u2026 that Your eyes may be open toward this temple \u2026, that You may _____  the _____ which Your _____ makes toward this place?","answer":"hear, prayer, servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 And may You hear what of Your servant and of Your people Israel?","answer":"the supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 2 pts. And may You hear the supplication of whom?","answer":"Your servant and of Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 May You hear the supplication of Your servant and of Your people Israel when they do what?","answer":"when they pray toward this place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 Hear from where, and when You hear, forgive.","answer":"in heaven Your dwelling place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 Hear in heaven Your dwelling place, and when You hear, do what?","answer":"forgive"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:30 Hear in heaven Your dwelling place, and when You do what, forgive?","answer":"when You hear"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31 When anyone does what against his neighbor, and is forced to take an oath, \u2026 (then hear in heaven, and act, \u2026)?","answer":"sins"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31 When anyone sins against whom, and is forced to take an oath, \u2026 (then hear in heaven, and act, \u2026)?","answer":"against his neighbor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31 When anyone sins against his neighbor, and is forced to do what, \u2026 (then hear in heaven and act, \u2026)?","answer":"to take an oath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31 When anyone sins against his neighbor, and is forced to take an oath, and then does what before Your altar \u2026 (then hear)?","answer":"comes and takes an oath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31 2 pts. When anyone sins \u2026 and is forced to take an oath, and then comes and takes and oath where \u2026, (then hear)?","answer":"before Your altar in this temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31-32 When anyone sins \u2026 and is forced to take an oath \u2026 then _____ in heaven, and _____, and _____ Your servants, \u2026?","answer":"hear, act, judge"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31-32 When anyone sins \u2026 and is forced to take an oath, then hear in heaven, and act, and judge whom?","answer":"Your servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:31-32 When anyone sins \u2026 and is forced to take an oath, then hear in heaven, and act, and judge Your servants, condemning whom?","answer":"the wicked"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:32 \u2026 hear in heaven, and act, and judge Your servants, condemning the wicked how?","answer":"bringing his way on his head"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:32 \u2026 hear in heaven, and act, and judge Your servants, condemning the wicked, bringing his way on his head, and doing what else?","answer":"justifying the righteous"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:32 \u2026 hear in heaven, and act, and judge Your servants, ... and justifying the righteous how?","answer":"by giving him according to his righteousness"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:32 The righteous will be what by giving him according to his righteousness?","answer":"justified"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:32 The wicked will be what when God brings his (the wicked) way on his (the wicked) head?","answer":"condemned"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33 When whom is defeated before an enemy because they have sinned against You, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33 When Your people Israel are what because they have sinned against You, \u2026 (then hear)?","answer":"are defeated before an enemy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33 When Your people Israel are defeated before an enemy -- why (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"because they have sinned against you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33 4 pts. When Your people Israel are defeated \u2026 because they have sinned against You, and when they do what, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"turn back to You and confess Your name, and pray and make supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33 When Your people Israel are defeated before an enemy \u2026 and when they turn back \u2026 confess \u2026 and pray and make supplication to You where, (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"in this temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33-34 When Your people Israel are defeated before an enemy and when they turn back \u2026 confess \u2026 and pray and make supplication \u2026, then do what 3 things?","answer":"hear in heaven, and forgive \u2026, and bring them back to the land which You gave to their fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:33-34 When Your people Israel are defeated \u2026 and when they \u2026 make supplication to You ..., then hear in heaven, and forgive the sins of Your people Israel, and bring them back where?","answer":"to the land which You gave to their fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:34 \u2026 then hear ... and forgive ..., and bring them back to the land which You gave to whom?","answer":"to their fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35 When what is shut up and there is no rain \u2026. (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"the heavens"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35 When the heavens are shut up and there is no what because they have sinned against You, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"there is no rain"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35 When the heavens are shut up and there is no rain because they have done what, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"have sinned against You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35 When there was no rain because they sinned against God, what 3 things does Solomon say could be done so God would hear and forgive?","answer":"pray toward this place, confess Your name, turn from their sin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35 When \u2026 there is no rain because they have sinned against You, when they pray toward this place and confess Your name, and turn from their sin -- for what reason? (then hear \u2026)","answer":"because You afflict them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35-36 When \u2026 there is no rain \u2026, when they \u2026 turn from their sin because You afflict them, then _____ in _____, and ______ the _____ of Your servants.","answer":"hear, heaven, forgive, sin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35-36 2 pts. When \u2026 there is no rain \u2026, when they \u2026 turn from their sin because You afflict them, then hear in heaven, and forgive the sin of whom?","answer":"of Your servants, Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35-36 When \u2026 there is no rain \u2026, when they \u2026 turn from their sin ..., then ... forgive the sin of Your servants \u2026, that You may teach them what; and send rain...?","answer":"teach them the good way in which they should walk"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:35-36 When \u2026 there is no rain \u2026, when they \u2026 turn from their sin ..., then ... forgive the sin of Your servants \u2026, that You may teach them the good way in which they should walk; and do what on Your land?","answer":"send rain"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:36 ... teach them the good way in which they should walk; and send rain on what which You have given to Your people?","answer":"on Your land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:36 \u2026 teach them the good way in which they should walk; and send rain on Your land which You have given to whom?","answer":"to Your people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:36 \u2026 send rain on Your land which You have given to Your people as an what?","answer":"as an inheritance"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:36 What was given to God's people as an inheritance?","answer":"Your land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:37 9 pts.  Name the problems listed in this verse.  ","answer":"famine, pestilence, blight, mildew, locusts, grasshoppers, enemy, plague, sickness"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:37 When there is famine in the land, pestilence or blight or mildew, or locusts or grasshoppers; when their enemy does what in the land of their cities \u2026 (then hear)?","answer":"besieges them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:37 When there is famine in the land, pestilence or blight or mildew, or locusts or grasshoppers; when their enemy besieges them where \u2026 (then hear)?","answer":"in the land of their cities"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38 \u2026 whatever _____, whatever _____ is made by anyone, or by all Your people Israel, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)","answer":"prayer, supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38 2 pts. \u2026 whatever prayer, whatever supplication is made by whom, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"by anyone, or by all Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38 \u2026 whatever supplication is made by anyone, or by all your people Israel, when each one knows what, (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"know the plague of his own heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38 \u2026 whatever supplication is made by anyone, or by all your people Israel, when each one knows the plague of his own heart, and does what, (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"spreads out his hands toward this temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38-39 \u2026 when each one knows the plague of his own heart, and spreads out his hands toward this temple, then do what in heaven Your dwelling place?","answer":"hear"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38-39 \u2026 when each one knows the plague of his own heart, and spreads out his hands toward this temple, then hear in what?","answer":"in heaven Your dwelling place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:38-39 \u2026 when each ... spreads out his hands toward this temple, then hear in heaven \u2026 and _____, and _____, and _____ to everyone according to all his ways.","answer":"forgive, act, give"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 \u2026 then hear \u2026 and forgive, and act, and give to everyone how?","answer":"according to all his ways"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 \u2026 then hear \u2026 and forgive, and act, and give to everyone according to all his ways, whose what You know?","answer":"whose heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 \u2026 then hear \u2026 and forgive, and act, and give to everyone according to all his ways, whose heart You what?","answer":"You know"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 For You alone know the what of all the sons of men?","answer":"the hearts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 For You alone know the hearts of whom?","answer":"of all the sons of men"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:39 Who knows the hearts of the sons of men?","answer":"You alone (God)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:40 (\u2026 give to everyone according to all his ways \u2026), that they may do what all the days that they live in the land?","answer":"fear You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:40 (\u2026 give to everyone according to all his ways \u2026), that they may fear You how long?","answer":"all the days they live in the land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:40 (\u2026 give to everyone according to all his ways \u2026), that they may fear You all the days that they live in the land which You gave to whom?","answer":"to our fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41 Moreover, concerning a what, who is not of Your people Israel, \u2026 (hear in heaven \u2026)?","answer":"a foreigner"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41 Concerning a foreigner, who is not of what, but has come from a far country for Your name's sake \u2026 (hear in heaven\u2026)?","answer":"is not of Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41 Concerning a foreigner, who is not of Your people Israel, but has come from where for Your name's sake \u2026 (hear in heaven\u2026)?","answer":"a far country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41 Concerning a foreigner, who is not of Your people Israel, but has come from a far country for what reason ... (hear in heaven\u2026)?","answer":"for Your name's sake"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41-42 Who will hear of Your great name and Your strong hand and Your outstretched arm?","answer":"a foreigner OR one who is not of Your people OR one who has come from a far country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41-42 When will a foreigner hear of Your great name and Your strong hand and Your outstretched arm?","answer":"when he comes and prays toward this temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:41-42 3 pts. ( A foreigner \u2026) will hear of Your what?","answer":"Your great name, Your strong hand, your outstretched arm"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all whom may know Your name and fear You, as do Your people Israel?","answer":"that all peoples of the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all peoples of the earth may know Your name and fear You, as do whom?","answer":"Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 (Concerning a foreigner \u2026 when he prays toward this temple:) then do what in heaven Your dwelling place?","answer":"hear"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 (Concerning a foreigner \u2026 when he prays toward this temple:) then hear in where?","answer":"in heaven Your dwelling place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 (Concerning a foreigner \u2026 when he prays toward this temple:) then hear in heaven ..., and what for which the foreigner calls to You?","answer":"do according to all"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 (Concerning a foreigner \u2026 when he prays toward this temple:) then hear in heaven \u2026, and do according to all for which the foreigner does what?","answer":"calls to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all the peoples of the earth may know what?","answer":"Your name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all the peoples of the earth may know Your name and do what?","answer":"fear You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all \u2026 may know Your name and fear You, \u2026 and that they may know that what is called by Your name?","answer":"this temple which I have built"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:43 \u2026 that all \u2026 may know Your name and fear You, \u2026 and that they may know that this temple which I have built is what?","answer":"is called by Your name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 When whom go out to battle against their enemy, \u2026 and they pray \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"Your people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 When Your people do what, wherever You send them, and when they pray \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"go out to battle against their enemy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 When Your people go out to battle against their enemy, wherever You do what, and when they pray \u2026, (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"wherever You send them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 When Your people go out to battle against their enemy, wherever You send them, and when they do what toward the city which You have chosen \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"pray to the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 2 pts. When Your people go out to battle \u2026, and when they pray to the Lord toward what (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"toward the city which You have chosen and the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:44 When Your people go out to battle \u2026, and when they pray to the Lord toward the city which You have chosen and the temple which I have built for what (then hear\u2026)?","answer":"for Your name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:45 (When your people go out to battle \u2026 and when they pray \u2026), then do what to their prayer and their supplication?","answer":"hear in heaven"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:45 2 pts. (When your people go out to battle \u2026 and when they pray \u2026), then hear in heaven their what?","answer":"their prayer and their supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:45 (When your people go out to battle \u2026 and when they pray \u2026), then hear in heaven their prayer and their supplication, and do what else?","answer":"maintain their cause (see similar in vs. 50)"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When they do what, (for there is no one who does not sin), \u2026 (yet when they \u2026 repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"when they sin against You"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When they sin against You (for there is no one who does not what), \u2026 (yet when they \u2026 repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"who does not sin"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When they sin against you \u2026, and You do what and deliver them to the enemy, \u2026 (yet when they .. repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"You become angry with them"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When they sin against you \u2026, and You become angry with them and do what, \u2026 (yet when they .. repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"deliver them to the enemy"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When \u2026 You become angry with them and deliver them to the enemy, and they do what, far or near, \u2026 (yet when they .. repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"take them captive to the land of the enemy"},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 8:46 When \u2026 You become angry with them and deliver them to the enemy, and they take them captive to the land of the enemy, where \u2026 (yet when they .. repent, \u2026 then hear \u2026)?","answer":"far or near"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 (When they sin) \u2026 yet when they what in the land where they were carried captive, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"come to themselves"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 (When they sin) \u2026 yet when they come to themselves where, \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"in the land where they were carried captive"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 (When they sin) \u2026 yet when they come to themselves in the land where they were carried captive, and do what, and make supplication to You \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"and repent"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 (When they sin) \u2026 yet when they come to themselves in the land where they were carried captive, and repent, and do what \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"make supplication to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 (When they sin) \u2026 yet when they come to themselves in the land where they were carried captive, and repent, and make supplication to You where \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"in the land of those who took them captive"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47 We have _____ and done _____, we have committed _____.","answer":"sinned, wrong, wickedness"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they do what with all their heart and with all their soul \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"return to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 2 pts. \u2026 when they return to You how in the land of their enemies who led them away captive \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"with all their heart and with all their soul"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You with all their heart and with all their soul where ... , and pray to You \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"in the land of their enemies who led them away captive"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You \u2026 in the land of their enemies ... , and do what toward their land which You gave their fathers \u2026 (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"pray to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You \u2026 in the land of their enemies ... , and pray to You toward what \u2026, the city which You have chosen and the temple which I have built for Your name: (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"toward their land which You gave their fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You \u2026 in the land of their enemies ... , and pray to You toward their land which You gave their fathers, the what and the temple which I have built for Your name: (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"the city which You have chosen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You \u2026 in the land of their enemies ... , and pray to You toward their land which You gave their fathers, the city which You have chosen and the what which I have built for Your name: (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:48 \u2026 when they return to You \u2026 in the land of their enemies ... , and pray to You toward their land which You gave their fathers, the city which You have chosen and the temple which I have what: (then hear \u2026)?","answer":"which I have built for Your name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:47-48 Name the 5 steps Solomon says the people should do if they sin and are taken captive, and God will hear in heaven.","answer":"come to themselves, repent,\nmake supplication to You,\nreturn to You, pray to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:49 (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026), then do what in heaven Your dwelling place?","answer":"hear"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:49 (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026), then hear in where their prayer and their supplication?","answer":"in heaven Your dwelling place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:49 2 pts. (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026), then hear in heaven Your dwelling place their what?","answer":"their prayer and their supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:49 (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026), then hear in heaven Your dwelling place their prayer and their supplication, and do what else?","answer":"maintain their cause (see similar in vs. 45)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026 then hear, and maintain their cause), and do what to Your people who have sinned against You?","answer":"forgive Your people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 (When they sin against You \u2026 and repent \u2026 then hear, and maintain their cause), and forgive Your people who have done what?","answer":"have sinned against You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 \u2026 forgive Your people who have sinned against You, and all their what which they have transgressed against You?","answer":"transgressions"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 \u2026 forgive Your people who have sinned against You, and all their transgressions which they have what?","answer":"have transgressed against You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 \u2026 forgive Your people ..., and all their transgressions which they have transgressed against You; and do what before those who took them captive?","answer":"grant them compassion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 \u2026 grant them compassion before those who did what, that they may have compassion on them?","answer":"who took them captive"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:50 \u2026 grant them compassion before those who took them captive, that they may have what on them?","answer":"have compassion on them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:51 2 pts. \u2026 (for they are what, whom You brought out of Egypt, out of the iron furnace)?","answer":"are Your people and Your inheritance"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:51 2 pts. \u2026 (for they are Your people and Your inheritance, whom You brought out of where?","answer":"out of Egypt, out of the iron furnace"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:52 Solomon is praying that what may be open to the supplication of his prayer and the supplication of the people of Israel?","answer":"Your (God's) eyes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:52 Solomon is praying that God's eyes may be open to the what of both himself and of the people of Israel?","answer":"the supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:52 2 pts. Solomon is praying that God's eyes may be open to the supplication of whom?","answer":"of Your servant,\nof Your people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:52 Solomon is praying that God's eyes may be open \u2026, to do what whenever they call to You?","answer":"to listen to them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:52 Solomon is praying that God's eyes may be open \u2026, to listen whenever they do what?","answer":"call to You"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:53 For You did what from among all the peoples of the earth to be Your inheritance?","answer":"You separated them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:53 For You separated them from among whom to be Your inheritance?","answer":"from among all the peoples of the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:53 You separated them from among all the peoples of the earth to be what?","answer":"to be Your inheritance"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:53 You separated them from among all the peoples of the earth to be Your inheritance, as You spoke by whom?","answer":"by Your servant Moses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:53 You separated them from among all the peoples of the earth to be Your inheritance, as You spoke by Your servant Moses, when You did what?","answer":"when You borught our fathers out of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:54 2 pts. When Solomon had done what to the Lord, that he arose from before the altar of the Lord?","answer":"had finished all this prayer and supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:54 When Solomon had finished praying all this prayer and supplication to the Lord, that he arose from where, from kneeling on his knees?","answer":"from before the altar of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:54 When Solomon had finished \u2026 he arose from before the altar of the Lord, from doing what with his hands spread up to heaven?","answer":"from kneeling on his knees"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:54 When Solomon had finished \u2026 he arose from before the altar of the Lord, from kneeling on his knees with his hands how?","answer":"spread up to heaven"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:54 When Solomon had finished \u2026 he arose ..., from kneeling on his knees with what spread up to heaven?","answer":"his hands"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:55 Then he _____ and _____ all the _____ of Israel with a loud voice.","answer":"stood, blessed, assembly"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:55 Then he stood and blessed all the assembly of Israel with what?","answer":"with a loud voice"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 Blessed be the Lord, who has given what to His people Israel?","answer":"given rest"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 Blessed be the Lord, who has given rest to whom?","answer":"to His people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 Blessed be the Lord, who has given rest to His people Israel, according to what?","answer":"to all that He promised"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 There has not failed what of all His good promise?","answer":"one word"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 There has not failed one word of what?","answer":"of all His good promise"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:56 There has not failed one word of all His good promise, which He promised through whom?","answer":"His servant Moses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:57 May the Lord our God be what, as He was with our fathers?","answer":"with us"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:57 May the Lord our God be with us, and He was with whom?","answer":"with our fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:57 May He not _____ us nor _____ us.","answer":"leave, forsake"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:58 (May He not leave us nor forsake us,) that He may do what, to walk in all His ways, and to keep His commandments \u2026?","answer":"incline our heart to Himself"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:58 (May He not leave us nor forsake us,) that He may incline our hearts to Himself, to do what, and to keep His commandments and His statutes and His judgments \u2026?","answer":"to walk in all His ways"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:58 3 pts. (May He not leave us nor forsake us,) that He may incline our hearts to Himself, to walk in all His ways, and to keep what \u2026?","answer":"His commandments and His statutes and His judgments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:58 ... that He may incline our hearts to Himself, to walk ..., and to keep His commandments and His statutes and His judgments, which He commanded whom \u2026?","answer":"our fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:58 3 pts.  What did He command our fathers?","answer":"to keep His commandments and His statutes and His judgments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 And may these what, with which I have made supplication before the Lord, be near the Lord our God day and night?","answer":"these words of mine"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 May these words of mine, with which I have done what before the Lord, be near the Lord our God day and night?","answer":"have made supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 May these words of mine, with which I have made supplication before the Lord, be what day and night?","answer":"be near the Lord our God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 2 pts. May these words of mine, with which I have made supplication before the Lord, be near the Lord our God when?","answer":"day and night"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 May these words of mine \u2026 be near the Lord \u2026 , that He may do what of His servant?","answer":"may maintain the cause"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 2 pts. May these words of mine \u2026 be near the Lord \u2026 , that He may maintain the cause of whom?","answer":"His servant, His people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:59 2 pts. May these words of mine \u2026 be near the Lord \u2026 , that He may maintain the cause of His servant and the cause of His people Israel, as what?","answer":"as each day may require"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:60 (May these words of mine \u2026 be near the Lord \u2026,) that whom may know that the Lord is God; there is no other?","answer":"all the peoples of the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:60 (May these words of mine \u2026 be near the Lord \u2026,) that all the peoples of the earth may know what; there is no other?","answer":"that the Lord is God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:61 Let your what therefore be loyal to the Lord our God?","answer":"your heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:61 Let your heart therefore be what to the Lord our God?","answer":"be loyal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:61 Let your heart therefore be loyal \u2026, to do what and keep His commandments, as at this day?","answer":"to walk in His statutes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:61 Let your heart therefore be loyal \u2026, to walk in His statutes and do what, as at this day?","answer":"keep His commandments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:62 2 pts. Then who offered sacrifices before the Lord?","answer":"the king and Israel with him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:62 Then the king and all Israel with him did what before the Lord?","answer":"offered sacrifices"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 Solomon offered a what, which he offered to the Lord?","answer":"a sacrifice of peace offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 How many bulls did Solomon offer as a sacrifice of peace?","answer":22000},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 Solomon offered a sacrifice of peace offerings, \u2026 22,000 what?","answer":"bulls"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 Solomon offered a sacrifice of peace offerings, \u2026 120,000 what?","answer":"sheep"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 How many sheep did Solomon offer as a sacrifice of peace?","answer":120000},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 2 pts. So who dedicated the house of the Lord?","answer":"the king and all the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 So the king and all the children of Israel did what?","answer":"dedicated the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:63 The 22,000 bulls and 120,000 sheep were offered as what kind of a sacrifice?","answer":"peace offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 When did the King consecrate the middle of the court that was in front of the house of the Lord?","answer":"on the same day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 On the same day the king did what for the middle of the court that was in front of the house of the Lord?","answer":"consecrated (it)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 On the same day the king consecrated what that was in front of the house of the Lord?","answer":"the middle of the court"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 On the same day the king consecrated the middle of the court that was where?","answer":"in front of the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 3 pts.  What offerings did the king use to consecrate the middle of the court?","answer":"burnt offerings, grain offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 Why did the king consecrate the middle of the court with burnt offerings, grain offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings?","answer":"because the bronze altar that was before the Lord was too small to receive (them)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 3 pts. The bronze altar that was before the Lord was too small to receive what?","answer":"burnt offerings, grain offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64 Where did the king offer burnt offerings, grain offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings?","answer":"the middle of the court that was in front of the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:64  What was too small for the burnt offerings, grain offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings?","answer":"the bronze altar that was before the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 At that time who held a feast, and all Israel with him?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 At that time Solomon did what, and all Israel with him?","answer":"held a feast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 At that time Solomon held a feast, and who else with him?","answer":"all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 At that time Solomon held a feast, and all Israel with him, a what from the entrance of Hamath to the Brook of Egypt?","answer":"a great assembly"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 At that time Solomon held a feast, and all Israel with him, a great assembly from where to where?","answer":"from Hamath to the Brook of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 Solomon held a feast, and all Israel with him, \u2026 before the Lord our God, for how many days?","answer":"7 days and 7 more days--14 days"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:65 For 7 days and 7 more days--14 days they did what?","answer":"held a feast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 Which day did he send the people away; and they blessed the king?","answer":"on the 8th day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 On the 8th day he did what, and they blessed the king?","answer":"he sent the people away"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 On the 8th day he sent the people away; and they did what, and went to their tents joyful and glad of heart?","answer":"blessed the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 \u2026 they blessed the king, and went where joyful and glad of heart?","answer":"to their tents (their homes)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 \u2026 they \u2026 went to their tents _____ and _____ of _____ for all the good that the Lord had done for His servant David \u2026","answer":"joyful, glad, heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 \u2026 they \u2026 went to their tents joyful and glad of heart for all the what that the Lord had done?","answer":"all the good"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 2 pts. \u2026 they \u2026 went to their tents joyful and glad of heart for all the good that the Lord had done for whom?","answer":"for His servant David,\nand for Israel His people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 8:66 Where did they go joyful and glad of heart?","answer":"to their tents (their homes)"}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */        
    ],
    "c9":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:1 2 pts. It came to pass, when Solomon had finished building what, \u2026 (that the Lord appeared to Solomon the 2nd time \u2026)?","answer":"the house of the Lord and the king's house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:1 When Solomon had finished building the house of the Lord and the king's house, and all Solomon's what, (that the Lord appeared to Solomon the 2nd time\u2026)?","answer":"desire which he wanted to do"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:1-2 When did the Lord appear to Solomon the 2nd time?","answer":"when Solomon had finished building the house of the Lord and the king's house, and all his desire which he wanted to do"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:2 \u2026 the Lord appeared to whom the second time?","answer":"to Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:2 \u2026 the Lord appeared to Solomon the what, as He had appeared to him at Gibeon?","answer":"the 2nd time"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:2 \u2026 the Lord appeared to Solomon the 2nd time, as He had appeared to him where?","answer":"at Gibeon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 I have heard your _____ and your _____ that you have made before Me.","answer":"prayer, supplication"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 I have what this house which you have built to put My name there forever?","answer":"I have consecrated"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 I have consecrated what which you have built to put My name there forever?","answer":"this house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 I have consecrated this house which you have built to put what there forever?","answer":"My name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 What two things did God say would be there perpetually?","answer":"My eyes and My heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:3 \u2026 My eyes and My heart will be there for how long?","answer":"perpetually"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 Now if you do what as your father David walked, in integrity and uprightness \u2026 (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"walk before Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 Now if you walk before Me as whom walked, in integrity and uprightness \u2026 (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"as your father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 2 pts.. Now if you walk before Me as your father David walked, in what, \u2026 (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"in integrity and uprightness"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 Now if you walk before Me \u2026, to what that I have commanded you, \u2026 (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"to do according to all that I have commanded you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 Now if you walk before Me \u2026, to do according to all that I have what, \u2026 (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"all that I have commanded you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:4 2 pts. Now if you walk before me \u2026, to do all that I have commanded you, and if you do what else, (then I will establish the throne \u2026 forever)?","answer":"keep My statutes and My judgments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:5 \u2026 I will do what over Israel forever, as I promised David your father \u2026 ?","answer":"establish the throne of your kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:5 \u2026 I will establish the throne of your kingdom over what forever, as I promised David your father?","answer":"over Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:5 \u2026 I will establish the throne of your kingdom over Israel for how long, as I promised David your father?","answer":"forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:5 \u2026 I will establish the throne of your kingdom over Israel forever, as I promised whom?","answer":"David your father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:5 \u2026 I promised David your father, saying, 'You shall not _____ to have a _____ on the _____ of _____.","answer":"fail, man, throne, Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6 2 pts. But if whom at all turn from following Me, \u2026 (then I will cut off Israel \u2026)?","answer":"you or your sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6 But if you or your sons at all do what, and do not keep My commandments and My statutes \u2026 (then I will cut off Israel)?","answer":"turn from following Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6 2 pts. But if you or your sons at all turn from following Me, and do not what \u2026 (then I will cut off Israel)?","answer":"keep My commandments and My statutes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6 But if you or your sons ... do not keep My commandments and My statutes which I have what, \u2026 (then I will cut off Israel)?","answer":"which I have set before you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6 2 pts. But if you or your sons ... do not keep My commandments and My statutes which I have set before you, but do what, \u2026 (then I will cut off Israel)?","answer":"go and serve other gods and worship them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:6-7 3 pts.  For what reasons would God cut off Israel?","answer":"if Solomon or his sons turn from following God, do not keep the commandments and statutes God set, or go and serve and worship other gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 (If Solomon or his sons go and serve and worship other gods) I will do what from the land which I have given them?","answer":"I will cut off Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 (If Solomon or his sons go and serve and worship other gods) I will cut off Israel from what?","answer":"from this land which I have given them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 \u2026 this what which I have consecrated for My name I will cast out of My sight?","answer":"this house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 \u2026 this house which I have done what for My name I will cast out of My sight?","answer":"I have consecrated"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 \u2026 this house which I have consecrated for what I will cast out of My sight?","answer":"for My name"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 \u2026 this house which I have consecrated for My name I will do what?","answer":"will cast out of My sight"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 2 pts. Israel will be a what among all peoples?","answer":"a proverb and a byword"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 What will be a proverb and a byword among all peoples?","answer":"Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:7 Israel will be a proverb and a byword among whom?","answer":"among all peoples"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 As for this what, which is exalted, everyone who passes by it will be astonished and will hiss?","answer":"this house (the temple)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 As for this house, which is what, everyone who passes by it will be astonished and will hiss?","answer":"is exalted"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 As for this house, which is exalted, everyone who does what will be astonished and will hiss?","answer":"who passes by it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 As for this house, which is exalted, everyone who passes by it will be what and will hiss?","answer":"be astonished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 As for this house, which is exalted, everyone who passes by it will be astonished and will what?","answer":"will hiss"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:8 What question would everyone ask when they pass by the ruined temple and be astonished and hiss?","answer":"Why has the Lord done thus to this land and to this house?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 Because they did what, \u2026, and have embraced other gods, and worshiped them and served them, therefore the Lord has brought all this calamity on them?","answer":"they forsook the Lord their God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 Because they forsook the Lord their God, who did what, and have embraced other gods, and worshiped them and served them, therefore the Lord has brought all this calamity on them?","answer":"who brought their fathers out of the land of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 Because they forsook the Lord their God, ..., and have done what, and worshiped them and served them, therefore the Lord has brought all this calamity on them?","answer":"have embraced other gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 2 pts. Because they forsook the Lord their God, ..., and have embraced other gods, and what else, therefore the Lord has brought all this calamity on them?","answer":"worshiped them and served them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 Because they forsook the Lord their God, ..., and have embraced other gods, and worshiped them and served them, therefore the Lord has done what?","answer":"has brought all this calamity on them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:9 4 pts.  Why has the Lord brought this calamity on them?","answer":"they forsook the Lord their God, have embraced other gods, worshiped and served them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:10 Now it happened when, when Solomon had built the 2 houses, \u2026 (... that King Solomon then gave Hiram 20 cities \u2026)?","answer":"at the end of 20 years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:10 Now it happened at the end of 20 years, when Solomon had built how many houses, \u2026 (... that King Solomon then gave Hiram 20 cities \u2026)?","answer":"the 2 houses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:10 What 2 houses had Solomon built at the end of 20 years?","answer":"the house of the Lord and the king's house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 Who had supplied Solomon with cedar and cypress and gold, as much as he desired?","answer":"Hiram the king of Tyre"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 Hiram the king of Tyre had supplied Solomon with what 3 things, as much as he desired?","answer":"cedar and cypress and gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 Hiram the king of Tyre had supplied Solomon with cedar and cypress and gold -- how much of it?","answer":"as much as he desired"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 (Now it happened at the end of 20 years \u2026) \u2026 that King Solomon then gave whom 20 cities in the land of Galilee?","answer":"Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 (Now it happened at the end of 20 years \u2026) \u2026 that King Solomon then gave Hiram what in the land of Galilee?","answer":"20 cities"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:11 Where were the 20 cities located which King Solomon gave to Hiram?","answer":"in Galilee"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:12 Then Hiram went from where to see the cities which Solomon had given him?","answer":"from Tyre"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:12 Then Hiram went from Tyre to see what?","answer":"the cities which  Solomon had given him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:12 The Hiram went \u2026 to see the cities which Solomon had given him, but they what?","answer":"they did not please him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:12 What did not please Hiram?","answer":"the 20 cities Solomon had given him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:13 What kind of _____ are these which you have _____ me, my brother?","answer":"cities, given"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:13 What name did Hiram call Solomon after he visited the 20 cities Solomon gave him?","answer":"my brother"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:13 What did Hiram call the 20 cities which Solomon had given him?","answer":"the land of Cabul"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:13 For how long were the 20 cities given to Hiram called \"land of Cabul\"?","answer":"(called that) to this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:14 Then who sent the king 120 talents of gold?","answer":"Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:14 Then Hiram sent whom 120 talents of gold?","answer":"the king (Solomon)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:14 Then Hiram sent the king what?","answer":"120 talents of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:15 And this is the reason for the what which King Solomon raised?","answer":"the labor force"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:15 And this is the reason for the labor force which who raised?","answer":"King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:15 7 pts. And this is the reason for the labor force which King Solomon raised: to build what?","answer":"the house of the Lord, his own house, the Millo, the wall of Jerusalem, Hazor, Megiddo, and Gezer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:15 Who built the house of the Lord, Solomon's own house, the Millo, the wall of Jerusalem, Hazor, Megiddo, and Gezer?","answer":"the labor force which Solomon raised"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Who had gone up and taken Gezer and burned it with fire?","answer":"Pharaoh king of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Pharoah king of Egypt had gone up and taken what and burned it with fire?","answer":"Gezer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Pharoah king of Egypt had gone up and taken Gezer and did what to it?","answer":"burned it with fire"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Pharaoh king of Egypt had gone up and taken Gezer and burned it with fire, had done what to the Canaanites who dwelt in the city?","answer":"killed (them)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Pharaoh king of Egypt had gone up and taken Gezer and burned it with fire, had killed whom?","answer":"the Canaanites who dwelt in the city"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 Pharoah king of Egypt took Gezer, burned it, killed the Caananites who dwelt in the city, and had done what then?","answer":"given it as a dowry to his daughter, Solomon's wife"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:16 What was given as a dowry to Pharoah's daughter, Solomon's wife?","answer":"Gezer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:17 Solomon built what 2 towns?","answer":"Gezer, Lower Beth Horon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:17 Who built Gezer and Lower Beth Horon?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:18 (Solomon built) what 2 towns in this verse?","answer":"Baalath, and Tadmor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:18 2 pts.  Where was Tadmor located?","answer":"in the wilderness, in the land of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:18 What town was located in the wilderness, in the land of Judah?","answer":"Tadmor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:19 (Solomon built) all the what that Solomon had?","answer":"storage cities"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:19 (Solomon built) all the storage cities that Solomon had, cities for what 2 things?","answer":"for his chariots and for his cavalry"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:19 3 pts. (Solomon built) all the storage cities that Solomon had \u2026 and whatever Solomon desired to build where?","answer":"in Jerusalem, in Lebanon, and in all the land of his dominion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:19 Who built in Jerusalem, in Lebanon, and in all the land of his dominion?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:20 Name the 5 peoples who were left, who were not of the children of Israel?","answer":"Amorites, Hittites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:20 All the people who were left, the Amorites, Hittites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites, who were not of what (from these Solomon raised forced labor)?","answer":"of the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:20-21 5 pts.  What groups had the children of Israel not been able to destroy completely?","answer":"the Amorites, Hittites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:21 (All the people who were left), that is, their what who were left in the land after them \u2026 (from these Solomon raised forced labor)?","answer":"their descendants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:21 (All the people who were left), that is, their descendants who were what \u2026 (from these Solomon raised forced labor)?","answer":"were left in the land after them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:21 What had the children of Israel not been able to do to all the people who were left in the land?","answer":"destroy them completely"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:21 From what groups did Solomon raise forced labor?","answer":"their descendants who were left in the land after them, OR the Amorites, Hittites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:21 From these Solomon raised forced labor -- how long did it last?","answer":"as it is to this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:22 But of whom Solomon made no forced laborers, because they were men of war and his servants?","answer":"of the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:22 But of the children of Israel Solomon made no what, because they were men of war and his servants?","answer":"no forced laborers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:22 2 pts. But the children of Israel Solomon made no forced laborers, because they were what?","answer":"men of war and his servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:22 Who were the men of war and Solomon's servants?","answer":"the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:22 4 pts.  Name the servants listed in this verse.","answer":"officers, captains, commanders of his chariots, and his cavalry"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:23 Others were what who were over Solomon's work?","answer":"were chiefs of the officials"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:23 Others were chiefs of the officials who were over what?","answer":"over Solomon's work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:23 How many were chiefs of the officials who ruled over the people who did the work?","answer":550},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:23 There were 550 who ruled over whom?","answer":"over the people who did the work"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:24 But who came up from the City of David to her house which Solomon had built for her?","answer":"Pharoah's daughter"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:24 But Pharaoh's daughter came up from where to her house which Solomon had built for her?","answer":"from the City of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:24 But Pharaoh's daughter came up from the City of David to what which Solomon had built for her?","answer":"to her house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:24 What did Solomon build after Pharoah's daughter came up from the City of David to her house?","answer":"the Millo"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:24 Who built the Millo?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 How often did Solomon offer burnt offerings and peace offerings on the alter which he had built for the Lord?","answer":"3 times a year"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 2 pts. Now 3 times a year Solomon offered what on the altar which he had built for the Lord?","answer":"burnt offering and peace offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 Three times a year Solomon offered burnt offerings and peace offerings on what which he had built for the Lord?","answer":"on the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 \u2026 Solomon offered burnt offerings and peace offerings on the altar which he had built for the Lord, and he did what with them on the altar?","answer":"burned incense"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 \u2026 Solomon \u2026 burned incense with them on what that was before the Lord?","answer":"on the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:25 So Solomon finished what?","answer":"the temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 King Solomon also built what at Ezion Geber?","answer":"a fleet of ships"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 King Solomon also built a fleet of ships where, which is near Elath on the shore of the Red Sea in the land of Edom?","answer":"at Ezion Geber"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 King Solomon also built a fleet of ships at Ezion Geber, which is near what on the shore of the Red Sea in the land of Edom?","answer":"near Elath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 King Solomon built a fleet of ships at Ezion Geber, which is near Elath on what in the land of Edom?","answer":"on the shore of the Red Sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 King Solomon built a fleet of ships at Ezion Geber, which is near Elath on the shore of the Red Sea, where?","answer":"in the land of Edom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:26 What did King Solomon build near Elath on the shore of the Red Sea, in the land of Edom?","answer":"a fleet of ships"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:27 Then who sent his servants with the fleet, seamen who knew the sea?","answer":"Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:27 2 pts. Then Hiram sent what with the fleet?","answer":"his servants, seamen who knew the sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:27 Hiram sent his servants with the fleet, seamen who knew the sea, to work with whom?","answer":"with the servants of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:27 Who was sent to work with the servants of Solomon?","answer":"Hiram's servants, seamen who knew the sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:28 They went to where, and acquired 420 talents of gold from there?","answer":"to Ophir"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:28 They went to Ophir, and acquired what from there?","answer":"420 talents of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 9:28 They went to Ophir, and acquired 420 talents of gold from there, and did what with it then?","answer":"brought it to King Solomon"}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        //
        
    ],
    "c10":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:1 Now when who heard of the fame of Solomon concerning the name of the Lord, she came to test him?","answer":"the queen of Sheba"},
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:1 Now when the queen of Sheba heard of what concerning the name of the Lord, she came to test him with hard questions?","answer":"of the fame of Solomon"},
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:1 Now when the queen of Sheba heard of the fame of Solomon concerning what, she came to test him with hard questions?","answer":"the name of the Lord"},
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:1 Now when the queen of Sheba heard of the fame of Solomon concerning the name of the Lord, she came to do what?","answer":"to test him with hard questions"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:1 Who came to test Solomon with hard questions?","answer":"the queen of Sheba"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:2 She came to where with a very great retinue, with camels that bore spices, very much gold, and precious stones?","answer":"to Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:2 She came to Jerusalem with what, with camels that bore spices, very much gold, and precious stones?","answer":"with a very great retinue"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:2 What 3 things did the queen of Sheba bring on the camels?","answer":"spices, very much gold, and precious stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:2 When the queen of Sheba came, what bore the spices?","answer":"camels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:2 \u2026 when she came to Solomon she spoke with him about what?","answer":"about all that was in her heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:3 So Solomon answered what?","answer":"all her questions"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:3 There was nothing so what for the king that he could not explain it to her?","answer":"so difficult"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:3 There was nothing so difficult for the king that he could not do what?","answer":"explain it to her"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:3 What was so difficult for the king that he could not explain it to her?","answer":"nothing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:4 And when who had seen all the wisdom of Solomon, the house that he had built, \u2026 (there was no more spirit in her)?","answer":"the queen of Sheba"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:4 And when the queen of Sheba had seen all the what, the house that he built, \u2026 (there was no more spirit in her)?","answer":"all the wisdom of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:4 And when the queen of Sheba had seen all the wisdom of Solomon, the what, \u2026 (there was no more spirit in her)?","answer":"the house that he had built"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:5 (And when the queen of Sheba had seen \u2026 ,) the food on his table, the seating of his servants, the service of his waiters and their apparel, his cupbearers, and his entryway by which he went up to the house of the Lord, there was what?","answer":"no more spirit in her"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:5 Name the 6 things listed in this verse which the queen of Sheba saw that left no more spirit in her.","answer":"the food on his table, the seating of his servants, the service of his waiters and their apparel, his cupbearers, and his entryway"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:5 (And when the queen of Sheba had seen \u2026 ,) ..., and his entryway by which he went where, there was no more spirit in her?","answer":"up to the house of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:6 It was a what which I heard in my own land about your words and your wisdom?","answer":"a true report"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:6 It was a true report which I heard where about your words and your wisdom?","answer":"in my own land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:6 It was a true report which I heard about your _____ and your _____.","answer":"words, wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 However I did not what until I came and saw with my own eyes?","answer":"I did not believe"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 2 pts. I did not believe until I did what with my own eyes?","answer":"came and saw"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 I did not believe until I came and saw with what?","answer":"with my own eyes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 I did not believe until I came and saw \u2026; and indeed the what was not told me?","answer":"the half"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 2 pts. Your what exceed the fame of which I heard?","answer":"your wisdom and prosperity"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:7 Your wisdom and prosperity exceed what?","answer":"the fame of which I heard"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:8 What are your men and these your servants?","answer":"happy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:8 Happy are your ____ and these your ____, who stand continually before you and hear your wisdom!","answer":"men, servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:8 Happy are your men and these your servants, who do what before you and hear your wisdom?","answer":"stand continually"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:8 Happy are your men and these your servants, who stand continually before you and do what?","answer":"and hear your wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 Blessed be whom, who delighted in you, setting you on the throne of Israel?","answer":"be the Lord your God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 Blessed be the Lord your God, who did what, and set you on the throne of Israel?","answer":"who delighted in you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 Blessed be the Lord your God, who delighted in you, and did what?","answer":"setting you on the throne of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 Because the Lord has done what, therefore He made you king?","answer":"has loved Israel forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 Because the Lord has loved Israel forever, therefore He did what, to do justice and righteousness?","answer":"made you king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:9 2 pts. Because the Lord has loved Israel forever, therefore He made you king, to do what?","answer":"justice and righteousness"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:10 Then she gave the king what three items?","answer":"120 talents of gold, spices in great quantity, and precious stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:10 There never again came such what as the queen of Sheba gave to King Solomon?","answer":"such quantity of spices"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:10 There never again came such quantity of spices as whom gave to King Solomon?","answer":"as the queen of Sheba gave"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:10 There never again came such quantity of spices as the queen of Sheba gave to whom?","answer":"to King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:11 Also, the what, which brought gold from Ophir, brought great quantities of almug wood and precious stones from Ophir?","answer":"the ships of Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:11 Also, the ships of Hiram, which brought what from Ophir, brought great quantities of almug wood and precious stones from Ophir?","answer":"gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:11 Also, the ships of Hiram, which brought gold from where, brought great quantities of almug wood and precious stones from Ophir?","answer":"from Ophir"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:11 2 pts. The ships of Hiram, which brought gold from Ophir, brought great quantities of what from Ophir?","answer":"of almug wood and precious stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:11 The ships of Hiram, ..., brought great quantities of almug wood and precious stones from where?","answer":"from Ophir"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 And the king made what of the almug wood for the house of the Lord and for the king's house, \u2026?","answer":"made steps"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 The king made steps of what for the house of the Lord and for the king's house \u2026?","answer":"of the almug wood"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 2 pts. The king made steps of the almug wood for what, also harps and stringed instruments for the singers?","answer":"for the house of the Lord and for the king's house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 2 pts. The king made steps of the almug wood for the house of the Lord and for the kings house, also what for the singers?","answer":"harps and stringed instruments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 The kings made steps of the almug wood \u2026, also harps and stringed instruments for whom?","answer":"for the singers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 There never again came such what, nor has the like been seen to this day?","answer":"almug wood"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:12 There never again came such almug wood, nor has the like been seen to when?","answer":"to this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:13 Now King Solomon gave whom all she desired, whatever she asked, besides what Solomon had given her according to the royal generosity?","answer":"the queen of Sheba"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:13 2 pts.  What had King Solomon given the queen of Sheba besides what he had given her according to the royal generosity?","answer":"all she desired, whatever she asked"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:13 King Solomon gave the queen of Sheba all she desired, whatever she asked, besides what Solomon had given her according to what?","answer":"according to the royal generosity"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:13 So she turned and went where, she and her servants?","answer":"to her own country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:13 2 pts.  So she turned and went to her own country -- who went?","answer":"she and her servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:14 The what that came to Solomon yearly was 666 talents of gold?","answer":"the weight of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:14 The weight of gold that came to Solomon how often was 666 talents of gold?","answer":"yearly"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:14 How much gold came to Solomon yearly?","answer":"666 talents of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:15 What 4 types of persons also contributed gold to Solomon?","answer":"from the traveling merchants, from the income of traders, from all the kings of Arabia, and from the governors of the country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:16 What did King Solomoon make of  hammered gold?","answer":"200 large shields"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:16 King Solomon made 200 shields of what?","answer":"of hammered gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:16 How much gold went into each of the large shields?","answer":"600 shekels of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:16 What did Solomon make using 600 shekels of gold for each?","answer":"large shields of hammered gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:17 He also made how many shields of hammered gold in this verse?","answer":"300 shields"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:17 He also made 300 shields of what?","answer":"of hammered gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:17 What did Solomon make out of 3 minas of gold?","answer":"shields"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:17 Where did the king put the shields?","answer":"in the House of the Forest of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:17 What did the king put into the House of the Forest of Lebanon?","answer":"200 large shields of hammered gold and 300 shields of hammered gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:18 Moreover the king made a what of ivory?","answer":"a great throne"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:18 Moreover the king made a great throne of what?","answer":"of ivory"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:18 The king made a great throne of ivory, and overlaid it with what?","answer":"with pure gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:18 What did the king make and overlay with pure gold?","answer":"a great throne of ivory"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 The throne had how many steps?","answer":"6 steps"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 What was the shape at the top of the throne at the back?","answer":"(it) was round"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 The throne \u2026 the top of the throne was round where?","answer":"at the back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 What was on either side of the place of the seat?","answer":"armrests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 There were armrests located where on the throne?","answer":"on either side of the place of the seat"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 What stood beside the armrests?","answer":"2 lions"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:19 Where did the 2 lions stand?","answer":"beside the armrests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:20 How many lions stood there, one on each side of the 6 steps?","answer":"12 lions"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:20 Twelve lions stood there, one on each side of what?","answer":"of the 6 steps"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:20 \u2026nothing like this had been made for whom?","answer":"for any other kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 All King Solomon's what were gold, and all the vessels of the House of the Forest of Lebanon were pure gold?","answer":"drinking vessels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 All King Solomon's drinking vessels were what?","answer":"were gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 All King Solomon's drinking vessels were gold, and all the what of the House of the Forest of Lebanan were pure gold?","answer":"all the vessels"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 All King's Solomon's drinking vessels were gold, and all the vessels of what were pure gold?","answer":"of the House of the Forest of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 All King's Solomon's drinking vessels were gold, and all the vessels of the House of the Forest of Lebanon were what?","answer":"were pure gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 What was pure gold?","answer":"all the vessels of the House of the Forest of Lebanon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 Not one was what, for this was accounted as nothing in the days of Solomon?","answer":"as silver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 Not one was silver, for this was what in the days of Solomon?","answer":"was accounted as nothing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:21 Not one was silver, for this was accounted as nothing when?","answer":"in the days of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 For the king had what at sea with the fleet of Hiram?","answer":"had merchant ships"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 For the king had merchant ships where with the fleet of Hiram?","answer":"at sea"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 For the king had merchant ships at sea with what?","answer":"with the fleet of Hiram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 How often did the ships come bringing gold, silver, ivory, apes, and monkeys?","answer":"once every 3 years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 5 pts.  Once every 3 years the merchant ships came bringing what items?","answer":"gold, silver, ivory, apes, and monkeys"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:22 Once every 3 years what came bringing gold, silver, ivory, apes, and monkeys?","answer":"the merchant ships"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:23 So King Solomon _____ all the _____ of the ____ in riches and wisdom.","answer":"surpassed, kings, earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:23 2 pts. So King Solomon surpassed all the kings of the earth in what?","answer":"in riches and wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:23 So who surpassed all the kings of the earth in riches and wisdom?","answer":"King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:24 Now all what sought the presence of Solomon to hear his wisdom?","answer":"all the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:24 Now all the earth sought the what of Solomon to hear his wisdom?","answer":"sought the presence of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:24 Now all the earth sought the presence of Solomon to do what?","answer":"to hear his wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:24 Now all the earth sought the presence of Solomon to hear his wisdom, which God had put where?","answer":"in his heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:24 What had God put in Solomon's heart?","answer":"wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:25 Each man brought what: articles of silver and gold, garments, armor, spices, horses, and mules, at a set rate year by year?","answer":"his present"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:25 7 pts.  What were the presents each man brought at a set rate year by year?","answer":"silver and gold, garments, armor, spices, horses, and mules"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:25 Each man brought his present ..., at a set rate, how often?","answer":"year by year"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:25 Each man brought his present, \u2026 at a what, year by year?","answer":"a set rate"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 2 pts. And Solomon gathered what; he had 1,400 chariots and 12,000 horsemen?","answer":"chariots and horsemen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 Solomon gathered chariots and horsemen; he had how many chariots?","answer":1400},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 Solomon gathered chariots and horsement; he had 1,400 what?","answer":"chariots"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 Solomon gathered chariots and horsemen; he had 1,400 chariots and how many horsemen?","answer":12000},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 Solomon gathered chariots and horsement; he had 1,400 chariots and 12,000 what?","answer":"horsement"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 2 pts.  Where did Solomon station his horsemen?","answer":"in the chariot cities and with the king at Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:26 2 pts.  What did Solomon station in the chariot cities and with the king at Jerusalem?","answer":"chariots and horsemen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:27 The king made what as common in Jerusalem as stones?","answer":"silver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:27 The king made silver what in Jerusalem?","answer":"as common as stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:27 The king \u2026 made what as abundant as the sycamores?","answer":"cedar trees"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:27 The king \u2026 made cedar trees as what which are in the lowland?","answer":"as abundant as the sycamores"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:27 The king \u2026 made cedar trees as abundant as the sycamores which are where?","answer":" in the lowland"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 Solomon had what imported from Egypt and Keveh?","answer":"horses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 2 pts. Solomon had horses imported from where?","answer":"Egypt and Kevehaa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 The king's merchants bought them where at the current price?","answer":"in Keveh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 Who bought horses in Keveh at the current price?","answer":"the king's merchants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 The king's merchants bought them in Keveh at what?","answer":"at the current price"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:28 What did the king's merchants buy in Keveh at the current price?","answer":"horses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 Now a what that was imported from Egypt cost 600 shekels of silver?","answer":"a chariot"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 Now a chariot that was imported from where cost 600 shekels of silver?","answer":"from Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 Now a chariot that was imported from Egypt cost how much?","answer":"600 shekels of silver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 How much did a horse imported from Egypt cost?","answer":"150 shekels of silver"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 A chariot that was imported from Egypt cost 600 shekels of silver, \u2026 thus, through whom, they exported them to all the kings of the Hittites and the kings of Syria?","answer":"throught their (the king's merchants) agents"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 What did the king's merchants do with the chariots and horses imported from Egypt?","answer":"they exported them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 2 pts.  To whom did the agents export the chariots and horses imported from Egypt?","answer":"to all the kings of the Hittites and the kings of  Syria"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 10:29 What did they export to all the kings of the Hittites and the kings of Syria?","answer":"chariots and horses imported from Egypt"}
       
        
        //{ "question" : "Fill in the blanks: “But we are not of those who ___ back to ___, but of those who ___ to the ___ of the ___.” (Heb10:39; 5 pts)" , "answer" : "Draw, perdition, believe, saving, soul"}
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
    ],
    "c11":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:1 But Solomon loved what, as well as the daughter of Pharaoh?","answer":"loved many foreign women"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:1 But Solomon loved many foreign women, as well as whom?","answer":"the daughter of Pharaoh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:1 5 pts.  But Solomon loved many foreign women -- what nationalities are listed?","answer":"Moabites, Ammonites, Edomites, Sidonians, and Hittites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 What had the Lord said the children of Israel were not to do?","answer":"\"You shall not intermarry with them, nor they with you.\""},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 (Solomon loved many foreign women \u2026) from the what of whom the lord had said \u2026 \"You shall not intermarry \u2026\"?","answer":"from the nations"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 Surely they will do what after their gods?","answer":"will turn away your hearts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 Surely they will turn away your hearts after what?","answer":"after their gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 Solomon did what to these in love?","answer":"clung to these"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:2 Solomon clung to these how?","answer":"in love"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 He had how many wives, princesses, and 300 concubines?","answer":"700 wives"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 2 pts. He had 700 what and 300 concubines?","answer":"wives, princesses"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 He had 700 wives, princesses and how many concubines?","answer":300},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 He had 700 wives, princesses and 300 what?","answer":"concubines"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 His wives did what (to Solomon)?","answer":"turned away his heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:3 Who turned away his (Solomon's) heart?","answer":"his wives"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 When was it that Solomon's wives turned away his heart after other gods?","answer":"when Solomon was old"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 When Solomon was old, his what turned his heart after other gods?","answer":"his wives"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 When Solomon was old, his wives did what after other gods?","answer":"turned his heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 When Solomon was old, his wives turned his heart after what?","answer":"other gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 \u2026 his heart was not what, as was the heart of his father David?","answer":"was not loyal to the Lord his God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:4 \u2026 his heart was not loyal to the Lord his God, as was the heart of whom?","answer":"of his father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:5 For Solomon went after what, and after Milcom the abomination of the Ammonites?","answer":"after Ashtoreth the goddess of the Sidonians"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:5 Ashtoreth was the goddess of whom?","answer":"of the Sidonians"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:5 For Solomon went after \u2026 Milcom, the abomination of whom?","answer":"of the Ammonites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:5 Solomon went after \u2026 what of the Ammonites?","answer":"Milcom the abomination"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:5 Who went after Ashtoreth \u2026 and after Milcom?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:6 Solomon did what in the sight of the Lord?","answer":"did evil"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:6 Solomon did evil in the sight of the Lord, and did not what, as did his father David?","answer":"fully follow the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:6 Solomon did evil in the sight of the Lord, and did not fully follow the Lord, as did whom?","answer":"his father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Then Solomon did what for Chemosh the abomination of Moab?","answer":"built a high place"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Then Solomon built a high place for what?","answer":"for Chemosh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Solomon built a high place for Chemosh the what?","answer":"the abomination of Moab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Where did Solomon build a high place for Chemosh?","answer":"on the hill that is east of Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Solomon built a high place for \u2026 what of the people of Ammon?","answer":"for Molech the abomination"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:7 Solomon built a high place for Molech the abomination of whom?","answer":"of the people of Ammon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:8 And he did what for all his foreign wives, who burned incense and sacrificed to their gods?","answer":"did likewise"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:8 And he did likewise for whom, who burned incense and sacrificed to their gods?","answer":"for all his foreign wives"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:8 2 pts. And he did likewise for all his foreign wives, who did what?","answer":"burned incense and sacrificed to their gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:9 So the Lord became what with Solomon, because his heart had turned from the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"became angry"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:9 So the Lord became angry with whom, because his heart had turned from the Lord God of Israel?","answer":"with Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:9 Why did the Lord became angry with Solomon?","answer":"because his heart had turned from the Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:9 The Lord became angry with Solomon, because his heart had turned from the Lord God of Israel, who had done what twice?","answer":"had appeared to him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:9 How many times had the Lord appeared to Solomon?","answer":"twice"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:10 (So the Lord \u2026 who appeared to him twice), and had done what concerning this thing, that he should not go after other gods?","answer":"had commanded him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:10 (So the Lord \u2026 who appeared to him twice), and had commanded him concerning this thing, that he should not what?","answer":"go after other gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:10 (So the Lord \u2026 who appeared to him twice), and had commanded him concerning this thing, that he should not go after other gods; but he did not what?","answer":"keep what the Lord had commanded"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:11 2 pts. Because you have done this, and have not kept what which I commanded you, \u2026 I will surely tear the kingdom away from you ...?","answer":"My covenant and My statutes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:11 Because you have not kept My covenant and My statutes which I commanded you, I will surely do what and give it to your servant?","answer":"tear the kingdom away from you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:11 Because you have not kept My covenant and My statutes which I commanded you, I will surely tear the kingdom away from you and do what?","answer":"and give it to your servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:11 What did the Lord say he would give to Solomon's servant?","answer":"the kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:12 I will not do it when, for the sake of your father David; I will tear it out of the hand of your son?","answer":"in your days"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:12 I will not do it in your days, for the sake of whom; I will tear it out of the hand of your son?","answer":"of your father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:12 I will not do it in your days, for the sake of your father David; I will tear it out of what?","answer":"out of the hand of your son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:12 What did the Lord say he would do to the kingdom when Solomon son rules?","answer":"tear it out of (his) hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 I will not tear away what; I will give one tribe to your son?","answer":"the whole kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 I will not tear away the whole kingdom; I will give how much to your son for the sake of My servant David?","answer":"1 tribe"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 I will not tear away the whole kingdom; I will give 1 tribe to whom for the sake of My servant David?","answer":"of your son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 2 pts. I will not tear away the whole kingdom; I will give 1 tribe to your son for the sake of whom?","answer":"of My servant David, and for the sake of Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 I will not tear away the whole kingdom; I will give 1 tribe to your son ..., and for the sake of Jerusalem which I have what?","answer":"which I have chosen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:13 What did the Lord say he had chosen?","answer":"Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:14 Now the Lord raised up what against Solomon?","answer":"an adversary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:14 The Lord raised up an advesary against Solomon, who was it?","answer":"Hadad the Edomite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:14 Hadad the Edomite was a descendant of whom?","answer":"of the king in Edom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:14 Who was the descendant of the king of Edom?","answer":"Hadad the Edomite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:15 When who was in Edoom, Joab the commander of the army had gone up to bury the slain, he killed every male in Edom?","answer":"David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:15 When David was where, Joab the commander of the army had gone up to bury the slain, after he killed every male?","answer":"in Edom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:15 When David was in Edom, who had gone up to bury the slain after he killed every male in Edom?","answer":"Joab the commander of the army"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:15 What had Joab the commander of the army gone to do when David was in Edom, after he killed every male?","answer":"to bury the slain"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:15 Joab the commander of the army had gone up (to Edom) to bury the slain, after he did what?","answer":"killed every male in Edom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:16   (when David was in Edom\u2026), how long did Joab remain there with all Israel until he had cut down every male?","answer":"for 6 months"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:16 (when David was in Edom \u2026), for 6 months who remained there with all Israel until he had cut down every male?","answer":"Joab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:16 (when David was in Edom \u2026), for 6 months Joab remained there with whom until he had cut down every male?","answer":"with all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:16 (when David was in Edom \u2026), for 6 months Joab remained there with all Israel until he had done what?","answer":"cut down every male in Edom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:17 (when David was in Edom \u2026), who fled to go to Egypt, he and certain Edomites of his father's servants with him?","answer":"Hadad"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:17 (when David was in Edom \u2026), Hadad fled to go where, he and certain Edomites of his father's servants with him?","answer":"to Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:17 (when David was in Edom \u2026), Hadad fled to go to Egypt, he and who else with him?","answer":"certain Edomites of his father's servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:17 What age was Hadad when he fled to Egypt?","answer":"(He was) still a little child"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:17 Who was still a little child when he fled to Egypt?","answer":"Hadad"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:18 Then they arose from _____ and came to _____; and they took men with them from _____ and came to _____.","answer":"Midian, Paran, Paran, Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:18 They arose from Midian and came to Paran; and they took what with them from Paran and came to Egypt?","answer":"took men with them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:18 \u2026 they took men with them from Paran and came to Egypt, to whom, who gave him a house etc.?","answer":"to Pharaoh king of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:18 3 pts.  What did Pharaoh king of Egypt give Hadad after he fled Edom?","answer":"a house, apportioned food for him, gave him land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:18 To whom did Pharaoh give a house, apportion food, and give land?","answer":"to Hadad"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:19 Hadad found what in the sight of Pharaoh?","answer":"great favor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:19 Hadad found great favor in the sight of whom?","answer":"of Pharaoh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:19 Hadad found great favor in the sight of Pharaoh, so that he gave him what?","answer":"as wife the sister of his own wife"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:19 What was the name of his (Pharaoh's) own wife?","answer":"Queen Tahpenes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:19 The sister of Queen Tahpenes was given to whom as wife?","answer":"to Hadad"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Then who bore him Genubath his son?","answer":"the sister of Tahpenes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Then the sister of Tahpenes bore him (Hadad) whom?","answer":"Genubath his son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Where did Tahpenes wean Genubath his (Hadad's) son?","answer":"in Pharaoh's house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Who was weaned in Pharaoh's house?","answer":"Genubath his (Hadad's) son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Who was in Pharaoh's household among the sons of Pharaoh?","answer":"Genubath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Genubath was where among the sons of Pharaoh?","answer":"in Pharaoh's household"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:20 Genubath was in Pharaoh's household among whom?","answer":"the sons of Pharaoh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:21 So when who heard in Egypt that David rested with his fathers, \u2026 Hadad said to Pharaoh, \"Let me depart \u2026\"?","answer":"Hadad"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:21 So when Hadad heard where that David rested with his fathers, \u2026 Hadad said to Pharaoh, \"Let me depart \u2026\"?","answer":"in Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:21 So when Hadad heard in Egypt what, \u2026 Hadad said to Pharaoh, \"Let me depart \u2026\"?","answer":"that David rested with his fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:21 When Hadad heard \u2026 that David rested with his fathers, \u2026 Hadad said to Pharaoh, \"Let me depart, that I may do what?","answer":"may go to my own country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:21 To whom did Hadad say, \"Let me depart, that I may go to my own country\"?","answer":"to Pharaoh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:22 \"But what have you _____ with me, that suddenly you _____ to go to your own _____?\"","answer":"lacked, seek, country"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:22 To the question of what he lacked Hadad answered, \"what, but do let me go anyway.\"","answer":"(I lacked) nothing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:22 Nothing, but do let me what?","answer":"go anyway"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 And God raised up another what against him, Rezon the son of Eliadah, who had fled from lord, Hadadezer king of Zobah?","answer":"another adversary"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 And God raised up another adversary against him, who?","answer":"Rezon the son of Eliadah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 What was the name of Rezon's father?","answer":"Eliadah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 Who had fled from his lord, Hadadezer king of Zobah?","answer":"Rezon the son of Eliadah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 Rezon the son of Eliadah had fled his lord, whom?","answer":"his lord, Hadadezer king of Zobah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 Who was the king of Zobah?","answer":"Hadadezer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:23 Hadadezer was king of what?","answer":"of Zobah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 So he gathered what to him and became captain over a band of raiders, when David killed those of Zobah?","answer":"gathered men"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 So he gathered men to him and became what, when David killed those of Zobah?","answer":"captain over a band of raiders"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 He gathered men to him and became captain over a band of raiders, when David did what?","answer":"killed those of Zobah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 Where did Rezon go and dwell?","answer":"to Damascus"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 They went to Damascus and dwelt there, and did what in Damascus?","answer":"reigned"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 Who went to Damascus and reigned there?","answer":"Rezon and his band of raiders"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:24 He gathered men to him and became captain over a band of raiders, when who killed those of Zobah?","answer":"David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 He was an what all the days of Solomon?","answer":"an adversary of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 He was an adversary of Israel for how long?","answer":"all the days of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 He was an adversary of Israel all the days of Solomon (besides what); and he abhorred Israel?","answer":"besides the trouble that Hadad caused"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 He was an advesary of Israel all the days of Solomon ...; and he what, and reigned over Syria?","answer":"he abhorred Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 He was an adversary of Israel all the days of Solomon ...; and he abhorred Israel, and did what?","answer":"and reigned over Syria"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:25 Who reigned over Syria?","answer":"Rezon the son of Eliadah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 Then whose servant, Jeroboam the son of Nebat, \u2026 also rebelled against the king?","answer":"Solomon's servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 Then Solomon's servant, who, an Ephraimite from Zereda, \u2026 also rebelled against the king?","answer":"Jeroboam the son of Nebat"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 Then Solomon's servant, Jeroboam the son of Nebat, a what from Zereda, \u2026 also rebelled against the king?","answer":"an Ephraimite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 Then Solomon's servant, Jeroboam the son of Nebat, an Ephraimite from where, \u2026 also rebelled against the king?","answer":"from Zereda"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 \u2026 Jeroboam the son of Nebat, an Ephraimite from Zereda, whose mother's name was what, \u2026 also rebelled against the king?","answer":"Zeruah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 What fact do we know from this verse about Zeruah the mother of Jeroboam?","answer":"(she was a) widow"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 Jeroboam the son of Nebat, \u2026 whose mother's name was Zeruah, a widow, also did what?","answer":"rebelled against the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 What was the name of Jeroboam's father?","answer":"Nebat"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:26 What was the name of Jeroboam's mother?","answer":"Zeruah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:27 This is what caused him to do what: Solomon had built the Millo and repaired the damages to the City of David his father.l","answer":"to rebel against the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:27 This is what caused him to rebel against the king: Solomon had built what and repaired the damages to the City of David?","answer":"the Millo"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:27 Solomon had built the Millo and done what to the City of David his father?","answer":"repaired the damages"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:27 Solomon had built the Millo and repaired the damages to what?","answer":"to the City of David his father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 The man Jeroboam was a what?","answer":"a mighty man of valor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Who was a mighty man of valor?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Solomon, seeing that the young man was what, made him the officer over all the labor force of the house of Joseph?","answer":"was industrious"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Solomon, seeing that who was industrious, made him the officer over all the labor force of the house of Joseph?","answer":"the young man (Jeroboam)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Solomon, seeing that the young man was industrious, made him the what of the house of Joseph?","answer":"the officer over all the labor force"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Solomon, seeing that the young man was industrious, made him the officer over all the labor force of what?","answer":"of the house of Joseph"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:28 Who was made officer over all the labor force of the house of Joseph?","answer":"the young man (Jeroboam)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 \u2026 when Jeroboam went out of where, the prophet Ahijah the Shilonite met him on the way?","answer":"out of Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 \u2026 when who went out of Jerusalem, the prophet Ahijah the Shilonite met him on the way?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 \u2026 when Jeroboam went out of Jerusalem, who met him on the way?","answer":"Ahijah the Shilonite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 Ahijah the Shilonite had clothed himself with what?","answer":"with a new garment"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 Ahijah the Shilonite had clothed himself with a new garment, and the two were what?","answer":"were alone in the field"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:29 2 pts.  Who was in the field?","answer":"Jeroboam and Ahijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:30 Then Ahijah did what and tore it into 12 pieces?","answer":"took hold of the new garment that was on him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:30 Then Ahijah took hold of the new garment that was on him and did what?","answer":"and tore it into 12 pieces"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:30 Who took hold of his new garment and tore it into 12 pieces?","answer":"Ahijah the Shilonite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:31 Take for yourself how much, for \u2026 \"I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon \u2026\"?","answer":"10 pieces"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:31 Take for yourself 10 pieces, for \u2026 I will do what out of the hand of Solomon and will give 10 tribes to you \u2026?","answer":"tear the kingdom out"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:31 Take for yourself 10 pieces, for \u2026 I will tear the kingdom out of what and will give 10 tribes to you \u2026?","answer":"out of the hand of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:31 Take for yourself 10 pieces, for \u2026 I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon and will do what \u2026?","answer":"give 10 tribes to you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:31 Who said, \"I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon and will give 10 tribes to you\"?  Be specific.  ","answer":"the Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:32 \u2026 but he (Solomon) shall have what for the sake of My servant David, and for the sake of Jerusalem, \u2026?","answer":"shall have 1 tribe"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:32 \u2026 but he (Solomon) shall have 1 tribe for the sake of whom, and for the sake of Jerusalem, \u2026?","answer":"My servant David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:32 \u2026 but he (Solomon) shall have 1 tribe for the sake of My servant David, and for the sake of what, which I have chosen out of all the tribes of Israel?","answer":"of Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:32 What have I (God) chosen out of all the tribes of Israel?","answer":"Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:32 \u2026 but he (Solomon) shall have 1 tribe for the sake of \u2026 Jerusalem, which I have chosen out of what?","answer":"out of all the tribes of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they have done what, and worshiped Ashtoreth \u2026, Chemosh \u2026, and Milcom \u2026,","answer":"have forsaken Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 3 pts. (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they have forsaken Me and worshiped what gods?","answer":"Ashtoreth, Chemosh, Milcom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Who was the goddess of the Sidonians?","answer":"Ashtoreth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Who was the god of the Moabites?","answer":"Chemosh"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Who was the god of the people of Ammon?","answer":"Milcom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Which people worshiped the goddess Ashtoreth?","answer":"the Sidonians"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Which people worshiped Chemosh?","answer":"the Moabites"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 Which people worshiped Milcom?","answer":"the people of Ammon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they have forsaken Me, and worshiped Ashtoreth \u2026, Chemosh \u2026, and Milcom \u2026, and have not done what to do what is right in My eyes?","answer":"walked in My ways"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they have ... worshiped Ashtoreth \u2026, Chemosh \u2026, and Milcom \u2026, and have not walked in My ways to do what?","answer":"to do what is right in My eyes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 2 pts. (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they \u2026 have not walked in My ways to do right in My eyes and keep what, as did his father David?","answer":"My statutes and My judgments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:33 2 pts. (I will tear the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon) \u2026 because they \u2026 have not walked in My ways to do right in My eyes and keep My statutes and My judgments, as did whom?","answer":"his father David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 I will not take what out of his hand, because I have made him ruler all the days of his life for the sake of My servant David?","answer":"the whole kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 I will not take the whole kingdom out of what, because I have made him ruler all the days of his life?","answer":"out of his hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 I will not take the whole kingdom out of his hand, because I have made him what all the days of his life?","answer":"made him ruler"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 I will not take the whole kingdom out of his hand, because I have made him ruler for how long?","answer":"all the days of his life"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 \u2026 I have made him ruler all the days of his life for the sake of whom?","answer":"of My servant David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 \u2026 I have made him ruler all the days of his life for the sake of My servant David, whom I what because he kept My commandments and My statutes?","answer":"whom I chose"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 2 pts. \u2026 I have made him ruler \u2026 for the sake of My servant David, whom I chose because he did what?","answer":"kept My commandments and My statutes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:34 Whom did I (God) choose because he kept My commandments and My statutes?","answer":"My servant David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:35 But I will take what out of his son's hand and give it to you?","answer":"the kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:35 But I will take the kingdom out of what and give it to you?","answer":"out of his son's hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:35 I will take the kingdom out of his son's hand and do what?","answer":"give it to you (Jeroboam)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:35 I will take the kingdom out of his son's hand and give it to you -- give what?","answer":"10 tribes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:35 I (God) will give 10 tribes to whom?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 And to whom will I give 1 tribe, that My servant David may always have a lamp before Me in Jerusalem?","answer":"to his (Solomon's) son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 And to his son I will give what, that My servant David may always have a lamp before Me in Jerusalem?","answer":"1 tribe"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 And to his son I will give one tribe, that who may always have a lamp before Me in Jerusalem?","answer":"My servant David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 And to his son I will give one tribe, that My servant David may always have what before Me in Jerusalem?","answer":"a lamp"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 And to his son I will give one tribe, that My servant David may always have a lamp before Me where?","answer":"in Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 To his son I will give 1 tribe, that My servant David may always have a lamp before Me in Jerusalem, the city which I have what?","answer":"have chosen for Myself"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 Why have I chosen Jerusalem for Myself?","answer":"to put My name there"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:36 What have I chosen for Myself, to put My name there?","answer":"the city of Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:37 So I will do what, and you shall reign over all your heart desires?","answer":"I will take you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:37 So I will take you, and you shall do what, and you shall be king over Israel?","answer":"reign over all your heart desires"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:37 So I will take you, and you shall reign over all your heart desires, and you shall be what?","answer":"be king over Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you do what, walk in My ways, and do what is right in My sight, to keep My statutes and My commandments, \u2026 then I will be with you \u2026?","answer":"if you heed all that I command you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you heed all that I command you, do what, and do what is right in My sight, to keep My statutes and My commandments, \u2026 then I will be with you \u2026?","answer":"walk in My ways"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you heed all that I command you, walk in My ways, and do what, to keep My statutes and My commandments, \u2026 then I will be with you \u2026?","answer":"do what is right in My sight"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you heed all that I command you, walk in My ways, and do what is right in My sight, to keep what, \u2026 then I will be with you \u2026?","answer":"keep My statutes and My commandments"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you \u2026 keep My statutes and My commandments, as whom did, then I will be with you?","answer":"as My servant David did"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you \u2026 keep My statutes and My commandments, as my servant David did, then I will what and build for you an enduring house, as I built for David?","answer":"will be with you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you \u2026 keep My statutes and My commandments, as my servant David did, then I will be with you and do what, as I built for David?","answer":"build for you an enduring house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you \u2026 keep My statutes and My commandments, as my servant David did, then I will be with you and build for you an enduring house, as I built for whom?","answer":"for David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 Then it shall be, if you \u2026 keep My statutes and My commandments, ..., then I will \u2026 build for you an enduring house, as I built for David, and will give what to you?","answer":"will give Israel to you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:38 To whom did God say He would be with him, would build for him an enduring house, and would give him Israel?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:39 I will do what to the descendants of David because of this?","answer":"will afflict"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:39 I will afflict whom because of this, but not forever?","answer":"the descendants of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:39 I will afflict the descendants of whom because of this?","answer":"of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:39 I will afflict the descendants of David because of this, but for how long?","answer":"but not forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Solomon therefore sought to do what?","answer":"sought to kill Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Who sought to kill Jeroboam?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Jeroboam rose and fled to where, to Shishak \u2026?","answer":"to Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Jeroboam rose and fled to Egypt, to whom, and was in Egypt until the death of Solomon?","answer":"Shishak king of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Jeroboam rose and fled to Egypt, and was in Egypt unil when?","answer":"until the death of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:40 Who rose and fled to Egypt, to Shishak king of Egypt?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:41 Now the rest of the _____ of Solomon, all that he ____, and his _____, are they not written in the book of the acts of Solomon?","answer":" acts, did, wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:41 Now the rest of the acts of Solomon, all that he did, and his wisdom, are they not written where?","answer":"in the book of the acts of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:41 What 3 things are written in the book of the acts of Solomon?","answer":"the rest of (his) acts, all that he did, and his wisdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:42 And the period that who reigned in Jerusalem over Israel was 40 years?","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:42 And the period that Solomon reigned where over Israel was 40 years?","answer":"in Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:42 The period that Solomon reigned over what was 40 years?","answer":"over Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:42 How long did Solomon reign in Jerusalem over Israel?","answer":"40 years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:43 Then Solomon did what, and was buried in the City of David his father?","answer":"rested with his fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:43 Then Solomon rested with his fathers, and was buried where?","answer":"in the City of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:43 Who reigned after Solomon died and was buried?","answer":"Rehoboam his son"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 11:43 Who rested with his fathers and was buried in the City of David?","answer":"Solomon"}
       
        
       
        
        
        //
        //{ "question" : "Who has provided something better for us? (Heb11:40)" , "answer" : "God"}
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        //{ "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],
    "c12":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:1 Who went to Shechem, for all Israel had gone to Shechem to make him king?","answer":"Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:1 Rehoboam went where, for all Israel had gone to Shechem to make him king?","answer":"to Shechem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:1 Rehoboam went to Shechem, for who had gone to Shechem to make him king?","answer":"all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:1 Rehoboam went to Shechem, for all Israel had gone where to make him king?","answer":"to Shechem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:1 Rehoboam went to Shechem, for all Israel had gone to Shechem to do what?","answer":"to make him king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:2 When who heard it (he was still in Egypt \u2026), (they sent and called him.)?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:2 When Jeroboam heard it (he was still where, for he had fled from the presence of King Solomon \u2026 ), (they sent and called him.)?","answer":"in Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:2 When Jeroboam heard it (he was still in Egypt, for he had fled from the what \u2026 ), (they sent and called him.)?","answer":"from the presence of King Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:2 When Jeroboam heard it (he was still in Egypt, for he had fled from the presence of King Solomon and had been doing what?","answer":"had been dwelling in Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:2 Who had been dwelling in Egypt as long as King Solomon lived?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:3 2 pts. Then who came and spoke to Rehoboam?","answer":"Jeroboam and the whole assembly of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:3 Jeroboam and the whole assembly of Israel came and spoke to whom?","answer":"to Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 Your what made our yoke heavy; now therefore, lighten the burdensome service of your father \u2026\"?","answer":"Your father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 Your father made what heavy; now therefore, lighten the burdensome service of your father \u2026?","answer":"our yoke"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 Your father made our yoke what; now therefore, lighten the burdensome service of your father?","answer":"heavy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 Your father made our yoke heavy; therefore, do what, and his heavy yoke which he put on us, and we will serve you?","answer":"lighten the burdensome service of your father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 ... lighten the burdensome service of your father, and his what, and we will serve you?","answer":"his heavy yoke"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:4 ... lighten the burdensome service of your father, and his heavy yoke, and we will do what?","answer":"will serve you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:5 Depart for how long, then come back to me?","answer":"for 3 days"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:5 Do what for 3 days, then come back to me?","answer":"Depart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:5 Depart for 3 days, then do what?","answer":"then come back to me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:5 And the people did what?","answer":"departed"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:6 King Rehoboam consulted whom who stood before his father Solomon while he still lived?","answer":"the elders"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:6 Who consulted the elders who stood before his father Solomon while he still lived?","answer":"King Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:6 King Rehoboam consulted the elders who stood before whom while he still lived?","answer":"before his father Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:6 King Rehoboam consulted the elders who stood before his father when?","answer":"while he still lived"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:6 How do you advise me to do what?","answer":"to answer these people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:7 If you will be a _____ to these people today, and _____ them, and _____ them, and speak good _____ to them, then they will be your servants forever.","answer":"servant, serve, answer, words"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:7 If you will be a servant to these people today, and \u2026speak good words to them, then they will be what?","answer":"will be your servants forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:7 2 pts. If you will be a servant to these people when, \u2026 then they will be your servants when?","answer":"today, forever"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:8 But he did what to the advice the elders had given him?","answer":"he rejected (it)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:8 He rejected what which the elders had given him?","answer":"the advice"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:8 He rejected the advice which who had given him?","answer":"the elders"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:8 He rejected the advice which the elders had given him, and did what?","answer":"consulted the young men"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:8 2 pts. After King Rehoboam rejected the advice of the elders, he consulted the young men who what?","answer":"had grown up with him, stood before him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:9 What what do you give? How should we answer this people who have spoken to me?","answer":"What advice do you give?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:9 The people asked King Rehoboam to do what?","answer":"\"Lighten the yoke which your father put on us.\""},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 My what shall be thicker than my father's waist!","answer":"my little finger"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 My little finger shall be what?","answer":"thicker than my father's waist"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 Then who spoke to him saying, \"Thus you should speak to this people who have spoken to you, \u2026\"","answer":"the young men who had grown up with him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 Thus you should speak to this people who have spoken to you, saying, 'Your what made our yoke heavy, but you make it lighter on us'?","answer":"Your father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 Thus you should speak to this people who have spoken to you, saying, 'Your father made what, but you make it lighter on us'?","answer":"made our yoke heavy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:10 Thus you should speak to this people who have spoken to you, saying, 'Your father made our yoke heavy, but you make it what'?","answer":"lighter on us"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 Whereas who put a heavy yoke on you, I will add to your yoke?","answer":"my father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 Whereas my father put a what on you, I will add to your yoke?","answer":"a heavy yoke on you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 Whereas my father put a heavy yoke on you, I will do what?","answer":"I will add to your yoke"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 My father did what, but I will chastise you with scourges?","answer":"chastised you with whips"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 My father chastised you with whips, but I will do what?","answer":"chastise you with scourges"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:11 Who chastised the people with whips?","answer":"my father (Solomon)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:12 2 pts. So who came to Rehoboam the 3rd day, as the king directed?","answer":"Jeroboam and all the people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:12 So Jeroboam and all the people came to whom the 3rd day?","answer":"to Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:12 So Jeroboam and all the people came to Rehoboam when?","answer":"the 3rd day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:12 So Jeroboam and all the people came to Rehoboam the 3rd day, as who had directed?","answer":"the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:13 Then the king answered the people how?","answer":"roughly"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:13 Then the king answered the people roughly, and did what with the advice the elders had given him?","answer":"rejected the advice"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:13 What did King Rehoboam reject?","answer":"the advice which the elders had given him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:14 He spoke to them according the advice of whom?","answer":"the young men"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:14 My father made your _____ heavy, but I will _____ to your yoke; my father ______ you with _____ but I will chastise you with _____.","answer":"yoke, add, chastised, whips, scourges"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 So the king did not what; for the turn of events was from the Lord?","answer":"did not listen to the people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 So the king did not listen to the people, for the what was of the Lord?","answer":"the turn of events"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 So the king did not listen to the people, for the turn of events was from whom?","answer":"from the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 \u2026 the turn of events was from the Lord, that He might do what?","answer":"fulfill His word"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 \u2026 the turn of events was from the Lord, that He might fulfill His word, which the Lord had spoken by whom to Jeroboam?","answer":"by Ahijah the Shilonite"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:15 \u2026the turn of events was from the Lord, \u2026. which was spoken by Ahijah the Shilonite to whom?","answer":"to Jeroboam the son of Nebat"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 Now when who saw that the king did not listen to them, the people answere the king?","answer":"when all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 Now when all Israel saw that the king did not what, the people answered the king?","answer":"did not listen to them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 What share have we in whom?","answer":"in David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 What ____ have we in David?","answer":"share"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 We have no what in the son of Jesse?","answer":"no inheritance"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 We have no inheritance in whom?","answer":"in the son of Jesse"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 To what, O Israel?","answer":"To your tents"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 Now, do what, O David?","answer":"see to your own house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:16 So Israel did what?","answer":"departed to their tents"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:17 But who reigned over the children of Israel who dwelt in the cities of Judah?","answer":"Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:17 But Rehoboam reigned over the children of Israel who dwelt where?","answer":"in the cities of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Then who sent Adoram, who was in charge of the revenue; but all Israel stoned him with stones and he died.","answer":"King Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Then King Rehoboam sent whom, who was in charge of the revenue, but all Israel stoned him?","answer":"Adoram"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Then King Rehoboam sent Adoram, who was in charge of what, but all Israel stoned him?","answer":"of the revenue"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Then King Rehoboam sent Adoram, who was in charge of the revenue, but all Israel did what, and he died?","answer":"stoned him with stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 \u2026 all Israel stoned him (Adoram) with stones, and he what?","answer":"he died"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Therefore King Rehoboam did what in haste to flee to Jerusalem?","answer":"mounted his chariot"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Therefore King Rehoboam mounted his chariot how to flee to Jerusalem?","answer":"in haste"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Therefore King Rehoboam mounted his chariot in haste to do what?","answer":"to flee to Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:18 Who mounted his chariot in haste to flee to Jerusalem?","answer":"King Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:19 So who has been in rebellion against the house of David to this day?","answer":"Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:19 So Israel has been what against the house of David to this day?","answer":"been in rebellion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:19 So Israel has been in rebellion against whom to this day?","answer":"against the house of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:19 So Israel has been in rebellion against the house of David to when?","answer":"to this day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 Now it came to pass that when who heard that Jeroboam had come back, they sent for him \u2026?","answer":"all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 Now it came to pass that when all Israel heard that who had come back, they sent for him \u2026?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 \u2026when all Israel heard that Jeroboam had come back, they _____ for him, and _____ him to the congregation, and made him _____ over all Israel.","answer":"sent, called, king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 \u2026 when all Israel heard that Jeroboam had come back, they sent for him and called him to the what?","answer":"to the congregation"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 \u2026 when all Israel heard that Jeroboam had come back, they sent for him and called him to the congregation, and made him what?","answer":"king over all Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 There were how many who followed the house of David, but the tribe of Judah only?","answer":"there were none"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 There were none who followed what, but the tribe of Judah only?","answer":"the house of  David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:20 There were none who followed the house of David, but who only?","answer":"the tribe of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 And when who came to Jerusalem, he assembled all the house of Judah with the tribe of Benjamin?","answer":"Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 And when Rehoboam came where, he assembled all the house of Judah with the tribe of Benjamin?","answer":"to Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 When Rehoboam came to Jerusalem, he did what with the house of Judah and the tribe of Benjamin?","answer":"assembled all (of them)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 2 pts. When Rehoboam came to Jerusalem, he assembled what?","answer":"the house of Judah with the tribe of Benjamin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 How many were there of the chosen men who were warriors?","answer":180000},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 Rehoboam .. assembled \u2026 180,000 chosen men who were what, to fight against the house of Israel?","answer":"who were warriors"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 Rehoboam \u2026 assembled \u2026 180,000 chosen men who were warriors, to do what?","answer":"to fight against the house of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 Why did Rehoboam choose 180,000 men who were warriors to fight against the house of Israel?","answer":"that he might restore the kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:21 Rehoboam wanted to fight against the house of Israel to restore the kingdom to whom?","answer":"to Rehoboam the son of Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:22 But what came to Shemaiah the man of God?","answer":"the word of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:22 But the word of God came to whom?","answer":"to Shemaiah the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:23 2 pts. Speak to whom, to all the house of Judah and Benjamin, and to the rest of the people?","answer":"to Rehoboam the son of Solomon, king of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:23 Speak to Rehoboam the son of Solomon, king of Judah, to whom, and to the rest of the people?","answer":"to all the house of Judah and Benjamin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:23 Speak to Rehoboam son of Solomon, king of Judah, to all the house of Judah and Benjamin, and to whom?","answer":"to the rest of the people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 2 pts. You shall not do what against your brethren the children of Israel.","answer":"go up nor fight"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 You shall not go up nor fight against whom?","answer":"your brethren the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 Let every man do what, for this thing is from Me.","answer":"return to his house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 Let every man return to his house, for this this is what?","answer":"is from Me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 T or F: They would not obey the word of the Lord, and continued on.","answer":"F -- they obeyed and turned back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 They obeyed the word of the Lord, and did what, according to the word of the Lord?","answer":"turned back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:24 They obeyed the word of the Lord, and turned back, according to what?","answer":"to the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 Then who built Shechem in the mountains of Ephraim?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 Then Jeroboam built what in the mountains of Ephraim?","answer":"Shechem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 Then Jeroboam built Shechem where?","answer":"in the mountains of Ephraim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 Where did Jeroboam dwell?","answer":"in Shechem in the mountains of Ephraim"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 He (Jeroboam) went out from there and built what else?","answer":"Penuel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:25 Who went out from there and built Penuel?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:26 Where did Jeroboam say, \"Now the kingdom may return to the house of David: \u2026\"?","answer":"in his heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:26 Who said in his heart, \"Now the kingdom may return to the house of David: \u2026\"?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:26 Now the what may return to the house of David?","answer":"the kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:26 Now the kingdom may return to what?","answer":"to the house of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 If these people go up to do what in the house of the Lord at Jerusalem, then the heart of this people will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam \u2026?","answer":"go up to offer sacrifices"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 2 pts. If these people go up to offer sacrifices where, then the heart of this people will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam \u2026?","answer":"in the house of the Lord at Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 If these people go up to offer sacrifices in the house of the Lord at Jerusalem, then the what will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam?","answer":"the heart of this people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 If these people go up to offer sacrifices in the house of the Lord at Jerusalem, then the heart of this people will do what, and they will kill me \u2026?","answer":"will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam king of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 If these people go up to offer sacrifices ... at Jerusalem, then the heart of this people will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam king of Judah, and they will do what and go back to Rehoboam king of Judah?","answer":"they will kill me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:27 If these people go up to offer sacrifices ... at Jerusalem, then the heart of this people will turn back to their lord, Rehoboam king of Judah, and they will kill me and do what?","answer":"go back to Rehoboam king of Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:28 Therefore the king did what, made 2 calves of gold, and said to the people, \"\u2026 Here are your gods \u2026\"?","answer":"asked advice"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:28 Therefore the king asked advice, made what, and said to the people, \" \u2026 Here are your gods \u2026\"?","answer":"2 calves of gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:28 It is too much for you to do what?","answer":"to go up to Jerusalem"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:28 It is too much for you to go up to Jerusalem. Here are your what, O Israel, which brought you up from the land of Egypt?","answer":"your gods"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:28 Here are your gods, O Israel, which did what?","answer":"which brought you up from the land of Egypt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:29 He set up one in _____, and the other he put in _____.","answer":"Bethel, Dan"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:29 What did Jeroboam set up in Bethel and in Dan?","answer":"golden calves"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:30 Now this thing became a what, for the people went to worship before the one as far as Dan?","answer":"a sin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:30 Now this thing became a sin, for the people went to do what before the one as far as Dan?","answer":"to worship"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:30 Now this thing became a sin, for the people went to before the one where?","answer":"as far as Dan"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:31 He made what, and made priests from every class of people, who were not of the sons of Levi?","answer":"shrines on the high places"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:31 He made shrines on the high places, and made what from every class of people, who were not of the sons of Levi?","answer":"priests"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:31 He made shrines on the high places, and made priests from what, who were not of the sons of Levi?","answer":"from every class of people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:31 He made shrines on the high places, and made priests from every class of people, who were not of what?","answer":"of the sons of Levi"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 Who ordained a feast on the 15th day of the 8th month?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 Jeroboam ordained a what on the 15th day of the 8th month?","answer":"a feast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 Jeroboam ordained a feast on what day and month?","answer":"the 15th day of the 8th month"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 Jeroboam ordained a feast \u2026, like the feast that was where?","answer":"in Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 Jeroboam ordained a feast \u2026, like the feast that was in Judah, and did what?","answer":"offered sacrifices on the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 (Jeroboam \u2026 offered sacrifices on the altar.) So he did at where, sacrificing to the calves that he had made?","answer":"at Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 (Jeroboam \u2026 offered sacrifices on the altar.) So he did at Bethel, sacrificing to what?","answer":"to the calves that he had made"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 And at where he installed the priests of the high places which he had made?","answer":"at Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:32 And at Bethel he installed the what which he had made?","answer":"the priests of the high places"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 So he made what on the altar which he had made at Bethel?","answer":"made offerings"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 So he made offerings on the what which he had made at Bethel?","answer":"on the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 So he made offerings on the altar which he had made where?","answer":"at Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 So he made offerings on the altar which he had made at Bethel on which day and which month, in the month which he had devised in his own heart?","answer":"on the 15th day of the 8th month"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 So he made offerings \u2026 on the 15th day of the 8th month, in the month which he had done what?","answer":"had devised in his own heart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 And he did what for the children of Israel, and offered sacrifices on the altar and burned incense?","answer":"ordained a feast"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 And he ordained a feast for whom, and offered sacrifices on the altar and burned incense?","answer":"for the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 12:33 2 pts. He ordained a feast for the children of Israel, and did what?","answer":"offered sacrifices on the altar and burned incense"}
   
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
    ],
    "c13":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:1 Who went from Judah to Bethel by the word of the Lord?","answer":"a man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:1 A man of God went from where to where by the word of the Lord?","answer":"from Judah to Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:1 A man of God went from Judah to Bethel by what, and Jeroboam stood by the altar to burn incense?","answer":"by the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:1 Who stood by the altar to burn incense?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:1 Where did Jeroboam stand to burn incense?","answer":"by the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 Then he cried out against what by the word of the Lord?","answer":"against the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 Then he cried out against the altar by what?","answer":"by the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 Behold, a what, Josiah by name, shall be born to the house of David?","answer":"a child"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 What was the name of the child who shall be born to the house of David?","answer":"Josiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 A child, Josiah by name, shall be born to what?","answer":"to the house of David"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on what he shall sacrifice the priests of the high places who burn incense on you?","answer":"on you (the altar)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on you he shall do what to the priests of the high places who burn incense on you?","answer":"he shall sacrifice (them)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on you he shall sacrifice whom, and men's bones shall be burned on you?","answer":"priests of the high places who burn incense on you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on you he shall sacrifice priests of the high places who do what, and men's bones shall be burned on you?","answer":"who burn incense on you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on you he shall sacrifice priests of the high places who burn incense on you, and what shall be burned on you?","answer":"men's bones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 \u2026 on you he shall sacrifice priests of the high places who burn incense on you, and men's bones shall be what?","answer":"shall be burned on you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:2 Who will sacrifice priests and burn men's bone on you (o altar)?","answer":"Josiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 He gave a what the same day, saying, \u2026?","answer":"a sign"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 He gave a sign when, saying, \"This is the sign \u2026\"","answer":"the same day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 This is the what which the Lord has spoken: \"Surely the altar shall split apart \u2026\"?","answer":"the sign"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 Surely the altar shall do what, and the ashes on it shall be poured out?","answer":"shall split apart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 Surely the altar shall split apart, and the what will be poured out?","answer":"the ashes on it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 Surely the altar shall split apart, and the ashes will do what?","answer":"will be poured out"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:3 Surely the what will split apart, and the ashes on it will be poured out?","answer":"the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 When \u2026 King Jeroboam heard the saying of whom, \u2026 he stretched out his hand from the altar?","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 When \u2026 who heard the saying of the man of God, \u2026 he stretched out his hand from the altar?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 When \u2026 Jeroboam heard the saying of the man of God, who did what in Bethel, he stretched out his hand \u2026?","answer":"cried out against the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 When \u2026 Jeroboam heard the saying of the man of God who cried out against the altar, he did what?","answer":"stretched out his hand from the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 What did Jeroboam say to do with the man of God?","answer":"\"Arrest him!\""},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 Then his hand, which he what, withered, so that he could not pull it back to himself?","answer":"which he stretched out toward him (the man of God)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 Then his hand, which he stretched out toward him, did what, so that he could not pull it back to himself?","answer":"withered"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:4 Then his hand, which he stretched out toward him, withered so that he could not do what?","answer":"could not pull it back to himself"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 What also was split apart, and the ashes poured out form the altar?","answer":"the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 The altar also was what, and the ashes poured out from the altar?","answer":"split apart"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 The altar also was split apart, and what else, according to the sign which the man of God had given by the word of God?","answer":"the ashes poured out from the altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 The altar also was split apart, and the ashes poured out from the altar, according to what which the man of God had given by the word of the Lord?","answer":"the sign"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 The altar also was split apart, and the ashes poured out from the altar, according to the sign which who had given by the word of the Lord?","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:5 The altar also was split apart, and the ashes poured out from the altar, according to the sign which the man of God had given by what?","answer":"by the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 Please do what, and pray for me, that my hand may be restored to me?","answer":"entreat the favor of the Lord your God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 Please entreat the favor of the Lord your God, and do what, that my hand may be restored to me?","answer":"pray for me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 Please entreat the favor of the Lord your God, and pray for me, that what may be restored to me?","answer":"my hand"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 Please entreat the favor of the Lord your God, and pray for me, that my hand may be what?","answer":"restored to me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 So who entreated the Lord, and the king's hand was restored to him?","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 So the man of God did what, and the king's hand was restored to him?","answer":"entreated the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:6 2 pts. So the man of God entreated the Lord, and what happened?","answer":"the king's hand was restored to him, and became as before"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:7 Who said, \"Come home with me and refresh yourself\"?","answer":"the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:7 Come do what and refresh yourself, and I will give you a reward?","answer":"come home with me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:7 Come home with me and do what, and I will give you a reward?","answer":"refresh yourself"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:7 Come home with me and refresh yourself, and I will do what?","answer":"give you a reward"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:8 If you were to give me what, I would not go in with you?","answer":"half your house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:8 If you were to give me half your house, I would not what; nor would I eat bread nor drink water in this place?","answer":"would not go in with you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:8 2 pts. If you were to give me half your house, I would not go in with you; nor would I do what in this place?","answer":"eat bread nor drink water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:8 Who told the king he would not go into the king's house, nor eat bread nor drink water in this place?","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:9 For so it was _____ me by the _____ of the _____, saying, 'You shall not eat bread, nor drink water, nor return by the same way you came.'","answer":"commanded, word, Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:9 You shall not do what, nor drink water, nor return by the same way you came?","answer":"eat bread"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:9 You shall not eat bread, nor what, nor return by the same way you came?","answer":"nor drink water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:9 You shall not eat bread, nor drink water, nor what?","answer":"nor return by the same way you came"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:10 So he went how and did not return by the way he came to Bethel?","answer":"he went another way"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:10 T or F:  So he went another way and returned by the way he came to Bethel.","answer":"F -- did not return by the way he came"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:10 So he went another way and did not return by the way he came to where?","answer":"to Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 Now a what dwelt in Bethel, and his sons came and told him all the works that the man of God had done that day in Bethel?","answer":"an old prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 An old prophet dwelt where, and his sons came and told him all the works that the man of God had done that day \u2026?","answer":"in Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 An old prophet dwelt in Bethel, and who came and told him all the works which the man of God had done that day?","answer":"his sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 An old prophet dwelt in Bethel, and his sons came and told him what?","answer":"all the works which the man of God had done that day"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 They also told whom the words which he (the man of God) had spoken to the king?","answer":"told their father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 They also told their father what which he (the man of God) had spoken to the king?","answer":"the words"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:11 They also told their father the words which he (the man of God) had what?","answer":"had spoken to the king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:12 What question did their father ask them?","answer":"\"Which way did he go?\""},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:12 For who had seen which way the man of God went who came from Judah?","answer":"his sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:12 For his sons had seen what?","answer":"which way the man of God went who came from Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:12 For his sons had seen which way the man of God went who came from where?","answer":"from Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:13 What command did the father give to his sons?","answer":"\"Saddle the donkey for me.\""},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:13 So they did what for him, and he rode on it?","answer":"saddled the donkey"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:13 So they saddled the donkey for him, and he did what?","answer":"he rode on it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:14 (he rode on it,) and went after what, and found him sitting under an oak?","answer":"after the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:14 (he rode on it,) and went after the man of God, and found him where?","answer":"sitting under an oak"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:14 Are you the what who came from Judah? Be specific.","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:14 Are you the man of God who came from where?","answer":"from Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:14 T or F:  Are you the man of God from Judah?  I am.","answer":"True"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:15 Do what with me and eat bread?","answer":"come home with me"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:15 Come home with me and do what?","answer":"eat bread"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:16 2 pts. I cannot what; neither can I eat bread nor drink water with you in this place?","answer":"cannot return with you nor go in with you"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:16 2 pts. I cannot return with you nor go in with you; neither can I do what in this place?","answer":"eat bread nor drink water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:17 For I have been told by what, 'You shall not eat bread nor drink water there, nor return by going the way you came.\"?","answer":"by the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:17 You shall not _____  _____ nor _____  _____, nor _____ by _____ the way you came.","answer":"eat bread, drink water, return, going"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 I too am a what as you are, and an angel wpoke to me by the word of the Lord?","answer":"a prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 I too am a prophet as you are, and what spoke to me by the word of the Lord?","answer":"an angel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 I too am a prophet as you are, and an angel spoke to me by what?","answer":"by the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 Bring him where, that he may eat bread and drink water?","answer":"back with you to your house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 2 pts. Bring him back with you to your house, that he may do what?","answer":"eat bread and drink water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:18 T or F:  The old prophet had a new revelation from God.","answer":"F:  he was lying to him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:19 So he did what, and ate bread in his house, and drank water?","answer":"went back with him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:19 So he went back with him, and did what in his house, and drank water?","answer":"ate bread"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:19 So he went back with him, and ate bread where, and drank water?","answer":"in his house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:19 So he went back with him, and ate bread in his house, and did what else?","answer":"drank water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:20 As they did what, the word of the Lord came to the prophet who had brought him back?","answer":"at the table"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:20 As they sat at the table, the what came to the prophet who had brought him back?","answer":"the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:20 As they sat at the table, the word of the Lord came to whom?","answer":"to the prophet who had brought him back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:21 He cried out to whom, saying, \"\u2026 Because you have disobeyed the word of the Lord, \u2026 (your corpse shall not come to the tomb of your fathers.\")?","answer":"to the man of God who came from Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:21 Because you have done what, and have not kept the commandment which the Lord your God commanded you, \u2026 (your corpse shall not come to the tomb of your fathers.)?","answer":"have disobeyed the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:21 Because you have disobeyed the word of the Lord, and have not what which the Lord your God commanded you, \u2026 (your corpse shall not come to the tomb of your fathers.)?","answer":"kept the commandment"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:22 You did what 3 things in the place of which the Lord said to you, \"Eat no bread and drink no water,\"?","answer":"you came back, ate bread, and drank water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:22 2 pts. The Lord said to you, what?","answer":"Eat no bread and drink no water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:22 (Because you \u2026 ) came back, ate bread, and drank water \u2026, your what shall not come to the tomb of your fathers?","answer":"your corpse"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:22 (Because you \u2026 ) came back, ate bread, and drank water \u2026, your corpse shall not come to where?","answer":"to the tomb of your fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:23 2 pts. After he had done what, he saddled the donkey for him, the prophet whom he had brought back.","answer":"had eaten bread and after he had drunk"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:23 After he had eaten bread and after he had drunk, he did what for him, the prophet whom he had brought back?","answer":"he saddled the donkey for him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:23 After he had eaten bread and after he had drunk, he saddled the donkey for him, for whom?","answer":"the prophet whom he had brought back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:24 When he was gone, a what met him on the road and killed him.","answer":"a lion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:24 When he was gone, a lion met him on the road and did what?","answer":"killed him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:24 \u2026 a lion met him on the road and killed him. And his what was thrown on the road and the donkey stood by it?","answer":"his corpse"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:24 \u2026 a lion met him on the road and killed him. And his corpse was thrown where and the donkey stood by it?","answer":"on the road"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:24 \u2026 a lion met him on the road and killed him. And his corpse was thrown on the road and what else?","answer":"and the donkey stood by it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:25 Who passed by and saw the corpse thrown on the road, and the lion standing by the corpse?","answer":"men passed by"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:25 Men passed by and saw what, and the lion standing by the corpse?","answer":"the corpse thrown on the road"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:25 Men passed by and saw the corpse thrown on the road, and what was beside it?","answer":"the lion (was standing by the corpse)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:25 They went and told it where?","answer":"in the city where the old prophet dwelt"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:25 Then went and did what in the city where the old prophet dwelt?","answer":"told it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 Who heard it and said, \"It is the man of God who was disobedient to the word of the Lord.\"?","answer":"the prophet who had brought him back from the way"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 When the prophet who had borught him back from the way heard it, he said, \"It is whom who was disobedient to the word of the Lord?","answer":"it is the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 When the prophet who had borught him back from the way heard it, he said, \"It is the man of God who was what?","answer":"disobedient to the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 The Lord did what, which has torn him and killed him?","answer":"has delivered him to the lion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 2 pts. The Lord has delivered him to the lion, which has done what?","answer":"torn him and killed him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:26 The Lord has delivered him to the lion, which has torn him and killed him, according to what?","answer":"to the word of the Lord which He spoke to him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:27 He spoke to whom, saying, \"Saddle the donkey for me.\"","answer":"to his sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:27 What did the old prophet ask his sons to do?","answer":"saddle the donkey for me."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:27 What did his sons do after he asked them to saddle the donkey?","answer":"So they saddled it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:28 Then he went and found what, and the donkey and the lion standing by the corpse?","answer":"his corpse thrown on the road"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:28 2 pts. Then he went and found his corpse thrown on the road, and the what standing by the corpse?","answer":"the donkey and the lion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:28 The donkey and the lion were standing by what?","answer":"by the corpse"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:28 2 pts. The lion had not done what?","answer":"eaten the corpse nor torn the donkey"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:28 What had not eaten the corpse nor torn the donkey?","answer":"the lion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 The prophet did what, laid it on the donkey, and brought it back?","answer":"took up the corpse of the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 The prophet took up the corpse of the man of God, and did what next, and brought it back?","answer":"laid it on the donkey"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 The prophet took up the corpse of the man of God, and laid it on the donkey, and did what then?","answer":"brought it back"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 So the old prophet came to where to mourn, and to bury him?","answer":"city"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 So who came to the city to mourn, and to bury him?","answer":"the old prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:29 2 pts. So the old prophet came to the city to do what?","answer":"to mourn and to bury him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:30 Then he laid what in his own tomb; and they mourned over him?","answer":"the corpse"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:30 Then he laid the corpse where, and they mourned over him?","answer":"in his own tomb"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:30 Then he laid the corpse in his own tomb, and they did what?","answer":"they mourned over him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:30 What did they say when the mourned over the man of God?","answer":"Alas, my brother!"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:31 When did he speak to his sons, saying, \"When I am dead, then bury me in the tomb where the man of God is buried \u2026\"?","answer":"after he had buried him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:31 After he had buried him, he spoke to whom, saying, \"When I am dead, then bury me in the tomb where the man of God is buried \u2026 ?","answer":"to his sons"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:31 When I am _____, then _____ me in the _____ where the man of God is buried; lay my _____ beside his _____.","answer":"dead, bury, tomb, bones, bones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:31 When I am dead, then bury me in the tomb where who is buried?","answer":"the man of God"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:32 The saying which he cried out by the word of the Lord against what, and against all the shrines on the high places \u2026, will surely come to pass?","answer":"against the altar in Bethel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:32 The saying which he cried out by the word of the Lord against the altar in Bethel, and against all the what which are in the cities of Samaria will surely come to pass?","answer":"all the shrines on the high places"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:32 The saying which he cried out by the word of the Lord against the altar in Bethel, and against all the shrines on the high places which are where will surely come to pass?","answer":"in the cities of Samaria"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:32 The saying which he cried out by the word of the Lord against the altar in Bethel, and against all the shrines on the high places ... will what?","answer":"will surely come to pass"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:32 What will surely come to pass?","answer":"the saying which he cried out by the the word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 When did Jeroboam not turn from his evil way, but again he made priests from every class of people for the high places?","answer":"after this event"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 After this event who did not turn from his evil way, but again he made priests from every class of people?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 After this event, Jeroboam did not what, but again he made priests from every class of people?","answer":"did not turn from his evil way"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 After this event, Jeroboam did not turn from his evil way, but again he did what for the high places?","answer":"made priests from every class of people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 \u2026 Jeroboam did not turn from his evil way, but again he made priests from every class of people for what?","answer":"for the high places"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 \u2026 Jeroboam ... again he made priests from every class of people for the high places; whoever wished, he did what, and he became one of the priests of the high places?","answer":"he consecrated him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 Who could be made a priest for the high places?","answer":"whoever wished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:33 \u2026 whoever wished, he consecrated him, and he (Jeroboam) became what?","answer":"one of the priests of the high places"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:34 This thing was the what of the house of Jeroboam, so as to exterminate and destroy it from the face of the earth?","answer":"the sin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:34 2 pts. This thing was the sin of the house of Jeroboam, so as to do what from the face of the earth?","answer":"to exterminate and destroy it"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:34 This thing was the sin of the house of Jeroboam, so as to exterminate and destroy it from what?","answer":"from the face of the earth"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:34 What was the sin that exterminated and destroyed the house of Jeroboam from the face of the earth?","answer":"he made priests from every class of people, whoever wished"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 13:34 This thing was the sin of what, so as to exterminate and destroy it from the face of the earth?","answer":"of the house of Jeroboam"}

        
        
        
        
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],"c14":[
        {"question":"According to 1 kings 14:1, When did Abijah the son of Jeroboam become sick?","answer":"At that time"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:1, At that time who became sick? 2pts.","answer":"Abijah the son of Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:1. Who was the son of Jeroboam that became sick?","answer":"Abijah"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:1, Abijah was the son of who?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:1, at that time what happened to Abijah the son of Jeroboam?","answer":"He became sick"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, fill in the blanks \u201cAnd Jeroboam said to his __, \u201cPlease __, and __ yourself, that they may not recognize you as the __ of Jeroboam, and go to ___. Indeed, Ahijah the __ is there, who told me that __ would be __ over this people.\u201d? 8 pts  ","answer":"wife, arise, disguise, wife, Shiloh, prophet, I, king"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, to whom did Jeroboam say \u201cplease arise, and disguise yourself, and they may not recognize you as the wife of jeroboam, and go to shiloh\u2026\u201d?","answer":"To his wife"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Jeroboam said to his wife to do what two things so that they wouldn\u2019t recognize her as the wife or Jeroboam? Be specific.","answer":"Please arise, and disguise yourself."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Why did Jeroboam ask his wife to please arise , and disguise herself?  1pt.","answer":"So that they may not recognize her as the wife of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Jeroboam said to his wife \u2018please arise, and disguise yourself so they may not recognize you as what? 1pt.","answer":"The wife of  Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Jeroboam said to his wife to \u2018please arise, and disguise yourself, that they may not recognize you as the wife of Jeroboam and then do what?","answer":"Go to Shiloh"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Jeroboam said to his wife to \u2018please arise\u2026 go to Shiloh and indeed who will be there? 1pt.","answer":"Ahijah the prophet"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, the wife should go to Shiloh and indeed who will be there?","answer":"Ahijah the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, What is the name of the prophet who would be at Shiloh?  1pt.","answer":"Ahijah"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, What did Ahijah the prophet tell him (Jeroboam)? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"That he would be king over this people"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Ahijah the prophet told Jeroboam that he would be king over who? 1pt.","answer":"This people"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:2, Ahijah the prophet told him (Jeroboam) he would be what over this people? 1pt.","answer":"King"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, fill in the blanks \u201calso take with you____, some __, and a jar of  __, and __ to him; he will tell __ what will become of the __\u2019? 6pts.","answer":"ten loaves, cakes, honey, go, you, child"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Jeroboam told his wife to take what? 3pts. Be specific.","answer":"10 loaves, some cakes, and a jar of honey."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Jeroboam told his wife to take how many loaves?","answer":"Ten"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Jeroboam told his wife to take how many cakes? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Some"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Apart from taking 10 loaves, some cakes what else should Jeroboam\u2019s wife take? 1pt.  ","answer":"A jar of honey"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Jeroboam\u2019s wife should also take with her ten loaves, some cakes, and a jar of honey and then do what? 1pt.  ","answer":"Go to him (the prophet)"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:3, Jeroboam\u2019s wife should also take with her 10 loves\u2026 and go to the prophet  and then, What will the prophet do? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"He will tell you what will become of the child."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, True or false, Jeroboam\u2019s wife did not do what Jeroboam said?","answer":"False (she did so)"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Jeroboam\u2019s wife did so; and then did what? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"she arose and went to Shiloh."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Jeroboam\u2019s wife did so; she arose and where did she go? 1pt.","answer":"To Shiloh."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Jeroboams wife did so; she did what and went to Shiloh?  1pt.","answer":"She arose"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Jeroboam\u2019s wife arose and went to Shiloh and came to where?  ","answer":"And came to the house of Ahijah."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Jeroboam\u2019s wife came to the house of who?","answer":"Ahijah"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, when Jeroboam\u2019s wife came to the house of Ahijah what happened ? 1pt.  Be specific.","answer":"Ahijah could not see, for his eyes were glazed by reason of his age"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, why could Ahijah not see? 1pt.  ","answer":"For his eyes were glazed by reason of his age."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:4, Ahijah could not do what because his eyes were glazed by reason of his age? 1pt.","answer":"Could not see."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, fill in the blanks \u201cnow the ___ had said to ___ \u2018here is the __ of ___, coming to __ you something about her __, for he is __. Thus and __ you shall say to __; for it will be, when she comes in, that she will __ to be ___ ___\u201d? 12pts.","answer":"Lord, Ahijah, wife, Jeroboam, ask, son, sick, thus, her, pretend, another, woman"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, the Lord said to who, \u2018here is the wife of jeroboam\u2026.? 1pt.","answer":"To Ahijah."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, Who said to Ahijah \u201chere is the wife of jeroboam\u2026?","answer":"The Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, when did the Lord say to Ahijah \u201chere is the wife of Jeroboam\u2026?  ","answer":"Now"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, Now the Lord had said to Ahijah here is who? 1pt.","answer":"The wife of Jeroboam.  "},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, The Lord said to Ahijah that here is the wife of who?","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, The Lord said to Ahijah that here is the wife of Jeroboam coming to do what? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Ask you something."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, Jeroboam\u2019s wife has come to ask Ahijah about what and why? 2pts.","answer":"About her son, for he is sick."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, who was sick?","answer":"Her son (Jeroboam\u2019s wife)."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, fill in the blanks \u201c\u2026__ and __ you shall say to her; for it will be, when she comes in, that she will pretend to be another woman.\u201d?  2pt.","answer":"thus, thus."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, thus and thus you shall do what to her (Jeroboam\u2019s wife)?","answer":"Shall say to her"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, for it will be when who comes in, that she will pretend to be another woman?","answer":"She"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, What will Jeroboam\u2019s wife do when she comes in? 1pt.  ","answer":"she will pretend to be another woman"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:5, For it will be, when she comes in, that she will pretend to be what? Be specific.","answer":"another woman"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, fill in the blanks \u201cAnd so it __, when __ heard the sound of her __ as she came through the __, he said \u2018come in, __ of Jeroboam. Why do you __ to be __ person? For I have been __ to you with __ news.\u201d? 9pts.","answer":"was, Ahijah, footsteps, door, wife, pretend, another, sent, bad."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, Who heard the sound of the footsteps of the wife of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Ahijah"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, What did Ahijah hear?","answer":"Heard the sound of her footsteps."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, whose footsteps did Ahijah hear?","answer":"Her (Jeroboam\u2019s wife)"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, What sound did Ahijah hear? 1pt.  ","answer":"Footsteps"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, When did Ahijah hear the sound of the footsteps of the wife of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"As she came through the door"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, What did Ahijah say when he heard the footsteps of Jeroboam\u2019s wife as she came through the door? 3pts. Be specific.","answer":"\u201ccome in, wife of Jeroboam. Why do you pretend to be another person? For I have been sent you with bad news."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, What did Ahijah say to Jeroboam\u2019s wife to do after she came through the door? 1pt.","answer":"Come in."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, How did Ahijah address the woman? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Wife of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, What did he (Ahijah) ask the wife of jeroboam?","answer":"Why do you pretend to be another person?"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, Who was  Jeroboam\u2019s wife pretending to be? 1pt.","answer":"Another person."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, what did Ahijah say after he asked Jeroboam\u2019s wife Why do you pretend to be another person?","answer":"For I have been sent to you with bad news."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:6, Ahijah had been sent to Jeroboam\u2019s wife with what? 1pt.    ","answer":"Bad news."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, fill in the blanks \u201c__, tell Jeroboam \u2018thus says the __ God of __:\u2019\u2019because I __ you from among the __, and made you __ over my people __\u201d? 7pts.","answer":"go, Lord, Israel, exalted people, ruler, Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, What should Jeroboam\u2019s wife go and tell Jeroboam? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"\u201cthus says the Lord god of Israel: \u201cbecause I exalted you from among the people, and made you ruler over My people Israel\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, Who says \u201cbecause I exalted you from among the people, and made you ruler over My people Israel? 1pt.  Be specific.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, What does the Lord God of Israel thus say that he made for Jeroboam? 2pts.  ","answer":"I exalted you from among the people, and made you ruler over my people Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, The Lord God of Israel says he has exalted Jeroboam from among who? 1pt.","answer":"Among the people."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, The Lord God of Israel has done what for Jeroboam from  among the people?  ","answer":"Has exalted him."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, The Lord God of Israel has exalted Jeroboam among the people, and has made him what? 1pt.","answer":"Ruler over My people Israel.  "},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:7, The Lord God of Israel has made Jeroboam ruler over who? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"My people Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, Fill in the blanks \u201cAnd tore the ___ away from the __ of David, and __ it to you; and __ you have not been as My ___ ___, who kept My __ and who __ me with all his heart, to do only what was __ in my __;\u201d? 10pts.","answer":"kingdom, house, gave, yet, servant, David, commandments, followed, right, eyes"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, apart from making you ruler over his (God) people Israel what else did he do to the kingdom?","answer":"Tore the kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, Away from whom did the Lord tore the kingdom?","answer":"Away from the house of David"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, To whom did the Lord give the kingdom after he tore it away from the house of David? 1pt.","answer":"To you (Jeroboam)"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, What did the Lord tore away from the house of David, and gave it to Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"The kingdom."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, What did the Lord say that His servant David do? 3pts.","answer":"Kept My commandments, followed Me with all his heart and do only what was right in My eyes."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, How did the Lord say that Jeroboam has not been? 1pt.","answer":"As My servant David."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, Who kept the Lord\u2019s commandments and followed the Lord with all his heart, to do only what was right in the Lord\u2019s eyes? 1pt.","answer":"David"},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, How did David follow the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"With all his heart."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, Why did David follow the Lord with all his heart?","answer":"To do only what was right in My eyes."},{"question":"According to 1 kings 14:8, What did the David do in the eyes of the Lord?","answer":"Only what was right."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, What has Jeroboam do more than all who were before him? 1pt.","answer":"More Evil"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, Jeroboam has done more evil than whom? 1pt.","answer":"All who were before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, What did  Jeroboam do that counted for him as more evil than all who were before him? 3pts.","answer":"He has gone and made for himself other gods and molded images to provoke the Lord (Me) to anger, and have cast the Lord behind your back."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, What has Jeroboam done for himself to provoke the Lord to anger? 2pts.","answer":"other gods and molded images."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, Why did Jeroboam make other gods and molded images for himself? 1pt.","answer":"To provoke Me (The Lord) to anger"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, Where did Jeroboam cast the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Behind his back."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, What had Jeroboam done with the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Cast him behind his back."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:9, fill in the blanks, \u201cBut you have done ___than all who where ___you, for you have ___and ___ for yourself ___and ____ to ___Me to ___, and have __Me ___your ____\u201d? 11pts.","answer":"More evil, before, gone, made, other gods, molded images, provoke, anger, cast, behind, back."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, What will the Lord bring on the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Disaster."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, On whom will the Lord bring disaster? 1pt.","answer":"On the house of Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, Who will the Lord cut off from Jeroboam? 3pts.","answer":"Every male in Israel, bond and free. 1pt. Every male in Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, From where will the Lord cut off every male in Israel, bond and free? 1pt.","answer":"From Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, Which type of male in Israel  will the Lord cut off from Jeroboam? 2pts.","answer":"Bond and free"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, What will the Lord do with the remnant of the house of Jeroboam? 2pts.","answer":"Take it away as one takes away refuse until it is all gone. 1pt. Take it away."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, What will the Lord take away as one takes away refuse until it is all gone? 1pt.","answer":"The remnant of the house of Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, Whose remnant will the Lord take away, as one takes away refuse until it is all gone? 1pt.","answer":"The remnant of the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, How will the Lord take away the remnant of the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"As one takes away refuse until it is all gone."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, Until when will the Lord take away the remnant of the house of Jeroboam, as one takes away refuse? 1pt.","answer":"Until it is all gone."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, What will the Lord do to the Jeroboam? 3pts.","answer":"Bring disaster on the house of Jeroboam, cut off from Jeroboam every male in Israel, bond and free, Take away the remnant of the house of Jeroboam, as one takes away refuse until it is all gone."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, The Lord will take away the remnant of the house of Jeroboam, as one takes away what until it is all gone? 1pt.","answer":"Refuse."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:10, fill in the blanks, \u201c_____\u201d I will bring ___on the ___of Jeroboam, and I will ___from Jeroboam ___in Israel, ____ and ___; I will ___the ___of the house of Jeroboam, as ___takes away ___until it is ____\u201d? 12pts.","answer":"Therefore behold!, disaster, house, cut off, every male, bond, free, take away, remnant, one, refuse, all gone."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, What shall eat whoever belongs to Jeroboam and dies in the city? 1pt.","answer":"The dogs."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, Who shall the dogs eat? 2pts.","answer":"Whoever belongs to Jeroboam and dies in the city."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, What will happen to whoever belongs to Jeroboam and dies in the city? 1pt.","answer":"The dogs shall eat him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, Who shall eat whoever dies in the field? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The birds of the air."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, Who shall the birds of the air eat? 1pt.","answer":"Whoever dies in the field."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, What will happen to whoever dies in the field? 1pt.","answer":"The birds of the air shall eat him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, The dogs and birds of the air shall eat whoever belongs to Jeroboam and dies where? 2pts.","answer":"in the city, in the field."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, Why shall the dogs and the birds of the air eat whoever belongs to Jeroboam and dies in the city and in the field? 1pt.","answer":"For the Lord has spoken."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:11, fill in the blanks, \u201cThe ___shall ___whoever belongs to ____and ___in the ___, and the ___shall ___whoever ___in the ___; for _____!\u201d 10pts.","answer":"Dogs, eat, Jeroboam, dies, city, birds of the air, eat, dies, field, the Lord has spoken."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:12, What did Ahijah say to the wife of Jeroboam to do? 2pts.","answer":"Arise therefore, go to your own house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:12, Where did Ahijah say to the wife of Jeroboam to go? 1pt.","answer":"To her own house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:12, What will happen as the feet of the wife of Jeroboam enter the city? 1pt.","answer":"The child shall die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:12, When did Ahijah say that the child shall die? 1pt.","answer":"When your feet enter the city. (The feet of the wife of Jeroboam)."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:12, What did Ahijah say to the wife of Jeroboam? 4pts.","answer":"Arise therefore, go to your own house. When your feet enter the city, the child shall die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, What shall all Israel do for the son of Jeroboam? 2pts.","answer":"Mourn for him and bury him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, Who shall mourn and bury the son of Jeroboam? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"All Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, Why shall all Israel mourn for the son of Jeroboam and bury him? 1pt.","answer":"For he is the only one of Jeroboam who shall come to the grave."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, Who is the only one of Jeroboam that shall come to the grave, because in him there is found something good toward the Lord God of Israel in the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"The son of Jeroboam (him)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, Why was the son of Jeroboam, the only one who shall come to the grave? 1pt.","answer":"Because in him there is found something good toward the Lord God of Israel in the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, What was there found in the son of Jeroboam toward the Lord God of Israel in the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Something good."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, How many of Jeroboam shall  come to the grave? 1pt.","answer":"He (His son) is the only one who shall come to the grave."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, In the house of Jeroboam in whom is found something good toward the Lord God of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"In him (Jeroboam\u2019s son)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:13, Towards whom was found something good in the son of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, What will the Lord do for Himself? 1pt.","answer":"Raise up a king over Israel who shall cut off the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, Who shall raise up for Himself a king over Israel who shall cut off the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, What will the Lord rise for Himself over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"a king"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, Where will the Lord rise for Himself a king? 1pt.","answer":"over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, What shall the king that the Lord will rise up for himself over Israel do? 1pt.","answer":"Cut off the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:14, fill in the blanks, \u201c_____ the Lord will ___for Himself a ____ over ____who shall ___the house of ____; ____. _____ _____!\u201d 9pts. Moreover, rise up, king, Israel, cut off, Jeroboam, this is the day, What?","answer":"Even now!"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, What will the Lord do to Israel as a reed is shaken in the water? 1pt.","answer":"Strike it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, Who will the Lord strike as a reed is shaken in the water? 1pt.","answer":"Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, Who will strike Israel, as a reed is shaken in the water? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, How will the Lord strike Israel? 1pt.","answer":"As a reed is shaken in the water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, For the Lord will shake Israel, as what is shaken in the water? 1pt.","answer":"A reed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, From where will the Lord uproot Israel? 1pt.","answer":"From this good land which He gave to their fathers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, What will the Lord do to Israel from this good land which He gave tot heir fathers? 1pt.","answer":"Uproot it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, To whom did the Lord give the good land form which Israel will be uprooted? 1pt.","answer":"To their fathers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, How was the land form where the Lord will uproot Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Good."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, What will the Lord do to Israel beyond the River? 1pt.","answer":"Scatter them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, Where will the Lord scatter Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Beyond the River."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, What will the Lord do to Israel because they have made their wooden images, provoking the Lord to anger? 3pts.","answer":"Will strike them, as a reed is shaken in the water. He will uproot Israel for this good land which He gave to their fathers, and will scatter them beyond the River."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, Why will the Lord strike Israel, as a reed is shaken in the water. Uproot Israel from this good land which He gave to their fathers, and will scatter them beyond the River? 2pts.","answer":"Because they have made their wooden images, provoking the Lord to anger.  "},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:15, What happened because the Israelites had made their wooden images? 1pt.","answer":"Provoking the Lord to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:16, Why will the Lord give Israel up? 1pt.","answer":"Because of the sins of Jeroboam. 3pts. Because of the sins of Jeroboam, who sinned and who made Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:16, What will the Lord do because of the sins of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Give Israel up."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:16, The Lord will give Israel up because of the sins of Jeroboam who did which things? 2pts.","answer":"Sinned and made Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:16, Because of the sins of whom will the Lord give Israel up? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:16, fill in the blanks, \u201cAnd He will give ____ up because of the ____of ______, who ____and who made ______ ____\u201d? 6pts.","answer":"Israel, sins, Jeroboam, sinned, Israel, sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, Who arose and departed and came to Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam\u2019s wife."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, What did Jeroboam\u2019s wife do? 3pts.","answer":"Arose and departed, and came to Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, To which city did Jeroboam\u2019s wife come? 1pt.","answer":"Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, When did the child die? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"When she came to the threshold."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, What happened when Jeroboam\u2019s wife came to the threshold of the house? 1pt.","answer":"The child died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:17, Where had Jeroboam\u2019s wife come when the child die? 1pt.","answer":"the threshold of the house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:18, What happened according to the word of the Lord which He spoke through His servant Ahijah the prophet? 2pts.","answer":"They buried him (the child) and all Israel mourned for him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:18, What did all Israel do for the son of Jeroboam when he died? 2pts.","answer":"buried him, mourned him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:18, Who buried and mourned for the son of Jeroboam according to the word of the Lord which He spoke through Hi servant Ahijah the prophet?  1pt.","answer":"All Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:18, The child died and they buried him; and all Israel mourned for him according to what? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord which He spoke through His servant Ahijah the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:18, Through whom had the Lord spoken the word of what would happen with Jeroboam\u2019s child? 1pt.","answer":"His servant Ahijah the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:19, What is indeed written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 3pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Jeroboam, how he made war and how he reigned."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:19, Where are written the rest of the acts of Jeroboam, hoe he made war and how he reigned? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, What was the period that Jeroboam reigned? 1pt.","answer":"Twenty-two years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, Who reigned for a period of twenty-two years? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, With whom did Jeroboam rested? 1pt.","answer":"With his fathers"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, Who reigned in place of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, What did Nadab do? 1pt.","answer":"Reigned in His (Jeroboam\u2019s) place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, What was the name of Jeroboam\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:20, What was the name of the Nadab\u2019s father? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Who reigned in Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Rehoboam the son of Solomon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Where did Rehoboam the son of Solomon reign? 1pt.","answer":"In Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Who was the son of Solomon who reigned in Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Rehoboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Who was the father of Rehoboam? 1pt.","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, How old was Rehoboam when he became king? 1pt.","answer":"Forty one years old."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, What happened when Rehoboam was forty-one years old? 1pt.","answer":"He became king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, How long did Rehoboam reign in Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"Seventeen years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Where did Rehoboam reigned seventeen years? 1pts.","answer":"In Jerusalem 3pts. In Jerusalem, the city which the Lord had chosen out of all the tribes of Israel, to put his name there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Which city had the Lord Chosen out of all the tribes of Israel, to put His name there? 1pt.","answer":"Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, From what had the Lord chosen Jerusalem to put His name there? 1pt.","answer":"Out of all the tribes of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Why had the Lord chosen Jerusalem out of all the tribes of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"To put his name there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, What was the name of Rehoboam\u2019s mother? 1pt.","answer":"Naamah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, Who was the son of Naamah? 1pt.","answer":"Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, What was the name of Rehoboam\u2019s parents? 2pts.","answer":"Salomon and Naamah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:21, What was Naamah\u2019s nationality? 1pt.","answer":"Ammomitess"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, What did Judah do in the sight of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Evil"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, Who did Evil in the sight of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, Where did Judah do evil? 1pt.","answer":"In the sight of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, To What did the people of Judah provoked the Lord with their sins which they committed? 1pt.","answer":"To Jealousy."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, How did the people of Judah provoked the Lord to Jealousy? 1","answer":"p. With the sins which they committed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, How where the sins that the people of Judah committed? 1pt.","answer":"More than all that their fathers had done."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:22, What was more than all that the fathers of Judah had done? 1pt.","answer":"Their sins."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:23, What did the fathers of Judah build for themselves on every hill and under every green tree? 3pts.","answer":"High places, sacred pillars, and wooden images."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:23, Where did the fathers of Judah build for themselves High places, sacred pillars, and wooden images? 2pts.","answer":"on every hill and under every green tree."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:23, What did the fathers of Judah do on every hill and under every green tree? 4pts.","answer":"Build for themselves high places, sacred pillars, and wooden images."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, What were there also in the land? 1pt.","answer":"Perverted people."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, Where were there perverted people? 1pt.","answer":"In the land."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, What did the perverted people in the land do? 1pt.","answer":"According to all the abominations of the nations which the Lord had cast out before the children of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, According to what did the perverted people in the land do? 1pt.","answer":"All the abominations of the nations which the Lord had cast out before the children of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, The perverted people in the land did according to the abominations of wh0? 1pt.","answer":"The nations which the Lord had cast out before the children of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:24, Before who had the Lord cast out the nations which the perverted people in the land did according to? 1pt.","answer":"The children of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, When did Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"In the fifth year of King Rehoboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, What happened in the fifth year of King Rehoboam? 1pt.","answer":"Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, In which year of King Rehoboam, Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"The fifth year."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, Who was the king of Egypt that came up against Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"Shishak."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, Shishak was king of which country? 1pt.","answer":"Egypt."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:25, Against who did Shishak king of Egypt came up in the fifth year of King Rehoboam? 1pt.","answer":"Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, what did king Shishak take away?  4pts.","answer":"The treasures of the house of the Lord, the treasures of the king\u2019s house, everything, all the gold shields which Salomon had made."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, Who took away the treasures of the house of the Lord and the treasures of the king\u2019s house and also all the gold shields which Solomon had made? 1pt.","answer":"He (King Shishak)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, Which treasures did King Shishak take? 2pts.","answer":"The treasures of the house of the Lord and the treasures of the king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, What did Shishak take from the house of the Lord and the king\u2019s house? 1pt.","answer":"The treasures."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, What did king Shishak took away also besides the treasures? 1pt.","answer":"All the gold shields which Solomon had made."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, Who had made all the gold shields that king Shishak took away? 1pt.","answer":"Solomon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, Of what material were made all the shields that king Shishak took away? 1pt.","answer":"gold."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:26, fill in the blanks, And he took away the treasures of the house of the Lord and the treasures of the king\u2019s house; he took away _____. He also took away all the gold shields which Solomon had made. 1pt.","answer":"Everything."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:27, Who made bronze shield in place of the gold shields which Shishak king of Egypt had taken? 1pt.","answer":"Rehoboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:27, What did Rehoboam make in place of the gold shields which Shishak king of Egypt had taken? 1pt.","answer":"Bronze shields."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:27, Into who\u2019s hands did Rehoboam committed the bronze shields that he made in place of the gold shields which Shishak king of Egypt had taken? 2pts.","answer":"The hands of the captains of the guard, who guarded the doorway of the king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:27, What did the captains of the guard, guard? 1pt.","answer":"the doorway of the king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:27, Which part of the king\u2019s house did the captains of the guard, guard? 1pt.","answer":"the doorway."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:28, When did the guards carry the bronze shields? 1pt.","answer":"Whenever the king entered the house of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:28, What happened whenever the king entered the house of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"The guard carried them (the bronze shields)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:28, What did the guards do after the king entered the house of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"They brought the bronze shields back into the guardroom."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:28, Who carried the shields whenever the king entered the hose of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"The guard."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:28, Where did the guard put the shields back after the king had entered the house of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"into the guardroom."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:29, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah? 2pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Rehoboam, and all that he did."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:29, Where are written the rest of the acts of Rehoboam, and all that he did? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:30, What was there between Rehoboam and Jeroboam all their days? 1pt.","answer":"War."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:30, Between who was there war all their days? 2pts.","answer":"Rehoboam and Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:30, For how long was there war between Rehoboam and Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"All their days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, Where was Rehoboam buried when he rested with his fathers? 1pt.","answer":"With his fathers  In the City of David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, Who was buried with his fathers in the city of David? 1pt.","answer":"Rehoboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, What was the name of Rehoboam\u2019s mother? 1pt.","answer":"Naamah, and Ammonitess."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, Who reigned in Rehoboams place? 1pt.","answer":"Abijam his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, Who was the son of Rehoboam? 1pt.","answer":"Abijam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 14:31, What did Abijam do in place if his father when he rested with his fathers? 1pt.","answer":"Reigned."}
        
      
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ],"c15":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, When did Abijam became king over Judah? 1pt.","answer":"In the eighteenth year of King Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, What Happened in the eighteenth year of King Jeroboam son of Nebat? 1pt.","answer":"Abijam became king over Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, Who became king over Judah in the eighteenth year of King Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Abijam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, Who was the son of Nebat? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, Who was the father of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Nebat"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:1, Abijam was king over which country? 1pt.","answer":"Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, How many years did Abijam reigned in Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"Three years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, Where did Abijam reigned three years? 1pt.","answer":"Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, What was the name of Abijam\u2019s mother? 1pt.","answer":"Maachah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, Who was Maacha\u2019s grandfather? 1pt.","answer":"Abishalom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, Who was Abishalom\u2019s granddaughter? 1pt.","answer":"Maachah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:2, What was Maachah to Abishalom? 1pt.","answer":"Granddaughter."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:3, How did Abijam walked? 1pt.","answer":"In all the sins of his father, which he had done before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:3, How was the heart of Abijam? 1pt.","answer":"Not loyal to the Lord his God."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:3, Abijam\u2019s heart was not loyal to the Lord his God as was whose heart? 1pt.","answer":"The heart of his father David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:4, Nevertheless why did the Lord God give him a lamp in Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"For David\u2019s sake."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:4, Nevertheless for David\u2019s sake What did the Lord his God do for him? 1pt.","answer":"Gave Him a lamp in Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:4, Nevertheless For David\u2019s sake what did the Lord his God gave him? 1pt.","answer":"A lamp in Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:4, For David\u2019s sake the Lord his God gave him a lamp in Jerusalem by doing what? 2pts.","answer":"By setting up his son after him and by establishing Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:5, Why did the Lord God gave David a lamp in Jerusalem? 2pts.","answer":"Because David did what was right in the eyes of the Lord, and had not turned aside from anything that He commanded him all the days of his life.  "},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:5, What did David do? 2pt.","answer":"What was right in the eyes of the Lord and had not turned aside from anything that He commanded him all the days of his life."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:5, From what David had not turned aside?","answer":"From anything that He (The Lord) commanded him all the days of his life."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:5, For how long David did not turned aside from anything that the Lord commanded him? 1pt.","answer":"All the days of his life."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:5, David did what was right in the eyes of the Lord, and had not turned aside from anything that He commanded him all the days of his life except in what matter?","answer":"In the matter of Uriah de Hittite."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:6, What was there between Rehoboam and Jereboam all the days of his life? 1pt.","answer":"War"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:6, Between whom was there war? 2pt.","answer":"Rehoboam and Jereboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:6, for how long was there war between Rehoboam and Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"All the days of his life."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:7, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Abijam and all that he did."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:7, Where were written the rest of the acts of Abijam, and all that he did? 1pt.","answer":"in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:7, Between whom was there war? 2pts.","answer":"Abijam and Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:7, What was there between Abijam and Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"War."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:8, Who rested with his fathers and was buried in the City of David? 1pt.","answer":"Abijam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:8, What happened to Abiham? 1pt.","answer":"rested with his fathers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:8, Where was Abijam buried?","answer":"In the City of David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:8, Who reigned in Abijam\u2019s place? 1pt.","answer":"Asa his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:9, When did Asa became king over Judah? 1pt.","answer":"In the twentieth year of Jeroboam king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:9, What happened in the twentieth year of Jeroboam king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Asa became king over Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:9, Who was king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:9, Who became king over Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:10, How long did Asa reign in Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"Forty one years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:10, Who reigned forty one years in Jerusalem? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:10, What was the name of Asa\u2019s grandmother? 1pt.","answer":"Maacha the granddaughter of Abishalom."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:10, Who was Maachah\u2019s grandson? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:10, Who was Maachah\u2019s grandfather? 1pt.","answer":"Abishalom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:11, What did Asa do? 1pt.","answer":"What was right in the eyes of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:11, Who did what was right in the eyes of the Lord, as did his father David? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:11, Asa did what was right in the eyes of the Lord as did who? 1pt.","answer":"His father David."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, What did Asa do? 2pts.","answer":"He banished the perverted persons from the land, and removed all the idols that his fathers made."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, Who banished the perverted persons from the land, and removed all the idols that his fathers had made? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, What did Asa do to the perverted persons from the land? 1pt.","answer":"Banished them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, Who did Asa banish from the land? 1pt.","answer":"The perverted persons."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, from where did Asa banish the perverted persons? 1pt.","answer":"From the land."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, What did Asa do with all the idols that his fathers made? 1pt.","answer":"Removed them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, What did Asa removed? 1pt.","answer":"All the idols that his fathers had made."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:12, Who had made all the idols that Asa removed? 1pt.","answer":"His fathers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, Who did Asa removed from being queen mother? 1pt.","answer":"Maachah his grandmother."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, From what did Asa removed Maachah his grandmother? 1pt.","answer":"From being a queen mother."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, Why did Asa removed Maachah his grandmother from being a queen mother? 1pt.","answer":"Because she had made an obscene image of Asherah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What have Maachah made? 1pt.","answer":"An obscene image of Asherah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, Who have made and obscene image of Asherah? 1pt.","answer":"Maachah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What was the position that Maachah had in the kingdom? 1pt.","answer":"Queen mother."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What did Asa do with the obscene image of Asherah that his grandmother had made? 2pts.","answer":"cut it down and burned it by the Brook Kidron."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What did Asa cut down and burned by the Brook Kidron? 1pt.","answer":"Her obscene image."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, Where did Asa burned the obscene image of Asherah that his grandmother had made? 1pt.","answer":"By the Brook Kidron."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, An image of whom had Maachah made? 1pt.","answer":"Asherah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What did Asa do with the image of Asherah by the Brook Kidron? 1pt.","answer":"burned it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, What is the name of the Brook by which Asa burned that obscene image of Asherah? 1pt.","answer":"Kidron."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:13, How is the image of Asherah described as? 1pt.","answer":"Obscene."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:14, What was not removed? 1pt.","answer":"The high places."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:14, What happened with the high places? 1pt.","answer":"Were not removed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:14, Nevertheless what happened with Asa\u2019s heart? 1pt.","answer":"Was loyal to the Lord all his days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:14, Whose heart was loyal to the Lord all his days? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:14, How long was Asa\u2019s heart loyal to the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"All his days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, Who brought into the house of the Lord the things which his father had dedicate, and the things which he himself had dedicated: silver and gold and utensils? 1pt.","answer":"Asa. (He)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, Where did Asa bring the silver and gold and utensils? 1pt.","answer":"Into the house of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, What did Asa bring into the house of the Lord which his father and he himself had dedicated? 3pts.","answer":"silver and gold and utensils."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, Who have dedicated the things which Asa brought into the house of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"His father, he himself."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, What did Asa bring into the house of the Lord? 5pts.","answer":"The things which his father had dedicated, and the things which he himself had dedicated: silver and gold and utensils."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:15, What have done Asa and his father with the things that Asa brought into the house of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Dedicated them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:16, What was there between Asa and Baasha king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"war."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:16, Between whom was there war all their days? 2pts.","answer":"Asa and Baasha king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:16, who was king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:16, For How long was there war between Asa and Baasha king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"All their days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:17, Who came up against Judah, and built Ramah, that he might let none go out or come in to Asa king of Judah?","answer":"Baasha king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:17, What did Baasha king of Israel do? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"Came up against Judah and built Ramah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:17, Against who did Baasha king of Israel came up? 1pt.","answer":"Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:17, Which city did Baasha build, that he might let none go out or come in to Asa king of Judah?","answer":"Ramah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:17, Why did Baasha king of Israel build Ramah? 2pts.","answer":"That he might let none go out or come in to Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who took all the silver and gold that was left in the treasuries of the house of the Lord and treasuries of the king\u2019s house, and delivered them into the hand of his servant? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, What did Asa take from the treasuries of the house of the Lord and the treasuries of the king\u2019s house? 2pts.","answer":"All the silver and gold"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18,  From where did Asa take all the silver and gold that was left? 2pts.","answer":"The treasuries of the house of the Lord and the treasuries of the king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, What did Asa do with the silver and gold that was left in the treasuries of the house of the Lord and the treasuries of the king\u2019s house? 1pt.","answer":"Delivered them into the hand of his servants."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Where did Asa delivered the silver and gold that was left in the treasuries of the house of the Lord and the treasuries of the king\u2019s house? 1pt.","answer":"into the hands of the his servants."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, To whom did king Asa send his servants? 1pt.","answer":"to Ben-Hadad king of Syria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who did  King Asa send to Ben-Hadad king of Syria? 1pt.","answer":"His servants"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who was the father of Ben-Hadad? 1pt.","answer":"Tabrimmon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who was the father of Tabrimmon? 1pt.","answer":"Hezion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who was the grandfather of Ben-Hadad? 1pt.","answer":"Hezion"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who was the son of Hezion? 1pt.","answer":"Tabrimmon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, what part of the geanealogy of Ben-Hadad is mentioned in this verse? 3pts.","answer":"Ben-Hadad the son of Tabrimmon, the son of Hezion."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Who was the king of Syria? 1pt.","answer":"Ben-Hadad."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:18, Where did Ben-Hadad dwell? 1pt.","answer":"In Damascus."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, What did Asa want between him and Ben-Hadad king of Syria? 1pt.","answer":"A treaty."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, Asa wanted a treaty between him and Ben-Hadad as there was with whom? 2pts.","answer":"Between my father (Asa\u2019s) and your father (Ben-Hadad\u2019s)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, What was there between Asa\u2019s father and Ben-Hadad\u2019s father? 1pt.","answer":"a treaty."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, What had Asa sent to Ben-Hadad king of Syria? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"A present of silver and gold."},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 15:19, Asa sent a present to Ben-Hadad king of Syria, what was the present? 2pts.","answer":"silver and gold."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, What did Asa want Ben-Hadad to do so that Baasha king of Israel will withdraw from him? 1pt.","answer":"Break his treaty with Baasha king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, With whom did Ben-Hadad have a treaty? 1pt.","answer":"with Baasha king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19, Why did Asa want Ben-Hadad to break his treaty with Baasha king of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"So that he will withdraw from him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:19 fill in the blanks, \u201c____a ____between you and me, as there was ____my ____and your ____. _____, I have sent you a ____of ____and ___. ___and ___ your _____with _____king of ____, so that he will ___from me.\u201d 15pts.","answer":"Let there be, treaty, between, father, father, see, present, silver, gold, come, break, treaty, Baasha, Israel, withdraw."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, True or false,  Ben-Hadad heeded King Asa and sent the captains of his armies against the cities of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"False (the cities of Israel)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, What did Ben-Hadad do because he heeded Asa? 1pt.","answer":"Sent the captains of his armies against the cities of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, What did Asa send against the cities of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"The captains of his Armies."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, Against whom did Ben-Hadad send the captains of his armies? 1pt.","answer":"the cities of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, why did Ben Hadad send the captains of his armies against the cities of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"He heeded King Asa."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:20, Which cities did Ben-Hadad attack? 5pts.","answer":"Ijon, Dan, Abel Beth Maacha, and all Chinneroth, with all the land of Nephtali."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:21, What happened when Baasha heard that Ben-Hadad sent the captains of his armies against the cities of Israel? 2pts.","answer":"He stopped building Ramah, and remained in Tirzah."},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 15:21, What did Baasha stop doing when heard that Ben-Hadad sent the captains of his armies against the cities of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Ramah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:21, Where did Baasha remained when he stopped building Ramah? 1pt.","answer":"In Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:21, Who stopped building Ramah and remained in Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, Who made a proclamation throughout all Judah? 1pt.","answer":"King Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, What did King Asa do throughout all Judah? 1pt.","answer":"A proclamation."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, Where did King Asa made a proclamation? 1pt.","answer":"Throughout all Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, Who was exempted of the proclamation that King Asa made? 1pt.","answer":"None was exempted."},{"question":" According to 1 Kings 15:22, True or false, King Asa made a proclamation throughout all Judah; some were exempted. 1pt.","answer":"False. (none was excepted.)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, What did they (the people of Judah) took away of Ramah? 2pts.","answer":"the stones and timber."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, For What had  Baasha used the stones and timber for? 1pt.","answer":"Building."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, What did King Asa do with the stones and timber that they took away of Ramah? 2pts.","answer":"Built Geba of Benjamin, and Mizpah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:22, Which cities did King Asa build with the stones and timber that they took away of Ramah? 2pts.","answer":"Geba of Benjamin, and Mizpah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the Kings of Judah? 4pts.","answer":"The rest of all the acts of Asa, all his might, all that he did, and the cities which he built."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, Where are written the rest of all the acts of Asa, all his might, all that he did, and the cities which he built? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, When was Asa diseased in his feet? 1pt.","answer":"In the time of his old age."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, What happened to Asa in the time of his old age? 1pt.","answer":"He was diseased in his feet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, Where was Asa diseased in the time of his old age? 1pt.","answer":"In his feet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:23, Who was diseased in his feet in the time of his old age? 1pt.","answer":"Asa."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:24, Where was Asa buried when he rested with his fathers? 2pts.","answer":"with his fathers in the City of David his father."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:24, Who reigned in Asa\u2019s place? 1pt.","answer":"Jehoshaphat his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:24, Who was the son of Asa? 1pt.","answer":"Jehoshaphat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:24, Who was the father of Jehoshaphat? 1pt.","answer":"Asa."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, Who became king over Israel in the second year of Asa king of Judah, and reigned over Israel two years? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab the son of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, Where did Nadab the son of Jeroboam became king? 1pt.","answer":"Over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, When did Nadab the son of Jeroboam became king over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"In the second year of Asa king Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, What happened in the second year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab the son of Jeroboam became king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, How long did Nadab the son of Jeroboam reigned over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"two years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:25, What did Nadab the son of Jeroboam do for a period of two years? 1pt.","answer":"Reigned over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:26, Who did evil int the sight of the Lord, and walked in the way of his father, and in his sin by which he had made Israel sin? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab (He)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:26, What did Nadab do in the sight of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Evil"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:26, How did Nadab walked? 2pts.","answer":"in the way of his father, and in his sin by which he had made Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Who conspired against Nadab king of Israel? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Baasha the son of Ahijah, of the house of Issachar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Who was the father of Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"Ahijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Who was the son of Ahijah? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Of which house was Baasha the son Ahijah? 1pt.","answer":"of the house of Issachar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, What did Baasha the son of Ahijah, of the house of Issachar do against Nadab? 1pt.","answer":"Conspired against him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Where did Baasha kill Nadab? 1pt.","answer":"At Gibbethon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, What happened at Gibbethon? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha killed Nadab there"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, To whom did Gibbethon belong? 1pt.","answer":"To the Philistines."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Which city belonged to the Philistines? 1pt.","answer":"Gibbethon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, What was Nadab and all Israel doing when Nadab was killed? 1pt.","answer":"Laid siege to Gibbethon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, When did Baasha kill Nadab? 2pts.","answer":"While Nadab and all Israel laid siege to Gibbethon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:27, Who laid siege to Gibbethon? 2pts.","answer":"Nadab and all Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:28, When did Baasha killed Nadab? 1pt.","answer":"In the third year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:28, What happened on the third year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha killed Nadab. (him)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:28, What did Baasha do in the third year of Asa king of Judah? 2pts.","answer":"Killed Nadab  and reigned his place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:28, Who reigned in Nadab\u2019s place? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, What did Baasha do when he became king? 1pt.","answer":"He killed all the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, When did Baasha killed all the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"when he became king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, true or false? And it was so, when he became king, that he killed some of the house of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"False (all)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, What did Baasha not leave to Jeroboam according to the word of the Lord which He had spoken by His servant Ahijah the Shilonite? 2pts.","answer":"Anyone that breathed, until he had destroyed him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, To whom did Baasha not leave anyone that breathed, until he had destroyed him? 1pt.","answer":"to Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, Until when did Baasha not leave to Jeroboam anyone that breathed? 1pt.","answer":"Until he had destroyed him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, According to what did Baasha destroyed Jeroboam? 2pts.","answer":"According to the word of the Lord which He had spoken by his servant Ahijah the Shilonite."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, Baasha did not leave to Jeroboam anyone that breathed, until he had destroyed him, according to the word of the Lord which He had spoken by whom? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"His servant Ahijah the Shilonite."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29, Who was a Shilonite? 1pt.","answer":"Ahijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:29-30, Why did Baasha destroy Jeroboam according to the word of the Lord which He had spoken by His servant Ahijah the Shilonite? 5pts.","answer":"Because of the sins of Jeroboam, which he had sinned and by which he had made Israel sin, because of his provocation with which he had provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:30, Who had provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:30, What did Jeroboam do with his provocation? 1pt.","answer":"Provoke the Lord God of Israel to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:30, With what did Jeroboam provoke the Lord God of Israel to anger? 1pt.","answer":"With provocation."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:30, Who did Jeroboam provoke to anger? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:30, To what did Jeroboam provoke the Lord God of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"To anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:31, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 2pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Nadab and all that he did."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:31, Where are written the rest of the acts of Nadab, and all that he did? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:31, Who\u2019s acts are written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Nadab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:32, What was there between Asa and Baasha king of Israel all their days? 1pt.","answer":"War"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:32, Between who was there war all their days? 2pts.","answer":"Asa and Baasha king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:32, For how long was there war between Asa and Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"All their days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:33, When did Baasha the son of Ahijah became king over all Israel in Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"In the third year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:33, What happened in the third year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha the son of Ahijah became king over all Israel in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:33, Where did Baasha the son of Ahijah became king in the third year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Over all Israel in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 15:33, How long did Baasha the son of Ahijah reign? 1pt.","answer":"Twenty four years."}
        
        
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c16":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, To whom did the word of the Lord come? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"To Jehu the son of Hanani."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, What came to Jehu the son of Hanani? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, Who was the son of Hanani? 1pt.","answer":"Jehu"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, Who was the father of Jehu? 1pt.","answer":"Hanani."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, Against whom did the word of the Lord come to Jehu the son of Hanani? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:1, What came against Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, Fill in the blanks, \u201c_____as I ___you ____and made you ___over _____, and you have ___in the way of ___, and have made ______ sin, to ___Me to ___with their ____,\u201d\u202611pts.","answer":"Inasmuch, lifted you our of the dust, ruler, My people Israel, walked, Jeroboam, My people Israel, provoke, anger, sins."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, From where did the Lord lifted Baasha up and made him ruler over His people Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Out of the dust."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, What did the Lord do to Baasha before making him ruler over His people Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Lifted him out of the dust."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, What did the Lord do to Baasha after lifing him out of the dust? 1pt.","answer":"Made him ruler over His people Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, Over whom did the Lord make Baasha Ruler? 1pt.","answer":"His people Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, How does the Lord refer to Israel? 1pt.","answer":"My People"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, What did the Lord say that Baasha have made to provoke Him to anger with their sins? 2pts.","answer":"Walked in the way of Jeroboam, and have made My people Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, In whose way did the Lord say that Baasha have walked? 1pt.","answer":"In the way of Jeroboam.  "},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, Who did the Lord say that Baasha have made sin? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"My people Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, What have Baasha made the Lord\u2019s people do? 1pt.","answer":"Sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, Why did Baasha have walked in the way of Jeroboam, and have made the Lord\u2019s people sin? 1pt.","answer":"to Provoke Me (the Lord) to anger with their sins."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, How did  Baasha and the people of Israel  provoke the Lord to anger? 1pt.","answer":"with their sins"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2, What was the result of the sins of Baasha and the people of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Provoke the Lord to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, fill in the blanks, \u201c\u2026_____ I will ____the ____of ____ and the _____of his ____, and I will make your _____like the ____ of _____ the son of ____\u201d. 10pts.","answer":"Surely, take away, posterity, Baasha, posterity, house, house, house, Jeroboam, Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:2-3, What will the Lord surely do to Baasha because had made His people Israel sin, to provoke Him to anger with their sins? 3pts.","answer":"Take away the posterity of Baasha and the posterity of his house, and I will make your house like the house of Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, What will the Lord take away from Baasha? 2pts.","answer":"His posterity and the posterity of his house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, What will the Lord take away from Baasha and of his house? 1pt.","answer":"The posterity."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, From whom and what will the Lord take away the posterity? 2pts.","answer":"Baasha, of his house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, How will the Lord make the house of Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"Like the house of Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, Who was the son of Nebat? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:3, Who was the father of Jeroboam? 1pt.","answer":"Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, fill in the blanks, \u201cThe ___shall ____ whoever ___to ___ and ____, and the ____shall ___whoever _____\u201d. 8pts.","answer":"dogs, eat, belongs, Baasha, dies in the city, birds of the air, eat, dies in the fields."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, Who shall eat whoever belongs to Baasha and dies in the city? 1pt.","answer":"The dogs."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, What shall the dogs do to whoever belongs to Baasha and dies in the city? 1pt.","answer":"Eat him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, Who shall the dogs eat? 2pts.","answer":"Whoever belongs to Baasha and dies in the city."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, Who shall eat whoever belongs to Baasha and dies in the fields? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The birds of the air."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:4, Who shall the birds of the air eat? 1pt.","answer":"Whoever dies in the fields."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:5, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 3pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Baasha, what he did, and his might."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:5, Where are written the rest of the acts of Baasha, what he did, and his might? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:6, Where was Baasha buried? 1pt.","answer":"In Tirzah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:6, Who was buried in Tirzah when he rested with his fathers? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:6, Who reigned in Baasha\u2019s place? 1pt.","answer":"Elah his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:6, What did Elah son of Baasha do in his place?","answer":"Reigned."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, What came by the prophet Jehu the son of Hanani against Baasha and his house?  1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, By whom did the word of the Lord came againsta Baasha and his house? 1pt.","answer":"By the prophet Jehu the son of Hanani"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, Who was the father of the prophet Jehu? 1pt.","answer":"Hanani"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, Who was the son of Hanani? 1pt.","answer":"Jehu"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, Against whom did the word of the Lord  come by the prophet Jehu the son of Hanani? 2pts.","answer":"Baasha and his house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, Why did the word of the Lord came by the prophet Jehu the son of Hanani against Baasha and his house? 3pts.","answer":"Because of all the evil that he did in the sight of the Lord in provoking Him to anger with the work of his hands, in being like the house of Jeroboam, and because he killed them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, How did Baasha and his house provoked the Lord to anger? 1pt.","answer":"With the work of his hands."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, What did Baasha and his house do with the work of his hands? 1pt.","answer":"Provoked Him (The Lord) to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:7, Baasha and his house were like which house? 1pt.","answer":"Like the house of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, When did Elah the son of Baasha become king over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"In the twenty-sixth year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, Who was king of Judah when Elah the son of Baasha became king over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Asa."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, What happened in the twenty-sixth year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Elah the son of Baasha became king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, Who became king over Israel in the twenty-sixth year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Elah the son of Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, Asa and Elah where kings over ____? 2pts.","answer":"Judah and Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, How long did Elah reigned in Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"Two years"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:8, Where did Elah the son of Baasha reign two years? 1pt.  ","answer":"In Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Who conspired against Elah? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"His servant Zimri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Who was Zimri? 2pts.","answer":"Elah\u2019s servant, commander of half his chariots"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Who was commander of half of Elah\u2019s chariots? 1pt.","answer":"his servant Zimri"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Zimri was commander of what? 1pt.","answer":"Half his (Elah\u2019s) chariots."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, What did Zimri do? 1pt.","answer":"Conspired against him (Elah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, When did Zimri conspired against Elah? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"As he was in Tirzah drinking himself drunk in the house of Arza steward of his house in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, What was Elah doing in Tirzah while Zimri, commander of half his chariots, conspired against him? 1pt.","answer":"Drinking himself drunk"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Where was Elah drinking himself drunk? 1pt.","answer":"In the house of Arza steward of his house in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Who was Arza? 1pt.","answer":"Steward of his house in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Who was the steward of Elah\u2019s house in Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"Arza."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, Where was Arza steward? 1pt.","answer":"Elah\u2019s house in Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:9, What position did Arza have in Elah\u2019s house in Tirzah.? 1pt.","answer":"Steward."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, Who went in and struck Elah, and killed him in the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah, and reigned in his place? 1pt.","answer":"Zimri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, What did Zimri do in the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah? 4pts.","answer":"Went in and struck him (ELah) and killed him and reigned in his place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, When did Zimri go in and struck Elah and killed him and reigned in his place? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"In the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, What happened on the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah? 4pts.","answer":"Zimri went in and struck him (Elah) and killed him and reigned in his place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, Who was king of Judah when Zimri went in and struck Elah and killed him? 1pt.","answer":"Asa"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, What did Zimri do in place of Elah? 1pt.","answer":"Reigned"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:10, What did Zimri do to Elah so he could reign in his place? 2pts.","answer":"Struck and killed him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, What came to pass, when Zimri began to reign, as soon as he was seated  on his throne? 1pt.","answer":"He killed all the household of Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, When did Zimri kill all the household of Baasha? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"When he began to reign, as soon as he was seated on his throne."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, Who did Zimri kill when he began to reign, as soon as he was setated on his throne? 1pt.","answer":"All the househould of Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, Who was left alive of the household of Baasha? 2pts.","answer":"He did not leave him one male, neither of his relatives nor of his friends."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, Zimri did not leave Baasha one male of whom? 2pts.","answer":"neither his relatives nor of his friends."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:11, What did Zimri not leave to Baasha neither of his relatives nor of his friends? 1pt.","answer":"One male."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:12, Who destroyed the household of Baasha according to the word of the Lord, which He spoke against Baasha by Jehu the prophet? 1pt.","answer":"Zimri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:12, What did Zimri do according to he word of the Lord, which He spoke against Baasha by Jehu the prophet? 1pt.","answer":"Destroyed the household of Baasha."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:12, According to what did Baasha destroy the household of Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"According to word of the Lord which He spoke against Baasha by Jehu the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:12, Against whom did the word of the Lord speak? 1pt.","answer":"Baasha"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:12, By whom did the word of the Lord speak against Baasha? 1pt.","answer":"Jehu the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:13, Why did Zimri destroy all the household of Baasha, according to the word of the Lord which He spoke against Baasja by Jehu the prophet? 2pts.","answer":"For all the sins of Baasha and the sins of Elah his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:13, How did Baasha and Elah his son provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger? 1pt.","answer":"with their idols."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:13, Who did Baasha and Elah his son provoked to anger with their idols? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1Kings 16:13, Who had sinned and had made Israel sin? 2pt.","answer":"Baasha and Elah his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:14, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 2pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Elah, and all that he did."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:14, Where are written the rest of the acts of Elah, and all that he did? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, When had Zimri reigned in Tirzah seven days. And the people were encamped against Gibbethon, which belonged to the Philistines? 1pt.","answer":"In the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, For how long had Zimri reigned in Tirzah when the people were encamped  against Gibbethon? 1pt.","answer":"Seven days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, What happened in the twenty-seventh year of Asa king of Judah, when Zimri had reigned in Tirzah seven days? 1pt.","answer":"The people were encamped against Gibbethon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, Who was encamped against Gibbethon in the twenty seventh year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"The people."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, Against whom were the people encamped in the twenty seventh year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Gibbethon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, To whom did Gibbethon belong? 1pt.","answer":"To the Philistines."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:15, How was the people against Gibbethon? 1pt.","answer":"Encamped."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, Who heard it said, \u201cZimri has conspired and also has killed the king.\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"The people who were encamped."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, What did the people who were encamped heard it say? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cZimri has conspired and also has  killed the king.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, What two things did people who were encamped heard that Zimri had done? 2pts.","answer":"Had conspired and also has killed the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, Who made Omri, the commander of the army, king over Israel that day in the camp? 1pt.","answer":"All Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, Who did all Israel make king over Israel that day in the camp? 2pts.","answer":"Omri, the commander of the army."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, What did all Israel do that day in the camp? 2pts.","answer":"Made Omri, the commander of the army, king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, When and where did all Israel made Omri, the commander of the Army, King over Israel? 2pts.","answer":"That day in the camp."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:16, What position did Omri? 1pt.","answer":"Commander of the army."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:17, Who went up from Gibbethon, and besieged Tirzah? 2pts.","answer":"Omri and all Israel with him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:17, What did Omri and all Israel with him do after Omri was made king over Israel? 2pts.","answer":"Went up from Gibbethon and they besieged Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:17, From which city did Omri and all Israel went up to besiege Tirzah? 1pt.","answer":"Gibbethon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:17, Which city did Omri and all Israel with him besiege? 1pt.","answer":"Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, What happened when Zimri saw that the city was taken? 3pts.","answer":"He went into the citadel of the king\u2019s house and burned the king\u2019s house down upon himself with fire, and died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, When did Zimri go into the citadel of the king\u2019s house and burned the king\u2019s house down upon himself with fire, and died? 1pt.","answer":"When he sat that the city was taken."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, Where did Zimri go when he saw that the city was taken? 1pt.","answer":"Into the citadel of the king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, What did Zimri burned when he saw that the city was taken? 1pt.","answer":"The king\u2019s house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, What happened when Zimri burned the king\u2019s house down upon himself with fire? 1pt.","answer":"He died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, How did Zimri die? 1pt.","answer":"He burned the king\u2019s house down upon himself with fire, and died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:18, Who died because he turned the king\u2019s house down upon himself on fire? 1pt.","answer":"Zimri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:19, Why did Zimri died burned with fire? 3pts.","answer":"Because of the sins which he had committed in doing evil in the sight of the Lord, in walking in the way of Jeroboam, and in his sin which he had committed to make Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:19, In whose way did Zimri walk? 1pt.","answer":"In the way of Jeroboam."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:19, What did Zimri do in the sight of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Evil."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:19, Which sins had Zimri committed? 3pts.","answer":"Doing evil in the sight of the Lord, walking in the way of Jeroboam, to make Israel sin."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:20, What is written in the book of the Chronicles of the kings of Israel? 2pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Zimri, and the treason he committed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:20, Where are written the rest of the acts of Zimri, and the treason he committed? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the Chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, What happened to the people of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Were divided into two parts: half of the people followed Tibni the son of Ginath, to make him king, and half followed Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, How were the people of Israel divided? 1pt.","answer":"Into two parts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Who was divided into two parts: half following Tibni and half following Omri to make him king? 1pt.","answer":"The people of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, why was the people of Israel divided into two parts? 2pts.","answer":"Half of the people followed Tibni the son of Ginath, to make him king, and half followed Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, How many people of the people of Israel follow Tibni and Omri to make them king? 1pt.","answer":"Half and Half"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Who did the people of Israel follow to make him king? 2pts.","answer":"Tibni the son of Ginath and Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Who was the son of Ginath? 1pt.","answer":"Tibni."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Who was Tibni\u2019s father? 1pt.","answer":"Gianath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Half the people followed Tibni, the son of Ginath to make him king, who did the other half follow? 1pt.","answer":"Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:21, Half the people followed Omri to make him king, who did the other half follow? 1pt.","answer":"Tibni the son of Ginath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:22, Who prevailed over the people who followed Tibni the son of Ginath? 1pt.","answer":"The people who followed Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:22, What did the people who follow Omri do? 1pt.","answer":"Prevailed over the people who followed Tibni the son of Ginath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:22, What happened when the people who followed Omri prevailed over the people who followed Tibni the son of Ginath? 2pts.","answer":"Tibni Died and Omri reigned."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:23, When did Omri become king over Israel? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"In the thirty-first year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:23, What happened in the thirty-first year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Omri became king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:23, How long did Omri reign? 1pt.","answer":"Twelve years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:23, How long did Omri reign in Tirzah?","answer":"Six years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:23, Where did Omri reign six years? 1pt.","answer":"In Tirzah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, What did Omri buy from Shemer for two talents of silver? 1pt.","answer":"The hill of Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, From who did Omri buy the hill of Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"From Shemer"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, For how much did Omri buy the hill of Samaria from Shemer? 1pt.","answer":"for two talents of silver."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, What did Omri do on the hill of Samaria after he bought it? 1pt.","answer":"He built on the hill."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, What did Omri called the name of Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"The city which he built."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, What name did Omri called the city which he built? 1pt.","answer":"Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, Why did Omri called the name of the city which he built, Samaria? 2pts.","answer":"After the name of Shemer, owner of the hill."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, Who was Shemer? 1pt.","answer":"The owner of the hill"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:24, What did Shemer own? 1pt.","answer":"The hill (of Samaria)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:25, What did Omri do in the eyes  of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Evil."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:25, What did Omri do? 2pts.","answer":"Evil in the eyes of the Lord, and worse that all who were before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:25, Who did evil in the eyes of the Lord, and did worse than all who were before him? 1pt.","answer":"Omri"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:25, Omri did worse than whom? 1pt.","answer":"all who were before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:26, How did Omri do worse than all who were before him? 3pts.","answer":"For he walked in all the ways of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, and in his sin by which he had made Israel sin, provoking the Lord God of Israel to anger with their idols. ."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:26, How did Omri provoke the Lord God of Israel to anger? 1pt.","answer":"With their idols."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:26, What did Omri cause with the idols? 1pt.","answer":"Provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:26, Who did Omri provoke to anger with their idols? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:26, Where did Omri walk? 1pt.","answer":"In all the ways of Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:27, What is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel? 2pts.","answer":"The rest of the acts of Omri which he did, and the might that he showed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:27, Where are written the rest of the acts of Omri which he did, and the might that he showed? 1pt.","answer":"In the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:28, Where was Omri buried when he rested with his fathers? 1pt.","answer":"In Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:28, Who reigned in Omri\u2019s place? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab his son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:28, Who was Omri\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:28, Who was Ahab\u2019s father? 1pt.","answer":"Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:29, When did Ahab the son of Omri became king over Israel? 1pt.","answer":"In the thirty-eight year of Asa king of Judah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:29, What happened in the thirty-eight year of Asa king of Judah? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab the son of Omri became king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:29, Who became king over Israel in the thirty-eight year of Asa king of Judah? 1","answer":"p. Ahab the son of Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:29, Where did Ahab the son of Omri reigned over Israel twenty-two years? 1pt.  ","answer":"in Samaria"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:29, How long did Ahab the son of Omri reign over Israel in Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"Twenty-two years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:30, Who did Evil in the sight of the Lord, more than all who were before him? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab the son of Omri."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:30, What did Ahab the son of Omri do in the sight of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Evil."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:30, Ahab the son of Omri did evil in the sight of the Lord, more than whom? 1pt.","answer":"All who were before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:30, Where did Ahab the son of Omri do evil? 1pt.","answer":"in the sight of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, What came to pass as though it had been a trivial thing for Ahab  to walk in the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat? 2pts.","answer":"He took as wife Jezabwl the daughter of Ethbaal, king of the Sidonians, and he went and served Baal and worshiped him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, What things did Ahab do after he took as wife Jezabel the daughter of Ethbaal, king of the Sidonians? 3pts.","answer":"He went and served Baal and worshiped him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, Who did Ahab served and worshiped when he took as wife Jezabel the daughter of Ethbaal, king of the Sidonians? 1pt.","answer":"Baal."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, What was a trivial thing for Ahab to do? 1pt.","answer":"Walk in the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, What kind of thing was it for Ahab to walk in the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat? 1pt.","answer":"A trivial thing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, It was a trivial thing for Ahab to walk in whose sins? 1pt.","answer":"Jeroboam the son of Nebat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, Who did Ahab take as wife? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Jezabel the daughter of Ethbaal, king of the Sidonians."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, Who was the father of Jezabel? 1pt.","answer":"Ethbaal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, Who was the daughter of Ethbaal?1pt.","answer":"Jezabel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, who was Ethbaal? 1pt.","answer":"King of the Sidonians."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:31, Who was the king of the Sidonians? 1pt.","answer":"Ethbaal."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, What did Ahab do in the temple of Baal, which he had built in Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"He set up an altar for Baal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, What did Ahab set up for Baal in the temple of Baal, which he had built in Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"An altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, For whom did Ahab build an altar? 1pt.","answer":"For Baal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, Where did Ahab build an altar for Baal? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"In the temple of Baal. 2pts. In the temple of Baal, which he had built in Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, What did Ahab build for Baal in Samaria? 1pt.","answer":"A temple"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:32, Where did Ahab build a temple of Baal? 1pt.","answer":"In Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:33, What did Ahab make? 1pt.","answer":"a wooden image."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:33, What did Ahab do more than all the kings of Israel who were before him? 1pt.","answer":"More to provoke the Lord God of Israel to anger."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:33, Ahab did more to provoke the Lord God of Israel to anger than whom? 1pt.","answer":"all the kings of Israel who were before him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, What happened in the days of Ahab? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Hiel of Bethel built Jericho."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who built Jericho?","answer":"Hiel of Bethel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Where was Hiel from? 1pt.","answer":"Bethel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, When did Hiel of Bethel build Jericho? 1pt.","answer":"In his days (Ahab\u2019s)."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, With whom did Hiel lay the foundation of Jericho? 1pt.","answer":"With Abiram his firstborn."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who was Hiel\u2019s firstborn? 1pt.","answer":"Abiram."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, What did Hiel do with Abiram his firstborn? 1pt","answer":"\/ Laid its (Jericho\u2019s) foundation."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, What did Hiel do with his youngest son Segub? 1pt.","answer":"Set up its gates."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, With whom did Hiel set up the gates of Jericho? 1pt.","answer":"His youngest son Segub."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who was the youngest son of Hiel? 1pt.","answer":"Segub."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who were the sons of Hiel? 2pts.","answer":"Abiram and Segub."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, True or false, Segub was Hiel\u2019s firstborn?","answer":"False (his youngest)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, How did Hiel laid the foundations of Jericho and set up its gates? 1pt","answer":"\/ According to word of the Lord, Which He had spoken through Joshua the son of Nun."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Through whom did the Lord spoke his word? 1pt.","answer":"Joshua the son of Nun."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who was the son of Nun? 1pt.","answer":"Joshua."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 16:34, Who was Joshua\u2019s father? 1pt.","answer":"Nun."}
        
        
       
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c17":[

        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, Who said to Ahab, \u201cAs the Lord God of Israel lives, before whom I stand, ther shall not be dew nor rain these years, except at my word.\u201d? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"Elijah the Tishbite, of the inhabitants of Gilead."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, Where was Elijah the Tishbite from? 1pt.","answer":"of the inhabitants of Gilead."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, To whom did Elijah the Tishbite say there shal not be dew nor rain these years, except at my word? 1pt.","answer":"To Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, What shall not be these years, except at Elijah\u2019s word? 2pts.","answer":"dew nor rain"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, Elijah said that there shall not be dew nor rain these years except what? 1pt.","answer":"Except at my word"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, When shall not be dew nor rain except at Elijah\u2019s word? 1pt.","answer":"These years."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:1, fill in the blanks, And Elijah the ____, of the Inhabitants of ___, said to Ahab, \u201c_______, _______, there shall not be ___nor ___these years, ___at my ____\u201d.","answer":"Tishbite, Gilead, As the Lord God of Israel lives, before whom I stand, dew, rain, except, word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, What did the word of the Lord say to Elijah the Tishbite? 3pts.","answer":"Get away from here and turn eastward, and hide by the Brook Cherith, which flows into the Jordan."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, Where did the word of the Lord say to Elijah to turn? 1pt.","answer":"Eastward"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, What did the word of the Lord say Elijah to do by the Brook of Cherith? 1pt.","answer":"Hide"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, Where did the word of the Lord say Elijah to hide? 1pt.","answer":"By the Brook of Cherith."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, Where does the Brook  Cherith flow? 1pt.","answer":"into the Jordan"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, Which Brook flows into the Jordan? 1pt.","answer":"The Brook Cherith."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:3, fill in the blanks, \u201c_____from here and turn ____, and ___by the ______, which ___into the _____\u201d.","answer":"Get away, eastward, hide, Brook Cherith, flows, Jordan."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:4, From where shall Elijah drink? 1pt.","answer":"From the brook."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:4, How was Elijah going to be fed while he was hiding by the Brook Cherith? 1pt.","answer":"I (The Lord) have commanded the ravens to feed him there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:4, Who did the Lord commanded to feed Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"The ravens"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:4, fill in the blanks, \u201cAnd it will be that you shall ____ from the ____, and I have ___the ___to ____you ____.\u201d 6pts.  ","answer":"drink, brook, commanded, ravens, feed, there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:5, What did Elijah do after the word of the Lord came to him saying that he had to get away and hide by the Brook Cherith? 2pts.","answer":"He went and did according to word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:5, What proof is there that Elijah did according to word of the Lord? 2pts.","answer":"For he went and stayed by the Brook Cherith, which flows into the Jordan."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:5, Where did Elijah stayed according to the word of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"By the Brook Cherith"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:5, Where does the Brook Cherith flow? 1pt.","answer":"into the Jordan."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:6, What did the ravens bring Elijah, morning and evening? 2pts.","answer":"Bread and meat."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:6, Who brought Elijah bread and meat in the morning and in the evening? 1pt.","answer":"the ravens"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:6, When did the ravens brought bread and meat to Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"in the morning and in the evening."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:6, From where did Elijah drank? 1pt.","answer":"from the brook."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:6, How was Elijah fed while hiding by the brook of Cherith? 3pts.","answer":"The ravens brough him bread and meat in the morning, and bread and meat in the evening; and he drank from the brook."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:7, What happened after a while because there had been no rain in the land? 1pt.","answer":"The brook dried up"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:7, Why did the brook dry up? 1pt.","answer":"Because there had been no rain on the land."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:7, When did the brook dried up, because there had been no rain in the land? 1pt.","answer":"After a while."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:8, What came to Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:8, To whom did the word of the Lord come? 1pt.","answer":"to him  (Elijah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, What did the word of the Lord say to Elijah? 4pts.","answer":"Arise, go to Zarephath, which belongs to Sidon, and dwell there. See, I have commanded a widow there to provide for you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, Where did the Lord say Elijah to go and dwell there? 1pt.","answer":"Zarephath, which belongs to Sidon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, Where did Zarephath belong? 1pt.  ","answer":"To Sidon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, Which place belongs to Sidon? 1pt.","answer":"Zarephath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, What did the word of the Lord say to Elijah to do in Zarephath? 1pt.","answer":"Dwell there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, Who have the Lord commanded in Zarephath to provide to Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"a widow"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, What did the Lord do for Elijah  when He send him to Zarephath? 1pt.","answer":"He have commanded a widow there to provide for him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, For what had the Lord commanded a widow in Zarephath? 1pt.","answer":"To provide for him (Elijah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:9, fill in the blanks, \u201c_____, ____to ____, which ____to ____, and ____there. ____, I have _____a ____there to _____for you.\u201d 10pts. Arise, go, Zarephat, belongs, Sidon, dwell, see, commanded, widow, provide.","answer":"Arise, go, Zarephat, belongs, Sidon, dwell, see, commanded, widow, provide."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, What did Elijah do after the word of the Lord say to him to arise and go to Zarephath? 2pt.","answer":"He arose and went to Zarephath."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, What did Elijah saw when he came to the gate of the city? 1pt.","answer":"a widow was there gathering sticks."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, When  did Elijah saw that indeed there was a widow gathering sticks? 1pt.","answer":"when he came to the gate of the city."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, Where did Elijah come when he saw that indeed a widow was there gathering sticks? 1pt.","answer":"To the gate of the city."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, What was the widow doing when Elijah came to the gate of the city? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Gathering sticks."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, What did Elijah ask the widow to bring him? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"A little water in a cup."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, What did Elijah say to widow? 2pts.","answer":"\u201cPlease bring me a little water in a cup, that I may drink\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, fill in the blanks, \u201c____bring me a ____in a ___, that I may ___\u201d. 4pts.","answer":"Please, little water, cup, drink."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:11, What did Elijah ask the widow as she was going to get the water in a cup? 1pt.","answer":"Please bring me a morsel of bread in your hand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:11, When did Elijah asked the widow to bring him a morsel of bread in her hand? 1pt.","answer":"as she was going to get the water (it)."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:11, What did Elijah ask the widow to bring  him in her hand? 1pt.","answer":"a morsel of bread."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:11, fill in the blanks, And as se was going to get it, he called to her and said, \u201c____ ___me a ____in your ___\u201d. 4pts.","answer":"Please, bring, morsel of bread, hand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:10, 11, What did Elijah as the widow to bring him? 2pts. Be specific.","answer":"A little water in a cup, a morsel of bread in her hand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, Who said, \u201cAs the Lord your God lives, I do not have bread, only a handful of flour in a vin, and a little oil in a jar? 1pt.","answer":"She (the widow)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What did the widow not have? 1pt.","answer":"Bread."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What did the widow have? 2pts.","answer":"a handful of flour in a bin, and little oil in a jar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, How much flour did the widow have? 1pt.","answer":"A handful."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, Where did the widow had the flour? 1pt.","answer":"in a bin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What did the widow have in a bin? 1pt.","answer":"a handful of flour"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What did the widow have in a jar? 1pt.","answer":"a little oil"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, Where did the widow had a little oil? 1 pt.","answer":"In a jar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, How much oil did the widow have? 1pt.","answer":"a little"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What was the widow gathering? 1pt.","answer":"a couple of sticks"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, Why was the widow gathering a couple of sticks? 4pts.","answer":"That she may go in and prepare (the bread) for herself and her son, that they may eat it, and die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, For whom was the widow preparing the bread? 2pts Be specific.","answer":"For herself and her son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, What did the widow say it will happen after she prepare the bread for herself and her son? 2pts.","answer":"they may eat it, and die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:12, fill in the blanks, So she said, \u201c_____, I do not have ___, only a ____of ____in a ___, and a ____in a ___, and ___, I am ____a ____that I may go ___and ___it for ___and ___, that we may ___it, and ___.\u201d 16pts.","answer":"As the Lord your God lives, bread, handful, flour, bin, little oil, jar, see, gathering, couple of sticks, in, prepare, myself, my son, eat, die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:13, What did Elijah say the widow to do first from the flour and bring it to him? 1pt.","answer":"a small cake."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:13, What did Elijah say to the widow to do? 1pt.","answer":"As you have said."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:13, What did Elijah say to the widow to do from the flour afterward she make him a small cake? 2pts.","answer":"Make some for yourself and your son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:13, fill in the blanks, And Elijah said to her, \u201c____, ___ and do ____, but make me a _______from it ___, and bring it to me; and ___make some for ___and your ____\u201d. 8pts.","answer":"Do not fear, go, as you have said, small cake, first, afterward, yourself, son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, What did Elijah say that the Lord God of Israel says? 3pts.","answer":"The bin of flour shall not be used up, nor shall the jar of oil run dry, until the day the Lord sends rain on the earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, Who said that the bin of flour shall not be used up, nor shall the jar of oil run dry, until the day the Lord sends rain on the earth? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The Lord God of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, What did the Lord say that shall not be used up? 1pt.","answer":"The bin of flour."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, What did the Lord say shall not run dry? 1pt.","answer":"the jar of oil."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, What did the Lord say shall not happen to the bin of flour and the jar of oil? 2pts.","answer":"shall not be used up, shall not run dry."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, For thus says the Lord God of Israel: \u2018The bin of flour shall not be used up, nor shall the jar of oil run dry, until when? 1pt.","answer":"Until the day the Lord sends rain on the earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:14, fill in the blanks, For thus says the Lord God of Israel: \u2018The ___shall not be ___, nor shall the ___ ____, until the ____the ___sends ___on the ___\u2019\u201d.","answer":"Bin of flour, used up, jar of oil, run dry, day, Lord, rain, earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:15, What did the widow do? 2pts.","answer":"She went away and did according to the word of Elijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:15, According to what did the widow do? 1pt.","answer":"According to the word of Elijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:15, Who ate for many days? 3pts.","answer":"She and he and her household."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:15, For how long did the widow, Elijah and her household ate? 1pt.","answer":"Many days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:16, What happened according to the word of the Lord which He spoke by Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"The bin of flour was not used up, nor did the jar of oil run dry."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:16, By whom did the Lord spoke? 1pt.","answer":"By Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:16, What did the Lord do by Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"Spoke"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:16, According to what  was the bin of flour not used up, nor did the jar of oil run dry?","answer":"According to the word of the Lord which He spoke by Elijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, What happened after this things ( the flour was not used up and the oil didn\u2019t dry up)? 1pt.","answer":"The son of the woman who owned the house became sick."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, Who became sick? 1pt.","answer":"The son of the woman who owned the house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, What happened to the so  of the woman who owned the house? 1pt.","answer":"Became sick"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, When did the son of the woman become sick? 1pt.","answer":"After these things."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, What did the woman own? 1pt.","answer":"The house."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, How was the sickness of the woman\u2019s son? Be specific.","answer":"It was so serious that there was no breath left in him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, What was so serious that there was no breath left in the woman\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"His sickness."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:17, What was not left in the woman\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"no breath"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, What did the women say to Elijah after there was no breath left in her son? 3pts.","answer":"What have I to do with you, O man of God? Have you come to me to bring my sin to remembrance, and to kill my son?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, To whom did the women say, \u201cWhat have I to do with you, O man of God? Have you come to me to bring my sin to remembrance, and to kill my son? 1pt.","answer":"To Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, What did the women called Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"Man of God."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, The women say to Elijah If he had come to her for what? 2pts.","answer":"Bring her sin to remembrance, and kill her son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, The women said that Elijah had come to bring what to remembrance? 1pt.","answer":"Her sin"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, What did the women say that Elijah had come to with her son? 1pt.","answer":"Kill him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:18, Fill in the blanks, So she said to Elijah, \u201cWhat have I to ___with you, ___?","answer":"Have you ___to me to ___my ___to ___and to ___ my ____?\u201d 8pts. Do, O man of God, come, bring, sin, remembrance, kill, son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, What did Elijah say to the women? 1pt.","answer":"Give me your son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, What did Elijah say to women to give him? 1pt.","answer":"her son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, How did Elijah take the women\u2019s son the upper room where he was staying? 1pt.","answer":"He took him out of her arms and carried him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, Where was Elijah staying? 1pt.","answer":"In the upper room."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, What did Elijah do with the women\u2019s son after he said to the women, \u201cGive me your son\u201d? 3pts.","answer":"Took him out of her arms and carried him to the upper room where he was staying, and laid him on his own bed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, Where did Elijah take the women\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"to the upper room where he was staying."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:19, Where did Elijah laid the women\u2019s son? 1pt.","answer":"on his own bed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, What did Elijah do after he took the women\u2019s son to the upper room where he was staying and laid him in his own bed? 1pt.","answer":"He cried out to the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, What did Elijah said to the Lord? 3pts.","answer":"\u201cO Lord my God, have You also brought tragedy on the widow with whom I lodge, by killing her son?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, How did Elijah start his prayer? 1pt.","answer":"O Lord my God."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, What question did Elijah ask the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Have You also brought tragedy on the widow with whom I lodge, by killing her son?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, What did Elijah think the Lord brought on the widow with whom he lodge? 1pt.","answer":"Tragedy"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, Elijah asked the Lord if He had also brought tragedy on whom? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The widow with whom I lodge."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, Elijah asked the Lord if He had also brought tragedy on the widow with who he lodge, by doing what? 1pt.","answer":"By killing her son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:20, fill in the blanks, Then he cried out to the Lord and said, \u201c___ my ____, have You also ____ ___on the ___with whom I ___, by ___her ___?\u201d. 8pts.","answer":"O Lord, God, brought, tragedy, widow, lodge, killing, son."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, What did Elijah do with the child three times? 1pt.","answer":"Stretched himself out on the child."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, How many times did Elijah stretched himself out on the child? 1pt.","answer":"three times"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, What did Elijah do besides stretching himself out on the child? 1pt.","answer":"Cried out to the LORD."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, What did Elijah say when he cried out to the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"O LORD my God, I pray, let this child\u2019s soul come back to him\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, What did Elijah pray for? 1pt.","answer":"Let this child\u2019s soul come back to him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, What did Elijah ask God in prayer to let come back to the child? 1pt.","answer":"his soul"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:21, fill in the blanks, \u201cO ___my ___, I____, let this _____come ___to ____.\u201d 6pts.","answer":"Lord, God, pray, child\u2019s soul, back, him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:22, What did the Lord hear? 1pt.","answer":"The voice of Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:22, Who heard the voice of Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"The Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:22, What happened after the Lord heard the voice of Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"The soul of the child came back to him, and he revived."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:22, What happened with the child after Elijah\u2019s prayer? 2pts.","answer":"His soul came back to him, and he revived."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:22, What came back to the child after Elijah\u2019s prayer? 1pt.","answer":"His soul."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:23, Who took the child and brought him down from the upper room into the house and gave him to his mother? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:23, What did Elijah do after the child revived? 3pts.","answer":"Took the child and brought him down form the upper room into the house, and gave him to his mother."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:23, From where did Elijah brought the child and gave him to his mother? 1pt.","answer":"From the upper room into the house.  "},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:23, What did Elijah say to the widow? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cSee your son lives!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:24, What did the woman said to Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"Now by this I know that you are a man of God, and that the word of the Lord in your mouth is the truth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:24, Now by this What did the woman know? 2pts.","answer":"That you (Elijah) are a man of God, and that the word of the Lord is the truth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:24, What was the word of the Lord in his mouth? 1pt.","answer":"the Truth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:24, What did the woman know that was the truth? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord in your mouth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 17:24, fill in the blanks, Then the woman said to Elijah, \u201cNow ____I know that you are a __________, and that the ____of the ____in your _____is the ____.\u201d 7pts.","answer":"by this, a man of God, word, Lord, mouth, truth."}

        //Concluding Moral Directions
        
        
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c18":[

        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, When did the word of the Lord came to Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"after many days, in the third year"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, What came to Elijah after many days, in the third year? 1pt.","answer":"the word of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, What came to pass after many days, in the third year?","answer":"The word of the Lord came to Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, It came to pass after many days that the word of the Lord came to whom in the third year? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, What did the word of the Lord that came to Elijah say? 3pts.","answer":"\u201cGo, present yourself to Ahab, and I will send rain on the earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, The word of the Lord said to Elijah to present himself to whom? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, What will the Lord say He will do when Elijah present himself to Ahab? 1pt.","answer":"He will send rain on the earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:1, fill in the blanks, And it came to pass after many days that the word of the Lord came to Elijah, in the third year saying, \u201c ____, ______yourself to _____, and I will send _____on the _____.\u201d 5pts.","answer":"Go, present, Ahab, rain, earth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:2, So what did Elijah do after the word of the Lord came to him? 1pt.","answer":"present himself to Ahab."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:2, What was there in Samaria when Elijah present himself to Ahab? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"A severe famine"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:2, Where was there a severe famine when Elijah present himself to Ahab? 1pt.","answer":"In Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:3, Who had Ahab called?  1pt.","answer":"Obadiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:3, Who was in charge of Ahab\u2019s house?","answer":"Obadiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:3, What responsibility did Obadiah had? 1pt.","answer":"was in charge of his house (Ahab\u2019s)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:3, How did Obadiah feel about the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"feared the Lord greatly."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:3, Who feared the Lord greatly? 1pt.","answer":"Obadiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, When had Obadiah taken one hundred prophets and hidden them? 1pt.","answer":"while Jezebel massacred the prophets of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, Who massacred the prophets of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Jezebel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, What did Jezebel do the prophets of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"massacred them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, Who did Jezebel massacre? 1pt.","answer":"the prophets of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, Who had taken one hundred prophets and hidden them? 1pt.","answer":"Obadiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, How many prophets had Obadiah hidden? 1pt.","answer":"One hundred"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, How had Obadiah hidden the one hundred prophets? 1pt.","answer":"Fifty to a cave."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, What had Obadiah done with one hundred prophets of the Lord? 2pts.","answer":"hidden them, fed them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:4, How did Obadiah feed the prophets? 2pts.","answer":"with bread and water"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Where did Ahab ask Obadiah to go? 3pts.","answer":"into the land, to all the springs of water and to all the brooks."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Who was sent to go into the land to all the springs of water and to all the brooks to find grass to keep horses and mules alive? 1pt.","answer":"Obadiah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Who sent Obadiah to go into the land to all the springs of water and to all the brooks to find grass to keep horses and mules alive? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, What was Obadiah to look for in all the springs of water and all the brooks? 1pt.","answer":"grass to keep the horses and mules alive."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Why was Obadiah sent to look for grass in all the springs and all the brooks?","answer":"To keep horses and mules alive."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Where will Obadiah look for grass to keep the horses and mules alive? 2pts.","answer":"all the springs of water and all the brooks."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, Why did Ahab want Obadiah to find grass to keep the horses and mules alive? 1pt.","answer":"So that they will not have to kill any livestock."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:5, fill in the blanks, And Ahab had said to Obadiah, \u201cGo into the ___to all the ______ and to all the ___; ____we may find ____to keep the _____ and ____ ____, so that we will not have to ____ any _____\u201d. 10 pts.","answer":"Land,  springs of water, brooks, perhaps, grass, horses, mules, alive, kill, livestock."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:6, What method did Ahab and Obadiah used to find grass to keep the horses and mules alive? 1pt.","answer":"they divided the land between them to explore it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:6, How did Ahab and Obadiah explore the land? 2pts.","answer":"Ahab went one way by himself, and Obadiah went another way by himself."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:6, True or false?","answer":"Ahab and Obadiah explore the land together. 1pt. False."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:6, What did Ahab and Obadiah divide between them? 1pt.","answer":"the land"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:6, For what purpose did Ahab and Obadiah divide the land between them? 1pt.","answer":"to explore it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, What happened suddenly as Obadiah was on his way? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah met him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, Who suddenly met Obadiah as he was on his way?","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, When did Elijah suddenly met Obadiah? 1pt.","answer":"as Obadiah was on his way."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, What did Obadiah do when he met Elijah? 3pts.","answer":"recognized him, fell on his face and said, \u201cIs that you, my lord Elijah?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, What did Obadiah do when he recognized Elijah and before he talked to him? 1pt.","answer":"fell on his face."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:7, What did Obadiah say to Elijah when he recognized him and fell on his face? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cIs that you, my lord Elijah?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:8, What did Elijah answer when Obadiah asked him. \u201cIs it you, my lord Elijah? 3pts.","answer":"\u201cIt is I. Go, tell you master, \u2018Elijah is here\u2019\u201d. 1pt. It its I."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:8, What message did  Elijah sent  to Obadiah\u2019s master? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cElijah is here\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:9, Who said, \u201cHow have I sinned, that you are delivering your servant into the hand of Ahab, to kill me? 1pt.","answer":"He (Obadiah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:9, Which was Obadiah\u2019s question to Elijah?","answer":"How have I sinned, that you are delivering your servant into the hand of Ahab, to kill me?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:9, Into whose hands did Obadiah say Elijah was delivering him?","answer":"Into the hand of Ahab."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:9, fill in the blanks, So he said, \u201cHow have I ____, that you are ____your ___ into the ___ of ____, to ___me?. 5pts.","answer":"sinned, delivering, servant, hand, Ahab, kill."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, What was there not where Obadiah\u2019s master has not sent someone to hunt for Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"nation or kingdom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, There is no nation or kingdom were whom has not sent someone to hunt for Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"My master (Ahab)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, There is no nation or kingdom where Obadiah\u2019s master has not done what? 1pt.","answer":"Sent someone to hunt for you (Elijah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, When did Obadiah\u2019s master took an oath from the kingdom or nation that they could not find Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"when they said, \u2018He is not there\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, What did Obadiah\u2019s master do when they said, \u201cHe is not here\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"Took an oath from the kingdom or nation that they could not find you (Elijah)."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, From whom did Obadiah\u2019s master took an oath that they could not find Elijah? 2pts.","answer":"from the kingdom or nation"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, Of what did Obadiah\u2019s master took an oath from the kingdom or nation? 1pt.","answer":"That they could not find Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:10, fill in the blanks, \u201c______, there is no _____or ____where my ____has not sent someone to _____ for you; and when they said, _____, he took an ____from the ____or ____that they could not ___you.\u201d 10pts.","answer":"As the Lord your God lives, nation, kingdom, master, hunt, he is not here, oath, kingdom, nation, find."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:11, fill in the blanks, \u201cand ____ you say, \u2018____, tell your _____, ______!\u2019. 4pts.","answer":"Now, Go, master, Elijah is here!."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, What did Obadiah say that it shall come to pass? 2pts.","answer":"As soon as I am gone from you, that the Spirit of the Lord will carry you to a place I do not know"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, When did Obadiah say that the Spirit of the Lord will carry Elijah to a place he do not know, so when he go and tell Ahab, and cannot find Elijah, he will kill him? 1pt.","answer":"As soon as I am gone from you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, Who did Obadiah say will carry Elijah to a place he do not know? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The Spirit of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, What did Obadiah say  the Spirit of the Lord will do to Elijah as soon as he was gone from him, to tell Ahab \u201cElijah is here!\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"Carry you to a place I do not know."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, Where did Obadiah say the Spirit of the Lord will carry Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"to a place I do not know."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, What did Obadiah say that will happen when he goes and tell Ahab, \u201cElijah is here!\u201d and he cannot find him? 1pt.","answer":"He will kill me."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, When did Obadiah say that Ahab will kill him? 2pt.","answer":"When I go and tell Ahab, and he cannot find you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, What did Obadiah say he has done from his youth? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Feared the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, Who have feared the Lord from his youth? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Your servant"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, Since when had Obadiah feared the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"From my youth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:12, fill in the blanks, \u201cAnd it ____, as soon as I am ___from you, that the ____ will ___you to a place I do not ____: so when I go and tell ___, and he cannot ___you, he will ___me. But your _____have ____the ___from my ____.\u201d. 12pts.","answer":"shall come to pass, gone, Spirit of the Lord, carry, know, Ahab, find, kill, servant, feared, Lord, youth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:13, fill in the blanks, \u201c Was it not ___to my ___what I did when ___killed the ____, how I hid _____men of the Lord\u2019s prophets, ____to a ___, and ___them with ___ and ___?\u201d. 10pts.","answer":"Reported, lord, Jezebel, prophets of the Lord, one hundred, fifty, cave, fed, bread, water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:13, What did Obadiah ask Elijah if it was not reported to him? 3pts.","answer":"What I did when Jezebel killed the prophets of the Lord, how I hid one hundred men of the Lord\u2019s prophets, fifty to a cave, and fed them with bread and water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:14, What did Obadiah say that Elijah says now? 2pts.","answer":"Go, tell your master,  \u201cElijah is Here.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:14, What did Obadiah say his master will do when he tells him \u201cElijah is here\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"He will kill me!."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, What did Elijah say to Obadiah? 3pts.","answer":"\u201cAs the Lord of hosts lives, before whom I stand, I will surely present myself to him today.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, What did Elijah say to Obadiah that he will surely do today? 1pt.","answer":"Present myself to him (Ahab)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, When did Elijah say to Obadiah that he will surely present himself to Ahab? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Today"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, Elijah assured that he will present himself to Ahab today, What did he say before making this statement? 2pts.","answer":"As the Lord of hosts lives, before whom I stand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, How does Elijah refers to the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Lord of hosts"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:15, fil in the blanks, The Elijah said, \u201c_______, before whom I ______, I will _____ ______ ______ to him ____.\u201d 6pts.","answer":"As the Lord of hosts lives, stand, surely, present, myself, today."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:16, What did Obadiah do? 1pt.","answer":"Ent to meet Ahab 2pts. went to meet Ahab, and told him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:16, What did Obadiah do when he went to meet Ahab? 1pt.","answer":"Told him (that Elijah was here)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:16, With whom will Obadiah meet? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:16, What did Ahab do after he met with Obadiah? 1pt.","answer":"Went to meet Elijah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:16, Who went to meet Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:17, How did Ahab refer to Elijah? 1pt. be specific.","answer":"Troubler of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:17, who did Ahab refer to as troubler of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:17, When did Ahab said to Elijah, \u201cIs that you, o troubler of Israel? 1pt.","answer":"When Ahab saw Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:17, What did Ahab said to Elijah when he saw him? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cIs that you, O troubler of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, Who did Elijah say that have troubled Israel? 2pts.","answer":"You (Ahab) and your father\u2019s house"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, true or false?","answer":"Elijah answered to Ahab saying, \u201cI have troubled Israel. 1pt. False (I have not troubled Israel)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, In which ways did Elijah say that  Ahab and his father\u2019s house have troubled Israel? 2pts.","answer":"In that you have forsaken the commandments of the Lord and have followed the Baals"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, What did Elijah say that Ahab and his father\u2019s house have forsaken? 1pt.","answer":"The commandments of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, What did Elijah say that Ahab and his father\u2019s house have followed? 1pt.","answer":"the Baals."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:18, fill in the blanks, And he answered, \u201cI have not _____Israel, but ___and your ____ have, in that you have ____the ____of the Lord and have ____the ____.\u201d 7pts.","answer":"troubled, you, father\u2019s house, forsaken, commandments, followed, Baals."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, Who did Elijah say Ahab to send and gather on Mount Carmel? 3pts.","answer":"All Israel, the four hundred and fifty prophets of Baal, and the four hundred prophets of Asherah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, Where was Ahab to gather to Elijah all Israel, the four hundred and fifty prophets of Baal and the four hundred prophets of Asherah? 1pt.","answer":"on Mount Carmel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, How many prophets of Baal will be gathered on Mount Carmel? 1pt.","answer":"four hundred and fifty"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, How many prophets of Asherah will be gathered on Mount Carmel? 1pt.","answer":"Four hundred"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, Where do the prophets of Baal and Asherah eat? 1pt.","answer":"at Jezebel\u2019s table."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, Who eat at Jezebel\u2019s table? 2pts.","answer":"the four hundred and fifty prophets of Baal, and the four hundred prophets of Asherah."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:19, fill in the blanks, \u201cNow ___, _____ and gather ____ to me on _____, the _____ prophets of _____, and _____prophets of ____, who eat at ____\u201d. 9pts.","answer":"therefore, send, all Israel, Mount Carmel, four hundred and fifty, Baal, four hundred, Asherah, Jezebel\u2019s table."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:20, What did Ahab do? 2pts.","answer":"sent for all the children of Israel and gathered the prophets together on Mount Carmel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:20, Who did Ahab gather together on Mount Carmel? 1pt.","answer":"The prophets"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:20, true or false?","answer":"Ahab sent for some of the children of Israel. 1pt. false (all)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, To whom did Elijah say, \u201cHow long will you falter between two opinions? If the Lord is God, follow Him; but if Baal, follow him\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"To all the people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, What did Elijah say when he came to all the people?","answer":"\u201cHow long will falter between two opinions? If the Lord is God, follow Him; but if Baal follow him.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, What question did Elijah asked all the people? 1pt.","answer":"How long will you falter between two pinions?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, How long will you what between two opinions? 1pt.","answer":"falter"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, What two choices did Elijah tell the people? 2pts.","answer":"If the Lord is God, follow HIM; but if Baal, follow him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, What did the people answered Elijah when he said to them, if the Lord is God follow Him; but if Baal, follow him.? 1pt be specific.","answer":"Not a word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:21, fill in the blanks, \u201c\u00a0And ____came to ____, and said, \u201cHow long will you _______between _____?","answer":"If the Lord is _____, ____ Him; but if ____, ____him.\u201d But _____answered him _______. 10pts.  Elijah, all the people, falter, two opinions, God, Baal, follow, the people, not a word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, Who did Elijah say to the people was left a prophet of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"I alone."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, What did Elijah say he alone was left as? 1pt.","answer":"a prophet of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, How many prophets of Baal did Elijah said were left?","answer":"Four hundred and fifty man"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, There were four hundred and fifty men, prophets of whom? 1pt.","answer":"Baal"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, To whom did Elijah say, \u201cI alone am left a prophet of the Lord; but Baal\u2019s prophets are four hundred and fifty men? 1pt.","answer":"to the people."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:22, fill in the blanks, Then Elijah said to the people, \u201c_______am left a _____of _____; but _____prophets are ____________men.\u201d 5pt.","answer":"I alone, prophet, the LORD, Baal\u2019s, four hundred and fifty."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, Elijah said that he alone was left a prophet of the Lord, Therefore what did he ask that the prophets of Baal give them? 1pt.","answer":"Two bulls"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, Elijah said that there were four hundred and fifty prophets of Baals therefore Elijah let them give to them two bulls and let them do what? 1pt.  ","answer":"choose one bull for themselves.  4pts. choose one bull for themselves, cut it in pieces, and lay it on the wood, but put no fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, Who chose and prepared the bull of Baal\u2019s prophets? 1pt.","answer":"Themselves."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, Who prepared the other bull? 1pt.","answer":"I (Elijah)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, What were the prophets of Baal to do in order to prepare their bull? 3pts.","answer":"Cut it in pieces, and lay it on wood, but put no fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, What will Elijah do with the other bull? 3pts.","answer":"Prepare it, and lay it on the wood, but put no fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, When Elijah, the prophet of the Lord, and the prophets of Baal prepared the bulls they wouldn\u2019t do one thing, what was it? 1pt.","answer":"put fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:23, fill in the blanks, \u201c______ let them give us ____; and let them choose _____ for themselves, _____, and lay it ______, but put no ____under it; and I will _____the _____, and ______, but put no ____ under it.  10pts.  ","answer":"Therefore, two bulls, one bull,  cut in pieces, on the wood, fire, prepare, other bull,  lay it on the wood, fire."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, When the bulls where prepared what will the prophets of Baal and Elijah, the prophet of the Lord do? 2pts.","answer":"Call on the name of your gods, call on the name of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, What will be the sign to prove who Is God? 1pt.","answer":"the God who answers by fire."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, fill in the blanks, The God who answers by fire _____. 1pt.","answer":"He is God."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, How did all the people and said? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"\u201cIt is well spoken\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, who answered and said \u201cit is well spoken\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"all the people."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:24, fill in the blanks, \u201cThen you ____on the ____of your gods, and I will ____on the ____of the ____; and the ____who ____by ____, ______.\u201d So all the people answered and said, \u201c______\u201d 10pts.","answer":"Call. Name, call, name, Lord, God, answers, fire, He is God, It is well spoken."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:25, What did Elijah said to the prophets of Baal? 4pts.","answer":"Choose one bull for yourselves and prepare firs, for you are many; and call on the name of your god, but put no fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:25, To whom did Elijah said \u201cChoose one bull for yourselves and prepare first for you are many; and call on the name of your god, but put no fire under it\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"the prophets of Baal."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:25, Why will the prophets of Baal prepare their bull first? 1pt.","answer":"For you are many."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:25, What will the prophets of Baal do for they were many? 2pts.","answer":"Choose one bull for themselves and prepare first."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:25, fill in the blanks, Now Elijah said to the prophets of Baal, \u201cChoose ____for yourselves and ___it ____, for you are ____; and ___on the ___of your ___, but ____\u201d. 8pts.","answer":"one bull, prepare, first, many, call, name, god, put no fire under it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:26, What did the prophets of Baal do after they choose the bull for themselves? 3pts.","answer":"They took the bull which was given them, and they prepared it, and called on the name of Baal from morning even till noon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:26, For how long did the prophets of Baal call on his name? 2pts.","answer":"from morning even till noon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:26, What did the prophets of Baal say while calling in his name? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"\u201cO Baal, hear us!"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:26, What happened after the prophets of Baal called on his name from morning even until noon, saying, \u201cO Baal, hear us!\u201d? 2pts.","answer":"There was no voice; no one answered."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:26, What did the prophets of Baal do when they called on the name of Baal but there was no voice and no one answered? 1pt.","answer":"They leaped about the altar which they had made."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:27, when did Elijah mocked the prophets of Baal and said, \u201cCry aloud, for he is a god; either he is meditating, or he is busy, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is sleeping and must be awakened\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"At noon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:27, What did Elijah do at noon? 1pt.","answer":"Mocked them (the prophets of Baal)."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:27, What did Elijah said to the prophets of Baal to do, when he mocked them? 1pt.","answer":"Cry aloud 2pts. Cry aloud, for he is a god."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:27, When Elijah mocked the prophets of Baal he said to them to cry aloud, for he is a God, What did he say their god might be doing? 5pts.","answer":"Either he is meditating, or he is busy, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is sleeping and must be awakened."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:27, fill in the blanks, An so it was, at noon, that Elijah mocked them and said, \u201c_____, for he is a ____\u2019 either he is ____, or he is ____, or he is ___, or perhaps he is ____and must be ____\u201d. 7pts.","answer":"Cry aloud, god, meditating, busy, on a journey, sleeping, awakened."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:28, What did the prophets of Baal do as was their custom? 4pts.","answer":"Cut themselves, with knives and lances, until the blood gushed out on them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:28, What did the prophets of Baal do as Elijah suggested to cry aloud? 2pts.","answer":"They cried aloud, and cut themselves."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:28, Why did the prophets of Baal cut themselves, with knives and lances, until the blood gushed out of them? 1pt.","answer":"As was their custom"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:28, With what did the prophets of Baal cut themselves, until the blood gushed out on them? 2pt.","answer":"with knives and lances"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:28, The prophets of Baal cried aloud, and cut themselves, as was their custom, with knives and lances, until what happened? 1pt.","answer":"Until the blood gushed out on them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:29, What did the prophets of Baal do when midday was past? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"They prophesied until the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:29, When did the prophets of Baal prophesied until the time offering of the evening sacrifice? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"when midday was past."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:29, until what time did the prophets of Baal prophecy? 1pt.","answer":"until the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:29, What did the prophets of Baal do until the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice? 1pt.","answer":"Prophesied."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:29, What happened after the prophets of Baal prophesied until the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice? 3pts.","answer":"There was no voice, no one answered, no one paid attention."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:30, What did Elijah said to all the people, after the prophets of Baal had no answer from their god? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cCome near to me\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:30, What did all the people do when Elijah asked them to come near to him? 1pt.","answer":"All the people came near to him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:30, What did Elijah do after all the people came near to him? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"He repaired the altar of the Lord that was broken down."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:30, How was the altar of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"Broken down."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:30, What was broken down that Elijah had to repair? 1pt.","answer":"The altar of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:31, What did Elijah took according to the number of the tribes of the sons of Jacob? 1pt.","answer":"twelve stones."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:31, According to what did Elijah took twelve stones for the altar? 1pt.","answer":"According to the number of the tribes of the sons of Jacob."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:31, To whom had the word of the Lord come, saying, \u201cIsrael shall be your name\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"to Jacob"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:31, What had come to Jacob saying, \u201cIsrael shall be your name.\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"The word of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:31, What did the word of the Lord say to Jacob? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cIsrael shall be your name\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, What did Elijah do with the stones? 1pt.","answer":"He built an altar in the name of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, With what did Elijah build an altar in the name of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"with the stones"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, What did Elijah built in the name of the Lord? 1pt.","answer":"An altar"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, What did Elijah made around the altar? 1pt.","answer":"a trench"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, Where did Elijah made a trench? 1pt.","answer":"around the altar."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, How big was the trench that Elijah made around the altar? 1pt.","answer":"Large enough to hold two seahs of seed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:32, The trench that Elijah made around the altar was large enough to hold what? 1pt.","answer":"Two seahs of seed."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, What did Elijah do before asking to Fill four waterpots with water, and pour it on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood? 3pts.","answer":"He put the wood in order, cut the bull in pieces, and laid it on the wood."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, What did Elijah say after he put the wood in order, cut the bull in pieces, and laid it on the wood? 2pts.","answer":"Fill four waterpots with water, and pour it on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, How many waterpots did Elijah say that needed to be filled with water? 1pt.","answer":"Four"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, Where did Elijah say that the four waterpots  with water should be poured? 2pts.","answer":"On the burnt sacrifice and on the wood."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, What should be poured on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood? 1pt.","answer":"Four waterpots with water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:33, fill in the blanks, And he put the wood in order, cut the bull in pieces, and laid it on the wood, and said, \u201cFill _____ with ____, and ___it on the ____ ___and on the ______.\u201d 6pts.","answer":"Four waterpots, water, pour, burnt sacrifice, wood."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:34, How many times did they poured water on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood? 1pt.","answer":"Three."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:34, What did the people do when Elijah asked them to pour water on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood a second and third time? 2pts.","answer":"They did it a second time, they did it a third time."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:34, What did Elijah say to the people to do? 2pts.","answer":"\u201cDo it a second time\u201d, \u201cDo it a third time\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:35, Where did the water run after it was poured three times on the burnt sacrifice? 2pts.","answer":"all around the altar; and also filled the trench with water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:35, What ran all around the altar, and also filled the trench? 1pt.","answer":"The water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, What came to pass, at the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice?","answer":"That Elijah the prophet came near and said, \u201cLord God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that You are God in Israel and I am Your servant, and that I have done all these things at Your word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, When came to pass, that Elijah the prophet came near and said, Lord God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that You are God in Israel and I am Your servant, and that I have done these things at Your word? 1pt.","answer":"at the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, Who came near and said, \u201cLord God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be know this day that You are God in Israel and I am Your servant, and that I have done all these things at Your word? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"Elijah the prophet."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, When Elijah prayed to the Lord he refers to Him as the God of whom? 3pts.","answer":"Abraham, Isaac, and Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, What did Elijah asked the Lord God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel to let it be known this day? 3pts.","answer":"That You are God in Israel, and I am Your servant, and that I have done all these things at Your word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, When did Elijah asked the Lord to let it be known that He is God and Israel and he was His servant, and that he has done all these things at His word? 1pt.","answer":"This day."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, What had Elijah done at the Lord\u2019s word? 1pt.","answer":"All these things."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, How had Elijah done all these things? 1pt.","answer":"At Your (the Lord\u2019s) word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:36, fill in the blanks, \u201c____ ___of _____, _____, and _____, let it be _____ ____ that You are ___ in _____ and I am Your ____, and that I have done all these ____at Your _____\u201d. 12pts.","answer":"Lord, God, Abraham, Isaac, Israel, known, this day, God, Israel, servant, things, word."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:37, fill in the blanks, \u201c______me, ______, ______me, that this ___may know that You are _____, and that You have ____their ____back to You ____.\u201d 8pts.","answer":"Hear, O Lord, Hear, people, The Lord God, turned, hearts, again."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:37, What did Elijah ask the Lord in his prayer  that this people may know? 2pts.","answer":"That You are the LORD God, and that You have turned their hearts back to You again."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:37, fill in the blanks, _____, _____, _____, that this people may know that You are the LORD God, and that You have turned their hearts back to You again. 3pts.","answer":"Hear me, O Lord, Hear me."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:37, What did Elijah want the people to know that Lord has done for them again? 1pt.","answer":"turned their hearts back to Him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What did the fire of the Lord do? 6pts.","answer":"Fell, and consumed the burnt sacrifice, and the wood and the stones and the dust, and it licked up the water that was in the trench."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What did the fire of the Lord consume when it fell? 4pts.","answer":"The burnt sacrifice, the wood, the stones and the dust."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What did the fire of the Lord licked up when it fell? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"The water that was in the trench."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What consumed the burnt sacrifice, and the wood and the stones and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench? 1pt.","answer":"The fire of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What did the fire of the Lord do to the burnt sacrifice, and the wood and the stones and the dust? 1pt.","answer":"consumed it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:38, What did the fire of the Lord do with the water that was in the trench? 1pt.","answer":"Licked it up."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:39, What did all the people do when they saw that the fire consumed the burnt sacrifice, and the wood, and the stones and the dust and licked up the water that was in the trench? 1pt.","answer":"They fell on their faces. 3pts. They fell on their faces and said, \u201cThe Lord, He is God! The Lord, He is God!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:39, What did all the people say when they saw that the fire consumed the burnt sacrifice, and the wood, and the stones and the dust and licked up the water that was in the trench? 2pts.","answer":"\u201cThe Lord , He is God! The Lord, He is God!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:39, Who fell on their faces, and said, \u201cThe Lord, He is God! The Lord, He is God!? 1pt.","answer":"all the people"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:39, When did all the people fell on their faces; and said, \u201cThe Lord, He is God! The Lord, He is God!? 1pt.","answer":"When they saw it (The fire)"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, What did Elijah say to the people? 2pts.","answer":"\u201cSeize the prophets of Baal! Do not let one of them escape!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, What did Elijah say the people to do with prophets of Baal? 2pts.","answer":"Seize them, Do not let one of them escape."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, What did the people do when Elijah say to them to seize the prophets of Baal and do not let one of them escape? 1pt.","answer":"Seized them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, Who executed the prophets of Baal at the Brook Kishon? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, What did Elijah do with the prophets of Baal after all the people seized them? 2pts.","answer":"brought them down to the Brook of Kishon and executed them there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, Where did Elijah execute the prophets of Baal? 1pt.","answer":"At the Brook Kishon"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:40, What did Elijah do at the Brook Kishon? 1pt.","answer":"Execute the prophets of Baal."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, What did Elijah say to Ahab? 3pts.","answer":"\u201dGo up, eat and drink; for there is the sound of abundance of rain.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, To whom did Elijah say, \u201cGo up, eat and drink; for there is the sound of abundance of rain.\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"Ahab"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, What did Elijah say to Ahab to do for there is the sound of abundance of rain? 3pts.","answer":"Go up, eat and drink."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, Why did Elijah say to Ahab to go up, eat and drink? 1pt.","answer":"For there is the sound of abundance of rain."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, What sound did Elijah say to Ahab there was? 1pt.","answer":"of abundance of rain."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:41, Fill in the blanks, Then Elijah said to  Ahab, \u201c___, ___ and ___; For there is the ____ of ____of _____\u201d. 6pts.","answer":"Go up, eat, drink, sound, abundance, rain."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, What did Ahab do after Elijah said to him that there was the sound of abundance of rain? 1pt.","answer":"went up to eat and drink."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, Where did Elijah go? 1pt.","answer":"up to the top of Carmel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, What did Elijah do when he was on the top of Carmel? 2pts.","answer":"He bowed down on the ground, and put his face between his knees."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, Where did Elijah bowed down? 1pt.","answer":"on the ground"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, Where did Elijah put his face? 1pt.","answer":"Between his knees."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:42, What did Elijah put between his knees? 1pt.","answer":"his face."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, What did Elijah said to his servant when they were in the top of Carmel? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cGo up now, look toward the sea\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, To whom did Elijah say. \u201cGo up now, look toward the sea\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"to his servant."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, When did Elijah say to his servant to go up and look toward the sea? 1pt.","answer":"Now"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, Where did Elijah say to his servant to look? 1pt.","answer":"Towards the sea."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, What did Elijah\u2019s servant do when Elijah say to him to go up and look toward the sea? 2pts.","answer":"He went up and looked."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, What did Elijah\u2019s servant say after he went up and looked toward the sea? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cThere is nothing\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, How many times did Elijah say to his servant, \u201cGo again.\u201d? 1pt.","answer":"seven times"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, What did Elijah say to his servant seven times? 1pt.","answer":"\u201cGo again\u201d."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:43, What did Elijah\u2019s servant look when he looked toward the sea the first time? 1pt.","answer":"Nothing"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What came to pass in the seventh time that Elijah\u2019s servant went up and look toward the sea? 3pts.","answer":"He said, \u201cThere is a cloud, as small as man\u2019s hand, rising out of the sea!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, When did Elijah\u2019s servant saw a cloud, as small as a man\u2019s hand, rising out of the sea? 1pt.","answer":"The seventh time."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What did Elijah\u2019s servant saw that was as small as a man\u2019s hand, rising out of the sea? 1pt.","answer":"A cloud."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, How big was the cloud that Elijah\u2019s servant saw rising out of the sea? 1pt.","answer":"as small as a man\u2019s hand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, Where did Elijah\u2019s servant saw a cloud, as small as man\u2019s hand? 1pt.","answer":"rising out of the sea."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What did Elijah say to his servant to do after he saw a cloud, as small as a man\u2019s hand, rising out of the sea? 4pts.","answer":"Go up, say to Ahab, prepare your chariot, and go down before the rain stops you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What will Elijah\u2019s servant say to Ahab? 2pts.","answer":"Prepare your chariot, and go down before the rain stops you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What did Elijah sent his servant to say to Ahab to prepare? 1pt.","answer":"His chariot."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, Elijah say to Ahab to prepare his chariot and go down before what happened? 1pt.","answer":"The rain stops you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, What would Ahab do before the rain stops him? 2pt.","answer":"prepare his chariot,  and go down."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:44, fill in the blanks, \u201cThere is a ____, as ___as a ___ ___, ___out of the ____!\u201d so he said, \u201c____, say to ____, ____your ____, and ___before the ___ ____you.\u201d 13 pts.","answer":"cloud, small, man\u2019s, hand, rising, sea, Go up, Ahab, prepare, chariot, go down, rain, stops."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, What happened in the meantime? 3pts.","answer":"the sky became black with clouds and wind, and there was a heavy rain."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, With what did the sky become black? 2 pts.","answer":"with clouds and wind."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, What became black with clouds and wind? 1pt.","answer":"The sky"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, What was there when the sky became black with clouds and wind? 1pt. Be specific.","answer":"A heavy rain"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, What did Ahab do? 2pts.","answer":"Rode away and went to Jezreel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:45, Where did Ahab go? 1pt.","answer":"To Jezreel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, What came upon Elijah? 1pt.","answer":"The hand of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, Upon whom did the hand of the Lord come? 1pt.","answer":"Elijah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, What did Elijah do when the hand of the Lord came upon him? 2pts.","answer":"girded up his loins and ran ahead of Ahab to the entrance of Jezreel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, What did Elijah girded up and ran ahead of Ahab to the entrance of Jezreel? 1pt.","answer":"His loins"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, Where did Elijah run? 1pt.","answer":"Ahead of Ahab to the entrance of Jezreel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 18:46, To Where did Elijah run?","answer":"To the entrance of Jezreel."}
        
        
       
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c19":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:1, To whom did Ahab describe all that Elijah had done on Mount Carmel?","answer":"And Ahab told Jezebel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:1, What did Ahab tell Jezebel about the events on Mount Carmel in addition to the death of the prophets?","answer":"all that Elijah had done,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:1, What did Ahab tell Jezebel Elijah had done with the prophets?","answer":"also how he had executed all the prophets with the sword."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:2, Who sent a message to Elijah after he had killed the prophets of the false god?","answer":"Then Jezebel sent a messenger to Elijah, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:2, What words did Jezebel use to indicate she was serious about killing Elijah?","answer":"\u201cSo let the gods do to me, and more also,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:2, What did Jezebel swear she would do to Elijah by the next day?","answer":"if I do not make your life as the life of one of them"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:2, By what time the following day did Jezebel swear that Elijah would be killed?","answer":"by tomorrow about this time.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:3, when did Elijah arise and run for his life?  Be specific.","answer":"And when he saw that,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:3, what did Elijah do when Jezebel's messenger told him her plans? 2pts.","answer":"he arose and ran for his life,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:3, to what city did Elijah take his servant to when he ran for his life from Jezebel?","answer":"and went to Beersheba,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:3, to what country did Elijah take his servat to when he ran for his life from Jezebel?","answer":"which belongs to Judah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:3, when Elijah ran for his life, who did he leave in Beersheba?","answer":"and left his servant there."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:4, How far did Elijah go from Beersheba before he sat down to rest under a broom tree?","answer":"But he himself went a day\u2019s journey into the wilderness,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:4, Where was Elijah when he prayed that he might die?","answer":"and came and sat down under a broom tree."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:4, What was the purpose of Elijah's prayer when he sat down and prayed under the broom tree?","answer":"And he prayed that he might die,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:4, Elijah prayed that God would do something because he was no better than his fathers. What did he ask?","answer":"and said, \u201cIt is enough! Now, Lord, take my life,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:4, What reason did Elijah give for asking God to take his life?","answer":"for I am no better than my fathers!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:5, During Elijah's trip to Mount Horeb, what was Elijah doing when an angel touched him?","answer":"Then as he lay and slept under a broom tree,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:5, who came and touched Elijah when he was sleeping under a broom tree?","answer":"suddenly an angel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:5, what did the angel do to Elijah while Elijah was sleeping under a broom tree?","answer":"touched him, and said to him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:5, what did the angel tell Elijah to do the first time Elijah was awakened?","answer":"\u201cArise and eat.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:6, During Elijah's trip to Mount Horeb, what was the first thing Elijah did after the first time the angel touched him?","answer":"Then he looked,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:6, Where did Elijah see food and water when he awoke under the broom tree the first time?","answer":"and there by his head was"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:6, How was the food and water described that Elijah saw the first time the angle awoke him?","answer":"a cake baked on coals, and a jar of water."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:6, What did Elijah do the first time the angel told him to Arise and eat?","answer":"So he ate and drank, and lay down again."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:7, Who came a second time to Elijah while he was sleeping under a broom tree?","answer":"And the angel of the Lord"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:7, What did the angel of the Lord do at the end of the second time Elijah was sleeping under the broom tree?","answer":"came back the second time, and touched him, and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:7, The angel told Elijah to do something because the journey was too great for him.  What did he tell Elijah to do?","answer":"\u201cArise and eat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:7, Why did the angel tell Elijah the second time to arise and eat?","answer":"because the journey is too great for you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:8, what 4 things did Elijah do after the angel provided the second meal? 4pts.","answer":"So he arose, and ate and drank; and he went"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:8, for how many days did the angel's food sustain Elijah?","answer":"in the strength of that food forty days and forty nights"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:8, how far did Elijah travel using the food the angel gave him?","answer":"as far as Horeb,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:8, how is Horeb described?","answer":"the mountain of God."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:9, When he got to Horeb where did Elijah spend the night?","answer":"And there he went into a cave,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:9, What was Elijah doing in the cave at Horeb when the word of the LOrd came to him?","answer":"and spent the night in that place;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:9, When Elijah got to Horeb, who asked him what he was doing there?","answer":"and behold, the word of the Lord came to him, and He said to him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:9, When Elijah was sleeping in the cave at Mount Horeb, what was the first question God ask him?","answer":"\u201cWhat are you doing here, Elijah?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, Elijah explained how he had acted because the children of Israel had forsaken God's covenant. With what words did Elijah use to describe his actions?","answer":"So he said, \u201cI have been very zealous for the Lord God of hosts;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, Elijah said he had been very zealous for for the Lord God of hosts for a group of people had forsaken God's covenant.  What group of people was this?","answer":"for the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have [done what], torn down Your altars, and killed Your prophets with the sword.\"","answer":"have forsaken Your covenant,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have forsaken Your covenant, [done what], and killed Your prophets with the sword.\"","answer":"torn down Your altars,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have forsaken Your covenant, torn down Your altars, and [done what].\"","answer":"and killed Your prophets with the sword."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, How many people did Elijah think had remained faithful to God?","answer":"I alone am left;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:10, What did Elijah think the children of Israel wanted to do with him?","answer":"and they seek to take my life.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, After listening to Elijah's reason to come to Horeb, where did God tell Elijah to go?","answer":"Then He said, \u201cGo out,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, After listening to Elijah's reason to come to Horeb, where did God tell Elijah to stand?","answer":"and stand on the mountain before the Lord.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, who passed by while Elijah was at Horeb?","answer":"And behold, the Lord passed by,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, describe the wind that Elijah observed at Horeb.","answer":"and a great and strong wind tore into the mountains and broke the rocks in pieces before the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, was the Lord in the wind that broke the rocks in pieces?","answer":"but the Lord was not in the wind;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11 what did Elijah notice after the wind?","answer":"and after the wind an earthquake,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:11, was the Lord in the earthquake that Elijah observed at Horeb?","answer":"but the Lord was not in the earthquake;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, what did Elijah notice after the earthquake?","answer":"and after the earthquake a fire,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, was the Lord in the fire?","answer":"but the Lord was not in the fire;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, what did Elijah notice after the fire?","answer":"and after the fire a still small voice."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:13, when did Eliajh wrap his face in his mantle?","answer":"So it was, when Elijah heard it,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, what did Elijah do with his mantle when he heard the still small voice?","answer":"that he wrapped his face in his mantle"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, what did Elijah do after wrapping his face in his mantle?","answer":"and went out and stood in the entrance of the cave."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, what happened after Elijah went out and stood in the entrance of the cave?","answer":"Suddenly a voice came to him, and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:12, a voice suddenly came to Elijah when he stood in the entrance of the cave.  What did this voice say?","answer":"\u201cWhat are you doing here, Elijah?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, Elijah explained how he had acted because the children of Israel had forsaken God's covenant. With what words did Elijah use to describe his actions?","answer":"And he said, \u201cI have been very zealous for the Lord God of hosts;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, Elijah said he had been very zealous for for the Lord God of hosts because a group of people had forsaken God's covenant.  What group of people was this?","answer":"because the children of Israel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have [done what], torn down Your altars, and killed Your prophets with the sword.\"","answer":"have forsaken Your covenant,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have forsaken Your covenant, [done what], and killed Your prophets with the sword.\"","answer":"torn down Your altars,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, Elijah said \"...the children of Israel have forsaken Your covenant, torn down Your altars, and [done what].\"","answer":"and killed Your prophets with the sword."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, How many people did Elijah think had remained faithful to God?","answer":"I alone am left;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:14, What did Elijah think the children of Israel wanted to do with him?","answer":"and they seek to take my life.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:15, Toward the wilderness of what city did God ask Elijah to go?","answer":"Then the Lord said to him: \u201cGo, return on your way to the Wilderness of Damascus;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:15, God told Elijah to anoint Hazael as king over Syria when Elijah did what?  Be specific.","answer":"and when you arrive,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:15, What did God tell Elijah to do when he got to the Wilderness of Damascus?","answer":"anoint Hazael as king over Syria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:16, At Horeb, who did God tell Elijah to anoint king over Israel?","answer":"Also you shall anoint Jehu the son of Nimshi as king over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:16, At Horeb, who did God tell Elijah to anoint as prophet?","answer":"And Elisha the son of Shaphat of Abel Meholah you shall anoint as prophet in your place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:17, Who did God say that Jehu would kill?","answer":"It shall be that whoever escapes the sword of Hazael, Jehu will kill;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:17, Who did God say that Elisha would kill?","answer":"and whoever escapes the sword of Jehu, Elisha will kill."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:18, how many people in Israel were faithful to God?","answer":"Yet I have reserved seven thousand in Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:18, God described two acts of worship to a false god that 7000 people had not done. What was the act that was related to their legs?","answer":"all whose knees have not bowed to Baal,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:18, God described two acts of worship to a false god that 7000 people had not done. What was the act that was related to their mouths?","answer":"and every mouth that has not kissed him.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, what did Elijah do after God finished speaking to him at Horeb and before he found Elisha?","answer":"So he departed from there,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, who did Elijah find plowing with 12 yoke of oxen?","answer":"and found Elisha the son of Shaphat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, How rich was Elisha's father?","answer":"who was plowing with twelve yoke of oxen before him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, How many oxen were under Elisha's supervision before he became a prophet?","answer":"who was plowing with twelve yoke of oxen before him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, with wich pair of oxen was Elisha with?","answer":"and he was with the twelfth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, What did Elijah do as he passed by Elisha in his father's field?","answer":"Then Elijah passed by him and threw his mantle on him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, once Elisha decided to follow Elijah, but before he spoke to him, what did Elisha do?","answer":"And he left the oxen and ran after Elijah, and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, what did Elisha ask for permission to do before starting to follow him?","answer":"\u201cPlease let me kiss my father and my mother, and then I will follow you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, how did Elijah respond to Elisha's request to kiss his parents before following Elijah?","answer":"And he said to him, \u201cGo back again, for what have I done to you?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, what did Elisha do after Elijah said he could kiss is parents and before he slaughtered a yoke of oxen?","answer":"So Elisha turned back from him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, What did Elisha do to get the meat for his farewell feast?","answer":"and took a yoke of oxen and slaughtered them and boiled their flesh,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, What did Elisha use for at least some of the fuel to cook the food for his farewell feast?","answer":"using the oxen\u2019s equipment,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, To whom did Elisha give the food he had prepared?","answer":"and gave it to the people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, What did the people do with the food that Elisha gave them?","answer":"and they ate."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 19:19, What did Elisha become after leaving his parent's farm?","answer":"Then he arose and followed Elijah, and became his servant."}
        
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c20":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:1, who besieged Samaria with 32 other kings?","answer":"Now Ben-Hadad the king of Syria gathered all his forces together;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:1, how many kings joined Ben-Hadad in besieging Samaria?","answer":"thirty-two kings were with him, with horses and chariots."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:1, what did Ben-Hadad do with 32 other kings against Ahab king of Israel?","answer":"And he went up and besieged Samaria, and made war against it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:2, after surrounding Samaria with his army, what did Ben-Hadad king of Syria do?","answer":"Then he sent messengers into the city"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:2, to whom did the king of Syria send a message when he surrounded Samaria with his army?","answer":"to Ahab king of Israel, and said to him, \u201cThus says Ben-Hadad:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:3, Ben-Hadad claimed to own two categories of things and two categories of people that had been Ahab's.  What were the two categories of things?","answer":"\u2018Your silver and your gold are mine;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:3, Ben-Hadad claimed to own two categories of people that had been Ahab's.  What was the older category of people?","answer":"your loveliest wives"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:3, Ben-Hadad claimed to own two categories of people that had been Ahab's.  What was the younger category of people?","answer":"and children are mine.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:4, when Ben-Hadad claimed ownership of Ahab's silver, gold, wives, and children, did Ahab agree?","answer":"And the king of Israel answered and said, \u201cMy lord, O king, just as you say,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:4, when Ben-Hadad claimed ownership of Ahab's silver, gold, wives, and children, what did Ahab say belonged to Ben-Hadad?","answer":"I and all that I have are yours.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:5, After Ahab agreed that all he had belonged to Ben-Hadad, what did the king of Syria do next?","answer":"Then the messengers came back and said, \u201cThus speaks Ben-Hadad, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:5, After Ahab agreed that all he had belonged to Ben-Hadad, what did Ben-Hadad say should be delivered to him?","answer":"\u2018Indeed I have sent to you, saying, \u201cYou shall deliver to me your silver and your gold, your wives and your children\u201d;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:6, who did Ben-Hadad say would search search Ahab's house and when did he say the search would be performed?","answer":"but I will send my servants to you tomorrow about this time,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:6, what did Ben-Hadad say his servants would do tomorrow about this time?","answer":"and they shall search your house and the houses of your servants."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:6, what things did Ben-Hadad say his servants would take when they would visit tomorrow?","answer":"And it shall be, that whatever is pleasant in your eyes,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:6, what did Ben-Hadad say his servants would do with whatever is pleasant in Ahab's eyes?","answer":"they will put it in their hands and take it.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:7, With whom did Ahab consult after Ben-Hadad's messenger said his servants would come the following day to take everything that was pleasant in Ahab's eyes?","answer":"So the king of Israel called all the elders of the land, and said,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:7, What did Ahab tell the elders that Ben-Hadad was seeking by asking for him to send his wives, children, silver, and gold?","answer":"\u201cNotice, please, and see how this man seeks trouble,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:7, What did Ahab tell the elders of the land that he had agreed to send Ben-Hadad?","answer":"for he sent to me for my wives, my children, my silver, and my gold;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:7, Did Ahab tell the elders that he had agreed to send Ben-Hadad his wives, children, silver, and gold?","answer":"and I did not deny him.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:8, who told Ahab, \u201cDo not listen or consent.\u201d","answer":"And all the elders and all the people said to him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:8, how did the elders of the people say Ahab should respond to Ben-Hadad?","answer":"\u201cDo not listen or consent.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:9, to whom did Ahab say \u2018All that you sent for to your servant the first time I will do,\u2019","answer":"Therefore he said to the messengers of Ben-Hadad, \u201cTell my lord the king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:9, after consulting with the elders, what part of Ben-Hadad's request did Ahab say the second time he would agree to?","answer":"\u2018All that you sent for to your servant the first time I will do,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:9, after consulting with the elders, what part of Ben-Hadad's request did Ahab say he would not agree to","answer":"but this thing I cannot do.\u2019 \u201d And the messengers departed and brought back word to him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:10, What words did the king of Syria use to ask for curses upon himself if he didn't plunder Ahab.","answer":"Then Ben-Hadad sent to him and said, \u201cThe gods do so to me, and more also,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:10, How did Ben-Hadad indicate that he was not going to return home without valuable plunder?","answer":"if enough dust is left of Samaria for a handful for each of the people who follow me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:11, Ahab answered Ben-Hadad's threat to plunder Samaria by saying that he shouldn't boast before the battle as if the battle was won. What words did he use to describe speaking before the battle?","answer":"So the king of Israel answered and said, \u201cTell him, \u2018Let not the one who puts on his armor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:11, Ahab answered Ben-Hadad's threat to plunder Samaria by saying that he shouldn't boast before the battle as if the battle was won. What words did he use to describe speaking after the battle?","answer":"boast like the one who takes it off.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:12, Who heard Ahab's caution about boasting of victory before the battle had started while drinking?","answer":"And it happened when Ben-Hadad heard this message,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:12, What was Ben-Hadad doing when he heard Ahab's advice to not boast before the battle was won?","answer":"as he and the kings were drinking at the command post,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:12, What did Ben-Hadad tell his servants when he heard Ahab's caution about boasting of victory before the battle had started?","answer":"that he said to his servants, \u201cGet ready.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:12, What did Ben-Hadad's servants to when he told them to get ready?","answer":"And they got ready to attack the city."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:13, who appeared before Ahab when Ben-Hadad's servants were preparing for battle?","answer":"Suddenly a prophet approached Ahab king of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:13, What did the prophet tell Ahab about the size of the Syrian army when Ben-Hadad's servants were preparing to attack?","answer":"saying, \u201cThus says the Lord: \u2018Have you seen all this great multitude?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:13, What did the Lord tell Ahab would happen to the great multitude of Ben-Hadad's army?","answer":"Behold, I will deliver it into your hand today,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:13, What reason did God give for delivering Ahab?","answer":"and you shall know that I am the Lord.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:14, When God told Ahab that Ben-Hadad would lose the battle, what did Ahab ask him?","answer":"So Ahab said, \u201cBy whom?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:14, Who did God say would deliver Ahab from Ben-Hadad?","answer":"And he said, \u201cThus says the Lord: \u2018By the young leaders of the provinces.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:14, After hearing that the young leaders of the provinces would deliver him from Ben-Hadad, what was Ahab's next battle question?","answer":"Then he said, \u201cWho will set the battle in order?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:14, Who did God say should set the battle in order?","answer":"And he answered, \u201cYou.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:15, After receiving the Lord's message from his prophet, what did Ahab do?","answer":"Then he mustered the young leaders of the provinces,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:15, how many young leaders of the provinces were on Israel's side?","answer":"and there were two hundred and thirty-two;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:15, who did Ahab gather for battle after the young leaders of the provinces?","answer":"and after them he mustered all the people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:15, how many people were in Israel's army in addition to the young leaders of the provinces?","answer":"all the children of Israel\u2014seven thousand."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:16, what time of day did Ahab's army attack Ben-Hadad's army?","answer":"So they went out at noon."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:16, who were getting drunk at noon on the day the Israelites and Syrian's battled each other?","answer":"Meanwhile Ben-Hadad and the thirty-two kings helping him"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:16, what were Ben-Hadad and the 32 kings with him doing when Ahab's army approached?","answer":"were getting drunk at the command post."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:17, Under Ahab's order, who started the attack?","answer":"The young leaders of the provinces went out first."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:17, Who told Ben-Hadad, \u201cMen are coming out of Samaria!\u201d","answer":"And Ben-Hadad sent out a patrol, and they told him, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:17, What did Ben-Hadad's patrol tell him?","answer":"\u201cMen are coming out of Samaria!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:18, There were 2 conditions under which Ben-Hadad ordered his men to take the Israelites alive.  What was the first?","answer":"So he said, \u201cIf they have come out for peace,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:18, What did Ben-Hadad ordered his men to do if the Israelites were come out for peace?","answer":"take them alive;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:18, There were 2 conditions under which Ben-Hadad ordered his men to take the Israelites alive.  What was the second?","answer":"and if they have come out for war,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:18, What did Ben-Hadad ordered his men to do if the Israelites were come out for war?","answer":"take them alive.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:19, Who came out from the city of Samaria in front of the army?","answer":"Then these young leaders of the provinces went out of the city"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:19, Who came out from the city of Samaria behind the young leaders of the provinces?","answer":"with the army which followed them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:20, What caused the Syrians to flee before the young leaders of the Israelite provinces?","answer":"And each one killed his man;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:20, what resulted from each of the young leaders killing his opponent?","answer":"so the Syrians fled,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:20, what did Israel do when the Syrians fled?","answer":"and Israel pursued them;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:20, how did Ben-Hadad escape the Israelite attack?","answer":"and Ben-Hadad the king of Syria escaped on a horse with the cavalry."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:21, What did Ahab do when Ben-Hadad's cavalry fled?","answer":"Then the king of Israel went out and attacked the horses and chariots,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:20, How successful was the battle that day for Israel?","answer":"and killed the Syrians with a great slaughter."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:22, after the victory over Ben-Hadad, what did God's prophet tell Ahab that he should do for himself?","answer":"And the prophet came to the king of Israel and said to him, \u201cGo, strengthen yourself;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:22, after the victory of Ben-Hadad, God's prophet told Ahab to do 2 things to strengthen himself.  What were they?","answer":"take note, and see what you should do,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:22, Why did God ask Ahab to strengthen himself after his first victory over Ben-Hadad?","answer":"for in the spring of the year the king of Syria will come up against you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:23, What reason did Ben-Hadad's servants give to explain why they lost against Ahab?","answer":"Then the servants of the king of Syria said to him, \u201cTheir gods are gods of the hills."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:23, Ben-Hadad's servants believed that the God of the Israelites was a god of the hills.  Based on this, what conclusion did they make about their strength in the first battle they had with Israel?","answer":"Therefore they were stronger than we;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:23, Ben-Hadad's servants believed that the God of the Israelites was a god of the hills.  Based on this, where did they advice the next battle to be.","answer":"but if we fight against them in the plain,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:23, What did Ben-hadad's servants think would happen to their strength if next time they fought with Israel in the plain?","answer":"surely we will be stronger than they."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:24, For the second battle with Ahab, what did Ben-Hadad's servants say to do with the kings?","answer":"So do this thing: Dismiss the kings,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:24, Ben-Hadad's servants said to put captains in the place of something that had been the king's. What was this?","answer":"each from his position,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:24, Ben-Hadad's servants told him to dismiss the kings and put what in their positions?","answer":"and put captains in their places;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:25, What did Ben-Hadad's servants say he should do \"horse for horse and chariot for chariot\"?","answer":"and you shall muster an army like the army that you have lost,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:25, By what to measures of the size of the army did Ben-Hadad's servants say he should use to muster the same sized army for the second battle with Ahab?","answer":"horse for horse and chariot for chariot."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:25, What did Ben-Hadad's servants say he should do after mustering a similar army as before?","answer":"Then we will fight against them in the plain;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:25, Ben-Hadad's servants said that if he mustered a similar army and fought Ahab in the plain, how would their strength compare?","answer":"surely we will be stronger than they.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:25, Did Ben-Hadad pay attention to his servant's advice?","answer":"And he listened to their voice and did so."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:26, When did Ben-Hadad muster the Syrians against Ahab the second time?","answer":"So it was, in the spring of the year,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:26, What did Ben-Hadad do in the spring of the year before going up to Aphek?","answer":"that Ben-Hadad mustered the Syrians"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:26, Where did Ben-Hadad take the army after he mustered the Syrians the second time?","answer":"and went up to Aphek to fight against Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:27, When Ben-Hadad took his army to Aphek what what did the children of Israel do to prepare for battle?","answer":"And the children of Israel were mustered and given provisions,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:27, After the children of Israel were mustered and given provisions, what did they do?","answer":"and they went against them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:27, How did Israel's army compare to Syrians'?","answer":"Now the children of Israel encamped before them like two little flocks of goats,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:27, How much space did the Syrian camp occupy?","answer":"while the Syrians filled the countryside."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:28, How did Ahab hear that God was going to give him the victory over Ben-Hadad?","answer":"Then a man of God came and spoke to the king of Israel, and said, \u201cThus says the Lord:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:28, God told Ahab two reasons he was going to deliver the Syrian army into his hands. One was that Ahab would then know that God is the Lord.  What was the other reason?","answer":"\u2018Because the Syrians have said, \u201cThe Lord is God of the hills, but He is not God of the valleys,\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:28, What did the Lord say he was going to do so that Ahab would know that God is Lord?","answer":"therefore I will deliver all this great multitude into your hand,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:28, God told Ahab two reasons he was going to deliver the Syrian army into his hands. One was that the Syrians thought that the god of Israel wasn't able to prevail in the plain.  What was the other reason?","answer":"and you shall know that I am the Lord.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:29, How long did Ahab and Ben-Hadad's armies camp near each other before starting to fight?","answer":"And they encamped opposite each other for seven days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:29, on what day was the battle between Ahab and Ben-Hadad's armies joined?","answer":"So it was that on the seventh day the battle was joined;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:29, how many Syrian foot soldiers died on the first day of the second battle?","answer":"and the children of Israel killed one hundred thousand foot soldiers of the Syrians"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:29, how many days did it take for the children of Israel to kill 100,000 Syrians?","answer":"in one day."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:30, Where did the Syrian army flee after engaging battle with Israel?","answer":"But the rest fled to Aphek, into the city;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:30, How many Syrians died in Aphek and what caused their death?","answer":"then a wall fell on twenty-seven thousand of the men who were left."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:30, Ben-Hadad went into an inner chamber.  Where did he go to get to this place?","answer":"And Ben-Hadad fled and went into the city,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:30, When Ben-Hadad fled and went into the city, where did he go?","answer":"into an inner chamber."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:31, What character trait had Ben-hadad heard about the kings of Israel had?","answer":"Then his servants said to him, \u201cLook now, we have heard that the kings of the house of Israel are merciful kings."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:31, When Ben-Hadad was hiding from Ahab's army, how did his's servants suggest that he dress himself?","answer":"Please, let us put sackcloth around our waists and ropes around our heads,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:31, Where did Ben-Hadad's servants say they should go after putting sackcloth around their waists and ropes around their heads?","answer":"and go out to the king of Israel;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:31, When Ben-Hadad was hiding from Ahab's army, why did Ben-Hadad's servants say they should go to the king of Israel?","answer":"perhaps he will spare your life.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:32, What did Ben-Hadad and his servants put around their waists as they prepared to go to Ahab?","answer":"So they wore sackcloth around their waists"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:32, What did Ben-Hadad and his servants put around their heads as they prepared to go to Ahab?","answer":"and put ropes around their heads,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:32, What did Ben-Hadad's servants say when he came before Ahab?","answer":"and came to the king of Israel and said, \u201cYour servant Ben-Hadad says, \u2018Please let me live.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:32, What did Ahab say when he heard Ben-Hadad's request to be permitted to live?","answer":"And he said, \u201cIs he still alive? He is my brother.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:33, what were Ben-Hadad's servants looking for in Ahab's response?","answer":"Now the men were watching closely to see whether any sign of mercy would come from him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:33, what did Ben-Hadad's servants say in response to Ahab's question, \"Is he still alive?\"","answer":"and they quickly grasped at this word and said, \u201cYour brother Ben-Hadad.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:33, when Ahab understood that Ben-Hadad was alive, what did he command should be done?","answer":"So he said, \u201cGo, bring him.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:33, what did Ben-Hadad do when Ahab said \"Go, bring him.\"","answer":"Then Ben-Hadad came out to him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:33, where did Ahab tell Ben-Hadad to go when he came to him?","answer":"and he had him come up into the chariot."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:34, while in Ahab's chariot what did Ben-Hadad say he would restore?","answer":"So Ben-Hadad said to him, \u201cThe cities which my father took from your father I will restore;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:34, where did Ben-Hadad say Ahab could set up marketplaces?","answer":"and you may set up marketplaces for yourself in Damascus, as my father did in Samaria.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:34, how did Ahab respond to Ben-Hadad's offer of peace?","answer":"Then Ahab said, \u201cI will send you away with this treaty.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:34, after making a treaty with Ben-Hadad, what did Ahab do to him?","answer":"So he made a treaty with him and sent him away."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:35, Who said to whom, \"Strike me, please.\"?","answer":"Now a certain man of the sons of the prophets said to his neighbor"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:35 What did a prophet say to his neighbor?","answer":"by the word of the Lord, \u201cStrike me, please.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:35, when a prophet asked his neighbor to strike him, how did his neighbor respond?","answer":"And the man refused to strike him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:36, why did a prophet tell his neighbor, \"..a lion shall kill you\"?","answer":"Then he said to him, \u201cBecause you have not obeyed the voice of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:36, what did a prophet tell his neighbor would happen to him because he refused to strike him?","answer":"surely, as soon as you depart from me, a lion shall kill you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:36, what happened to the prophet's neighbor?","answer":"And as soon as he left him, a lion found him and killed him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:37, how did the prophet get someone to wound him?","answer":"And he found another man, and said, \u201cStrike me, please.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:37, when a prophet asked a second person to strike him, what did this second person do?","answer":"So the man struck him, inflicting a wound."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:28, what did the prophet do before disguising himself with a bandage over his eyes?","answer":"Then the prophet departed and waited for the king by the road,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:38, what did the prophet do as he waited for the king by the road?","answer":"and disguised himself with a bandage over his eyes."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:39, where did the prophet tell the king that he (the prophet) had been?","answer":"Now as the king passed by, he cried out to the king and said, \u201cYour servant went out into the midst of the battle;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:39, what did the prophet say someone had has him to do?","answer":"and there, a man came over and brought a man to me, and said, \u2018Guard this man;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:39, what did the prophet say he had agreed to with a punishment of his own life or a talent of silver?","answer":"if by any means he is missing,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:39, what did the prophet say he had agreed to if he didn't have a talent of silver and the man he was asked to guard became missing?","answer":"your life shall be for his life,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:39, what did the prophet say he had agreed to as a way to spare his life even if the man he was asked to guard became missing?","answer":"or else you shall pay a talent of silver.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:40, What did the prophet say happened to the man he was asked to guard?","answer":"While your servant was busy here and there, he was gone.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:40, How merciful was Ahab to the prophet?","answer":"Then the king of Israel said to him, \u201cSo shall your judgment be;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:40, what reason did Ahab give his judgment of the prophet?","answer":"you yourself have decided it.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:41, what did the prophet do as soon as the king gave his judgment?","answer":"And he hastened to take the bandage away from his eyes;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:41, what did Ahab see when the prophet remove his bandage?","answer":"and the king of Israel recognized him as one of the prophets."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:42, what did the prophet say Ahab had done wrong?","answer":"Then he said to him, \u201cThus says the Lord: \u2018Because you have let slip out of your hand a man whom I appointed to utter destruction,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:42, what consequence did the prophet say the king would have for himself because he let Ahab go?","answer":"therefore your life shall go for his life,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:42, what consequence did the prophet say the king would have for his people because he let Ahab go?","answer":"and your people for his people.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:42, How did Ahab feel when he heard the prophet say that the Lord would take his life the the life of his people?","answer":"So the king of Israel went to his house sullen and displeased,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 20:42, Where did Ahab go after hearing that the Lord would take his life the the life of his people?","answer":"and came to Samaria."}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c21":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:1, who owned property next to Ahab's palace in Jezreel and what was he doing with it?","answer":"And it came to pass after these things that Naboth the Jezreelite had a vineyard which was in Jezreel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:1, who lived next to the vineyard in Jezreel that belonged to Naboth?","answer":"next to the palace of Ahab king of Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, what did Ahab tell Naboth to give him?","answer":"So Ahab spoke to Naboth, saying, \u201cGive me your vineyard,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, what was Ahab going to do with Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"that I may have it for a vegetable garden,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, why did Ahab want Naboth's vineyard instead of someone else's land?","answer":"because it is near, next to my house;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, Ahab offered Naboth 2 options in exchange for the vineyard. What did he offer instead of money?","answer":"and for it I will give you a vineyard better than it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, Who did Ahab say could choose between the two offers he was giving Naboth for the vineyard?","answer":"Or, if it seems good to you,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:2, Ahab offered Naboth 2 options in exchange for the vineyard.  What did he offer instead of a better vineyard?","answer":"I will give you its worth in money.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:3, who did Naboth say should forbid him from giving his vineyard to Ahab?","answer":"But Naboth said to Ahab, \u201cThe Lord forbid"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:3, what did Naboth say the Lord would forbid?","answer":"that I should give the inheritance of my fathers to you!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:4, how did Ahab feel after hearing Naboth's answer to his request for Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"So Ahab went into his house sullen and displeased"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:4, who's words caused Ahab be sullen and displeased?","answer":"because of the word which Naboth the Jezreelite had spoken to him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:4, what did Naboth say to Ahab?","answer":"for he had said, \u201cI will not give you the inheritance of my fathers.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:4, what 3 things did Ahab do when he went to his house after speaking with Naboth?","answer":"And he lay down on his bed, and turned away his face, and would eat no food."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:5, who ask Ahab why he wasn't eating food? What did this person say?","answer":"But Jezebel his wife came to him, and said to him, \u201cWhy is your spirit so sullen"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:5, Jezebel was concerned that Ahab's spirit was so sullen that he wouldn't do what?","answer":"that you eat no food?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:6, who did Ahab tell his wife he had spoken with that made him sullen?","answer":"He said to her, \u201cBecause I spoke to Naboth the Jezreelite,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:6, Ahab told Jezebel the two offers he had made to Naboth. How did he describe the offer that wasn't for a better vineyard?","answer":"and said to him, \u2018Give me your vineyard for money;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:6, Ahab told Jezebel the two offers he had made to Naboth. How did he describe the offer that wasn't for money?","answer":"or else, if it pleases you, I will give you another vineyard for it.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:6, What did Ahab tell his wive that Ahab had said in response to his offers?","answer":"And he answered, \u2018I will not give you my vineyard.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:7, what did Jezebel exclaim to Ahab before telling him to arise, eat, and be cheerful?","answer":"Then Jezebel his wife said to him, \u201cYou now exercise authority over Israel!"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:7, what 3 things did Jezabel tell Ahab to do because she would give him Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"Arise, eat food, and let your heart be cheerful;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:7, what reason did Jezabel give Ahab to be cheerful?","answer":"I will give you the vineyard of Naboth the Jezreelite.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:8, what did Jezebel seal with Ahab's seal?","answer":"And she wrote letters in Ahab\u2019s name,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:8, how did Jezebel prepare to send the letters she wrote in Ahab's name?","answer":"sealed them with his seal,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:8, to whom did Jezebel send letters in Ahab's name?","answer":"and sent the letters to the elders and the nobles who were dwelling in the city with Naboth."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:9, in the letters what did Jezebel tell the elders and nobles to proclaim?","answer":"She wrote in the letters, saying, Proclaim a fast,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:9, where did Jezebel say Naboth should be seated at the fast?","answer":"and seat Naboth with high honor among the people;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:10, who did Jezebel say should be seated in front of Naboth? and for what purpose?","answer":"and seat two men, scoundrels, before him to bear witness against him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:10, what did Jezabel say the scoundrels should say to Naboth?","answer":"saying, \u201cYou have blasphemed God and the king.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:10, what did Jezebel say to do to Naboth after the false accusations were made against him? 3pts.","answer":"Then take him out, and stone him, that he may die."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:11, there were 3 groups of people that did what Jezebel said to do. What was the name of the group that wasn't either the elders or the nobles?","answer":"So the men of his city,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:11, who did as Jezebel ordered in Ahab's name in addition to the men of the city?","answer":"the elders and nobles who were inhabitants of his city,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:11, how did the elders and nobles of the city receive Jezebel's letters","answer":"did as Jezebel had sent to them,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:11, did the elders and nobles do as Jezebel told them to do?","answer":"as it was written in the letters which she had sent to them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:12, what did the elders and nobles proclaim?","answer":"They proclaimed a fast,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:12, where did the elders and nobles seat Naboth?","answer":"and seated Naboth with high honor among the people."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:13, how many of what kind of people sat in front of Naboth?","answer":"And two men, scoundrels, came in and sat before him;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:12, what did the scoundrels do against Naboth by saying \"Naboth has blasphemed God and the king!\"?","answer":"and the scoundrels witnessed against him, against Naboth, in the presence of the people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:12, what did the scoundrels say against Naboth?","answer":"saying, \u201cNaboth has blasphemed God and the king!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:12, what did the men of the city do to Naboth?","answer":"Then they took him outside the city and stoned him with stones, so that he died."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:14, whom did the nobles of Jezreel inform when they had killed Naboth.","answer":"Then they sent to Jezebel, saying, \u201cNaboth has been stoned and is dead.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:15, when did Jezebel tell Ahab to take possession of Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"And it came to pass, when Jezebel heard that Naboth had been stoned and was dead,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:15, what did Jezebel do when she heard that Naboth was dead?","answer":"that Jezebel said to Ahab, \u201cArise, take possession of the vineyard of Naboth the Jezreelite,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:15, of which offer that Ahab had made to Naboth did Jezebel remind him?","answer":"which he refused to give you for money;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:15, what reason did Jezebel give for telling him to take posession of Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"for Naboth is not alive, but dead.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:16, when did Ahab go down to take possession of Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"So it was, when Ahab heard that Naboth was dead,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:16, what did Ahab do when he heard that Naboth was dead?","answer":"that Ahab got up and went down to take possession of the vineyard of Naboth the Jezreelite."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:17, what happened after Ahab went to take possession of Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"Then the word of the Lord came to Elijah the Tishbite, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:18, Who did God tell Elijah to go and meet?","answer":"\u201cArise, go down to meet Ahab king of Israel, who lives in Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:18, Where did God tell Elijah that he would find Naboth?","answer":"There he is, in the vineyard of Naboth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:18, God told Elijah why Ahab would be in Naboth's vineyard.  What was the reason?","answer":"where he has gone down to take possession of it."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:19, what question did God tell Elijah to ask Ahab when Elijah would meet him in Naboth's vineyard?","answer":"You shall speak to him, saying, \u2018Thus says the Lord: \u201cHave you murdered and also taken possession?\u201d \u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:19, What did God say would happen to Ahab's blood?","answer":"And you shall speak to him, saying, \u2018Thus says the Lord: \u201cIn the place where dogs licked the blood of Naboth, dogs shall lick your blood, even yours.\u201d \u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:20, when Elijah came to talk with Ahab after Naboth was dead, what did Ahab say to greet him?","answer":"So Ahab said to Elijah, \u201cHave you found me, O my enemy?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:20, what did Elijah say to Ahab when he asked \"Have you found me, O my enemy?\"?","answer":"And he answered, \u201cI have found you,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:20, what was the reason Elijah gave Ahab that he had found Ahab?","answer":"because you have sold yourself to do evil in the sight of the Lord:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:21, what did God say he would bring on Ahab?","answer":"\u2018Behold, I will bring calamity on you."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:21, what did God say he would take away from Ahab?","answer":"I will take away your posterity,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:21, what did God say he would cut off from Ahab?","answer":"and will cut off from Ahab every male in Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:21, God emphasized that he would cut off from Ahab every male in Israel by mentioning 2 categories of Ahab's people. What were they? 2pts.","answer":"both bond and free."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:22, to describe how completely the destruction to Ahab would be, God compared to two specific families. What was the earlier family?","answer":"I will make your house like the house of Jeroboam the son of Nebat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:22, to describe how completely the destruction to Ahab would be, God compared to two specific families. What was the more recent family?","answer":"and like the house of Baasha the son of Ahijah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:22, in addition to making Israel sin, what was the other reason God gave for planning destruction on Ahab?","answer":"because of the provocation with which you have provoked Me to anger,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:22, in addition to making God angry, what was the other reason God gave for planning descruction on Ahab?","answer":"and made Israel sin.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:23, what did God say dogs would do to Jezebel?","answer":"And concerning Jezebel the Lord also spoke, saying, \u2018The dogs shall eat Jezebel"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:23, where did God say dogs would eat Jezebel?","answer":"by the wall of Jezreel.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:24, who would dogs eat?","answer":"The dogs shall eat whoever belongs to Ahab and dies in the city,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:24, who would birds eat?","answer":"and the birds of the air shall eat whoever dies in the field.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:25, what result did Jezebel have on her husband?","answer":"But there was no one like Ahab who sold himself to do wickedness in the sight of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:25, why was Ahab so wicked?","answer":"because Jezebel his wife stirred him up."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:26, in what way did Ahab behave like the Amorites?","answer":"And he behaved very abominably in following idols,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:26, Ahab behaved abominably following whose behavior?","answer":"according to all that the Amorites had done,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:26, what had the Lord done to the Amorites that had acted like Ahab was acting?","answer":"whom the Lord had cast out before the children of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, when did Ahab go about mourning?","answer":"So it was, when Ahab heard those words,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, what did Ahab do to his clothes when he heard God's judgment against him?","answer":"that he tore his clothes"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, what type of clothing did Ahab put on when he heard God's judgment against him?","answer":"and put sackcloth on his body,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, how did Ahab's eating habits change when he heard God's judgment against him?","answer":"and fasted"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, what did Ahab use for his bed sheets when he heard God's judgment against him?","answer":"and lay in sackcloth,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:27, when Ahab heard God's judgment against him what did he go about doing?","answer":"and went about mourning."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:28, when Ahab humbled himself what came to Elijah?","answer":"And the word of the Lord came to Elijah the Tishbite, saying,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:29, what did the Lord ask Elijah to notice Ahab was doing after the judgment was proclaimed against him?","answer":"\u201cSee how Ahab has humbled himself before Me?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:29, what reason did God give for deciding to not bring the calamity against Ahab during his life?","answer":"Because he has humbled himself before Me,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:29, because Ahab humbled himself what did the Lord decide to not do?","answer":"I will not bring the calamity in his days."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 21:29, because Ahab humbled himself when did the Lord decide to bring calamity on Ahab's house?","answer":"In the days of his son I will bring the calamity on his house.\u201d"}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]  ,"c22":[
        {"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:1, how long had there been peace between Syria and Israel before Ahab decided to fight for Gilead along with Jehoshaphat?","answer":"Now three years passed without war between Syria and Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:2, how long after the previous battle between Israel and Syria did Jehoshaphat go to visit Ahab?","answer":"Then it came to pass, in the third year,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:2, what did Jehoshaphat do in the third year after the previous battle between Syria and Israel?","answer":"that Jehoshaphat the king of Judah went down to visit the king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:3, what city did Ahab want to take back from Syria?","answer":"And the king of Israel said to his servants, \u201cDo you know that Ramoth in Gilead is ours,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:3, from what country did Ahab want to take Ramoth in Gilead?","answer":"but we hesitate to take it out of the hand of the king of Syria?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:4, when Ahab was thinking about taking a city from Syria, what did he ask Jehoshaphat?","answer":"So he said to Jehoshaphat, \u201cWill you go with me to fight at Ramoth Gilead?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:4, when Ahab asked the king of Judah if he would help him fight at Ramoth Gilead, what did he say about himself?","answer":"Jehoshaphat said to the king of Israel, \u201cI am as you are,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:4, when Ahab asked the king of Judah if he would help him fight at Ramoth Gilead, what did he say about his people?","answer":"my people as your people,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:4, when Ahab asked the king of Judah if he would help him fight at Ramoth Gilead, what did he say about hims horses?","answer":"my horses as your horses.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:5, what did the king of Judah ask Ahab to do before they prepared for battle?","answer":"Also Jehoshaphat said to the king of Israel, \u201cPlease inquire for the word of the Lord today.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:6, what was the name of the category of people that Ahab gathered to advise him before going to fight Syria?","answer":"Then the king of Israel gathered the prophets together,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:6, how many prophets did Ahab gather?","answer":"about four hundred men,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:6, what did he ask the prophets?","answer":"and said to them, \u201cShall I go against Ramoth Gilead to fight, or shall I refrain?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:6, which direction did the prophets tell the king to go?","answer":"So they said, \u201cGo up,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:6, what reason did the prophets give for their advise, \"go up\"?","answer":"for the Lord will deliver it into the hand of the king.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:7, was Jehoshaphat satisfied with the 400 prophets Ahab had gathered?","answer":"And Jehoshaphat said, \u201cIs there not still a prophet of the Lord here,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:7, what did Jehoshaphat ask to be done after hearing from the 400 prophets?","answer":"that we may inquire of Him?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:8, how many prophets of the Lord were there in the areas where Ahab was?","answer":"So the king of Israel said to Jehoshaphat, \u201cThere is still one man,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:8, what was the name of the prophet of the Lord that Ahab mentioned to Jehoshaphat?","answer":"Micaiah the son of Imlah, by whom we may inquire of the Lord;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:8, did Ahab like Micaiah?  why or why not?","answer":"but I hate him, because he does not prophesy good concerning me, but evil.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:8, what did Jehoshaphat say when Ahab said that he hated Micaiah?","answer":"And Jehoshaphat said, \u201cLet not the king say such things!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:9, what did Ahab say to get the prophet of the Lord to come? and to whom did he say it?","answer":"Then the king of Israel called an officer and said, \u201cBring Micaiah the son of Imlah quickly!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:10, when the prophets came before Ahab and Jehoshaphat, how were they dressed?","answer":"The king of Israel and Jehoshaphat the king of Judah, having put on their robes,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:10, when the prophets came before Ahab and Jehoshaphat, on what were they sitting?","answer":"sat each on his throne,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:10, where were the king of Israel and the King of Judah when the prophets came before them?","answer":"at a threshing floor at the entrance of the gate of Samaria;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:10, what was done before Ahab and Jehoshaphat at the threshing floor at the entrance of the gate of Samaria?","answer":"and all the prophets prophesied before them."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:11, who said this, \"With these you shall gore the Syrians...\"?","answer":"Now Zedekiah the son of Chenaanah had made horns of iron for himself;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:11, What did Zedekiah the son of Chenaanah say before Ahab?","answer":"and he said, \u201cThus says the Lord: \u2018With these you shall gore the Syrians until they are destroyed.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:12, how many of the prophets said that the Lord will deliver Ramoth into the king's hand?","answer":"And all the prophets prophesied so, saying, \u201cGo up to Ramoth Gilead and prosper,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:12, what reason did the prophets give for saying that Ahab and Jehoshaphat should go up to Ramoth Gilead?","answer":"for the Lord will deliver it into the king\u2019s hand.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:13, who told the prophet of the Lord all the other prophets were encouraging the king?","answer":"Then the messenger who had gone to call Micaiah spoke to him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:13, how did the king's messenger tell Micaiah that the other prophets were encouraging the king?","answer":"saying, \u201cNow listen, the words of the prophets with one accord encourage the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:13, did the king's messenger ask Micaiah to also encourage the king?","answer":"Please, let your word be like the word of one of them, and speak encouragement.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:14, when the king's messenger asked Micaiah encourage the king like the other prophets, how did Micaiah answer?","answer":"And Micaiah said, \u201cAs the Lord lives, whatever the Lord says to me, that I will speak.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:15, what did the king ask Micaiah?","answer":"Then he came to the king; and the king said to him, \u201cMicaiah, shall we go to war against Ramoth Gilead, or shall we refrain?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:15, what did Micaiah say when the king asked if he should go to war against Ramoth Gilead?","answer":"And he answered him, \u201cGo and prosper, for the Lord will deliver it into the hand of the king!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:16, what did the king say that indicated he wanted Micaiah to speak honestly?","answer":"So the king said to him, \u201cHow many times shall I make you swear that you tell me nothing but the truth in the name of the Lord?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:17, after the king asked Micaiah to only speak the truth in the name of the Lord, what did Micaiah say?","answer":"Then he said, \u201cI saw all Israel scattered on the mountains, as sheep that have no shepherd."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:17, what did the Lord say about the soldiers of Israel?","answer":"And the Lord said, \u2018These have no master. Let each return to his house in peace.\u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:18, after Micaiah gave the Lord's true message, who said to whom, \"Did I not tell you he would not prophesy  good...?\"","answer":"And the king of Israel said to Jehoshaphat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:18, after Micaiah gave the Lord's true message, what did Ahab say to Jehoshaphat?","answer":"\u201cDid I not tell you he would not prophesy good concerning me, but evil?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:19, after Ahab reminded Jehoshaphat that he had said Micaiah would not prophesy good, what did Micaiah say?","answer":"Then Micaiah said, \u201cTherefore hear the word of the Lord:"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:19, what did Micaiah say that he saw with all the host of heaven standing by?","answer":"I saw the Lord sitting on His throne,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:19, what did Micaiah say that he saw on the right and left of the Lord?","answer":"and all the host of heaven standing by,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:19, where did Micaiah say that he saw all the host of heaven standing?","answer":"on His right hand and on His left."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:20, who asked for a volunteer to make someone fall at Ramoth Gilead? and who was that someone?","answer":"And the Lord said, \u2018Who will persuade Ahab to go up,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:20, the Lord asked for a volunteer to persuade Ahab to go up so that something would happen, what was this?","answer":"that he may fall at Ramoth Gilead?\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:20, multiple ideas were mentioned for how to persuade Ahab to go up to Ramoth Gilead. With what words does the Bible describe these?","answer":"So one spoke in this manner, and another spoke in that manner."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:21, who gave the wining idea for persuading Ahab to go up to Ramoth Giliad? How did he introduce this idea to the Lord?","answer":"Then a spirit came forward and stood before the Lord, and said, \u2018I will persuade him.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:22, how did the Lord respond to the spirit who said, \"I will persuade him.\"?","answer":"The Lord said to him, \u2018In what way?\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:22, what was the wining idea for pursuading Ahab to go up to Ramoth Giliad?","answer":"So he said, \u2018I will go out and be a lying spirit in the mouth of all his prophets.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:22, with what words did the Lord give permission to the spirit to do as he had suggested?","answer":"And the Lord said, \u2018You shall persuade him, and also prevail. Go out and do so.\u2019"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:23, what did Micaiah say to Ahab about the truthfulness of the message delivered by the other prophets?","answer":"Therefore look! The Lord has put a lying spirit in the mouth of all these prophets of yours,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:23, had the Lord declared disaster against Ahab?","answer":"and the Lord has declared disaster against you.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:24, one of the other prophets came near to Micaiah, did something, and asked which way the spirit from the Lord went from him to Micaiah.  What did this other prophet do?","answer":"Now Zedekiah the son of Chenaanah went near and struck Micaiah on the cheek,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:24, When Zedekiah struck Micaiah on the cheek, what did Zedekiah ask Micaiah?","answer":"and said, \u201cWhich way did the spirit from the Lord go from me to speak to you?\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:25, what did Micaiah say in response to Zedekiah's question about which way the spirit of the Lord went?","answer":"And Micaiah said, \u201cIndeed, you shall see on that day when you go into an inner chamber to hide!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:26, Who commanded that a prophet should be put in prison and feed bread of affliction and water of affliction? and what was the name of the prophet?","answer":"So the king of Israel said, \u201cTake Micaiah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:26, To which two people did the king of Israel say that Micaiah should be returned?","answer":"and return him to Amon the governor of the city and to Joash the king\u2019s son;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:27, What did command did Ahab say should be relayed about Micaiah to Amon the city's governor and to Joash the king's son?","answer":"and say, \u2018Thus says the king: \u201cPut this fellow in prison,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:27, Describe the food and water that Ahab said should be given to Micaiah until Ahab returned in peace?","answer":"and feed him with bread of affliction and water of affliction,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:27, For what duration of time did Ahab say Micaiah should be kept in prison?","answer":"until I come in peace.\u201d \u2019 \u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:28, What did Micaiah say about the message he had received when Ahab said that he should be put in prison?","answer":"But Micaiah said, \u201cIf you ever return in peace, the Lord has not spoken by me.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:28, What did Micaiah say to all who were listening when Ahab said that he should be put in prison?","answer":"And he said, \u201cTake heed, all you people!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:29, where did Ahab and Jehoshaphat go after Micaiah delivered the Lord's message?","answer":"So the king of Israel and Jehoshaphat the king of Judah went up to Ramoth Gilead."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:30, what did Ahab say he was going to ware into battle?","answer":"And the king of Israel said to Jehoshaphat, \u201cI will disguise myself and go into battle;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:30, what did Ahab tell Jehoshaphat to ware into battle?","answer":"but you put on your robes.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:30, what did Ahab do to prepare for battle?","answer":"So the king of Israel disguised himself and went into battle."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:31, who commanded, \"Fight with no one small or great, but only with the king...\"","answer":"Now the king of Syria had commanded the thirty-two captains of his chariots,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:31, what did the king of Syria command his captains?","answer":"saying, \u201cFight with no one small or great, but only with the king of Israel.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:32, who did the Syrian captains think was the king of Israel?","answer":"So it was, when the captains of the chariots saw Jehoshaphat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:32, what did the captains of the chariots say when they saw Jehoshaphat?","answer":"that they said, \u201cSurely it is the king of Israel!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:32, what did the Syrian captains do when they thought Jehoshaphat was Ahab?","answer":"Therefore they turned aside to fight against him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:32, what did Jeoshaphat do when the 32 captains of the Syrian chariots turned to fight him?","answer":"and Jehoshaphat cried out."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:33, when did the captains of the chariots turn back from pursuing Jehoshaphat?","answer":"And it happened, when the captains of the chariots saw that it was not the king of Israel,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:33, what did the captains of the chariots do when they saw Jehoshaphat was not the king of Israel?","answer":"that they turned back from pursuing him."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:34, how was that arrow aimed that struck the king of Israel.","answer":"Now a certain man drew a bow at random,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:34, a man drew a bow at random.  Where did it land?","answer":"and struck the king of Israel between the joints of his armor."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:34, when the arrow hit Ahab, what did he say?","answer":"So he said to the driver of his chariot, \u201cTurn around and take me out of the battle, for I am wounded.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:33, how did the battle progress the day Ahab died?","answer":"The battle increased that day;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:33, What 3 things did king Ahab do after he left his last battle in Ramoth Gilead?","answer":"and the king was propped up in his chariot, facing the Syrians, and died at evening."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:33, Where did the blood from Ahab's wound go while he was watching the battle with the Syrians?","answer":"The blood ran out from the wound onto the floor of the chariot."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:36, when was this command issued and by whom: \"Every man to his city, and every man to his own country\"","answer":"Then, as the sun was going down, a shout went throughout the army,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:36, what was shouted throughout the army.","answer":"saying, \u201cEvery man to his city, and every man to his own country!\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:37, what happened to Ahab the day he was shot with an arrow?","answer":"So the king died,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:37, when Ahab died where was he taken?","answer":"and was brought to Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:37, where was Ahab buried?","answer":"And they buried the king in Samaria."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:38, where was Ahab's chariot cleaned?","answer":"Then someone washed the chariot at a pool in Samaria,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:38, what did the dogs do?","answer":"and the dogs licked up his blood while the harlots bathed,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:38, had the Lord said that the dogs were going to lick Ahab's blood at the pool in Samaria?","answer":"according to the word of the Lord which He had spoken."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:39, what is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel about Ahab in add to his house and cities that he built?","answer":"Now the rest of the acts of Ahab, and all that he did,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:39, what did Ahab use to built his house?","answer":"the ivory house which he built"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:39, what did Ahab build in addition to his house?","answer":"and all the cities that he built,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:39, where are the rest of the acts of Ahab written?","answer":"are they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:40, what happened to Ahab when Ahaziah his son reigned in his place?","answer":"So Ahab rested with his fathers."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:40, when Ahab rested with his fathers, what did his son do?","answer":"Then Ahaziah his son reigned in his place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:41, who was Jehoshaphat's father and where did he reign?","answer":"Jehoshaphat the son of Asa had become king over Judah"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:41, Jehoshaphat became king over Judah in what year of which king of Israel?","answer":"in the fourth year of Ahab king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:42, How old was Jehoshaphat when he became king in Jerusalem?","answer":"Jehoshaphat was thirty-five years old when he became king,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:42, how long did Jehoshaphat reign? and from what city did he reign?","answer":"and he reigned twenty-five years in Jerusalem."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:42, who was Jehoshaphat's mother?","answer":"His mother\u2019s name was Azubah the daughter of Shilhi."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:43, Jehoshaphat walked according to whom?","answer":"And he walked in all the ways of his father Asa."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:43, what did Jehoshaphat do that was like what Asa did?","answer":"He did not turn aside from them, doing what was right in the eyes of the Lord."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:43, what was not taken away during the reign of Jehoshaphat?","answer":"Nevertheless the high places were not taken away,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:43, what evidence showed that the high places were not taken away during Jehoshaphat's reign?","answer":"for the people offered sacrifices and burned incense on the high places."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:44, with whom did Jehoshaphat make peace?","answer":"Also Jehoshaphat made peace with the king of Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:45, in addition to what is recorded in this book about Jehoshaphat what is written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?","answer":"Now the rest of the acts of Jehoshaphat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:45, what did Jehoshaphat show?","answer":"the might that he showed,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:45, what was Jehoshaphat known for making?","answer":"and how he made war,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:45, where was more about Jehoshaphat written than what is in this book?","answer":"are they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:46, who did king Jehoshaphat banish from the land?","answer":"And the rest of the perverted persons,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:46, which perverted persons did Jehoshaphat banish from the land?","answer":"who remained in the days of his father Asa,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:46, what did Jehoshaphat do to the rest of the perverted persons?","answer":"he banished from the land."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:47, what was not present in Edom?","answer":"There was then no king in Edom,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:47, how was Edom being governed when there was no king there?","answer":"only a deputy of the king."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:48, what did Jehoshaphat make to get gold?  where did he intend to get it from?","answer":"Jehoshaphat made merchant ships to go to Ophir for gold;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:48, how successful were Jehoshaphat's merchant ships?","answer":"but they never sailed,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:48, why did Jehoshaphat's merchant ships not sail?","answer":"for the ships were wrecked at Ezion Geber."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:49, who volunteered to help Jehoshaphat with his merchant ships?","answer":"Then Ahaziah the son of Ahab said to Jehoshaphat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:49, what did Ahaziah the son of Ahab say to Jehoshaphat?","answer":"\u201cLet my servants go with your servants in the ships.\u201d"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:49, did Jehoshaphat accept the offer from Ahaziah the son of Ahab?","answer":"But Jehoshaphat would not."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:50, where was Jehoshaphat buried?","answer":"And Jehoshaphat rested with his fathers, and was buried with his fathers in the City of David his father."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:50, who reigned in the place of Jehoshaphat?","answer":"Then Jehoram his son reigned in his place."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:51, who became king in Samaria in king Jehoshaphat's 17th year?","answer":"Ahaziah the son of Ahab became king over Israel in Samaria"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:51 in relation to Jehoshaphat, when did Ahaziah become king in Samaria?","answer":"in the seventeenth year of Jehoshaphat king of Judah,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:51, how long did Ahaziah the son of Ahab reign?","answer":"and reigned two years over Israel."},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, was Ahaziah the son of Ahab good in the sight of the Lord?","answer":"He did evil in the sight of the Lord,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, how did Ahaziah compare to Ahab?","answer":"and walked in the way of his father"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, Ahaziah walked according to the ways of what woman?","answer":"and in the way of his mother"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, how did Ahaziah compare to Jeroboam?","answer":"and in the way of Jeroboam the son of Nebat,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, what did the following people have in common: Ahaziah, his father, his mother, and Jeroboam the son of Nebat?","answer":"who had made Israel sin;"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, what false God did Ahaziah serve?","answer":"for he served Baal and worshiped him,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, what did Ahaziah do toward the Lord?","answer":"and provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger,"},{"question":"According to 1 Kings 22:52, who else had provoked the Lord God of Israel to anger?","answer":"according to all that his father had done."}
        /*
        //
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        { "question" : "" , "answer" : ""},
        */
        
    ]       

}

//chapter 1
function king_1_c1(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c1.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c1[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c1[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 2
function king_1_c2(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_2.c1.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c2[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c2[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 3
function king_1_c3(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c3.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c3[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c3[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 4
function king_1_c4(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c4.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c4[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c4[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 5
function king_1_c5(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c5.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c5[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c5[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 6
function king_1_c6(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c6.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c6[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c6[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 7
function king_1_c7(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c7.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c7[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c7[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 8
function king_1_c8(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c8.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c8[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c8[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 9
function king_1_c9(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c9.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c9[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c9[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}


//chapter 10
function king_1_c10(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c10.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c10[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c10[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 11
function king_1_c11(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c11.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c11[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c11[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 12
function king_1_c12(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c12.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c12[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c12[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 13
function king_1_c13(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c13.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c13[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c13[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}


//chapter 14
function king_1_c14(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c14.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c14[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c14[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 15
function king_1_c15(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c15.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c15[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c15[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 16
function king_1_c16(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c16.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c16[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c16[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 17
function king_1_c17(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c17.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c17[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c17[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}

//chapter 18
function king_1_c18(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c18.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c18[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c18[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 19
function king_1_c19(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c19.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c19[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c19[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 20
function king_1_c20(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c20.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c20[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c20[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 21
function king_1_c21(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c21.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c21[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c21[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}
//chapter 22
function king_1_c22(){
    //converts the json object into somthing readable
    //generates a random number over the length of the JSON array
    var i = Math.floor(Math.random()*king_1.c22.length);
    document.getElementById("number").innerHTML = "Question #" + (i+1);
    //puts the random question into the html
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML =
    king_1.c22[i].question;
    //puts the correct random answer into the html
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML =
    "<b>"+" Correct Answer:" + "<br>"+ "</b>"+
    king_1.c22[i].answer ;
    //hides the answer
    document.getElementById("answer").style.display = "none";
    //changes the button back 
    document.getElementById("show").innerHTML ="Show Answer";
    //erases user text
    document.getElementById("u_answer").value = "";
}